<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sandy and Company Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Sandy and Company - your professional Marysville Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 14:39:06 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 14:39:06 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Traffic Is Great Here on the Extra Mile</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rE_nFSt9SV4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m out at a new construction site with one of my buyers who’s doing their inspection, and we had a great time.&lt;strong&gt;One of the things I really love about real estate is that I get to help each individual family in whatever story they’re in right then. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, I listed a house. Then I held an open house for it on each of our snowy Saturdays. When I talked to a contractor who was working on the bathroom, he asked, “Why would you hold an open house when most people can’t get out here?” The answer is simple: I’ve been hired to do a job. And we’re going to do the best possible job for our clients every way we can. We’ve got great systems to help our clients on a regular basis so that when something is extenuating, like snow, we’re able to stretch out so that our clients’ needs are met.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my job. I love being able to let people know that I can help you through a process that can be really tricky and hairy.&lt;strong&gt;We can provide some sanity and peace and give you a home or a relief on the other end that really works for you. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what I love about real estate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know anyone who’s thinking that houses are cool and they love people, I’d love to talk with them. We have a couple of opportunities both on our team and in our office, and I’d love to see if there would be a fit for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can provide some sanity and peace and give you something on the other end that really works for you.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/traffic-is-great-here-on-the-extra-mile.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We can provide some sanity and peace and give you something on the other end that really works for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy a house, click the box to see all area homes. If you’re thinking of selling your home, click the box for your home’s value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks so much and have an amazing day! Let’s talk houses!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/traffic-is-great-here-on-the-extra-mile.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/traffic-is-great-here-on-the-extra-mile.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The One-Liner Isn't the Whole Story</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cDI8PfoJBqo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that the one-liners we see are not really the whole story. I have a tendency, like many others, to feel like my reality is wrapped up in this very moment. But when I slow down and wait for the story to unfold, oftentimes it just keeps getting better. I love that a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, I had four buyers: Two offers got accepted, and two offers got turned down. The short story is that the market is already starting to pick up with that spring intensity that we’re expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What we really need to be asking is, “What can we do for you today?”%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/the-one-liner-isnt-the-whole-story.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What we really need to be asking is, “What can we do for you today?””&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And still there’s another part of that story: This last week, the second two sellers came back to my buyers and said, “Let’s take another look at this.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How’s the market?” is too big a question—too broad. What we really need to be asking is, “What can we do for you today?” And then we sit down, maybe grab a cup of tea, and then talk about where you are right now, what you’re looking for in your home, and how we can help you over the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have an amazing day! We are so excited to talk with you about how we can help if you’re looking to buy or sell a home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/the-one-liner-isnt-the-whole-story.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/the-one-liner-isnt-the-whole-story.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keeping It Simple in 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XYI9b3OUG74?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With buying and selling real estate, there is so much going on. So how do we really narrow down what’s most important? That’s what we’re talking about today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christmastime that we just passed through is an excellent time to give us an example of how to keep it simple. Keep it simple, sweetie, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did we do with our family at Christmastime? We got to talk about Jesus, which is our favorite story to tell, we saw our family, whether they were coming to see us or we were going to see them, and Don and I also talked about what’s most important for 2019 and what we can do to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep it simple and keep the top priority the top priority. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In just the same way, I am working for my clients whether they are looking to sell their house or to buy. We have to talk about what is most important about this investment: Is it the space? Is it the security? Is it what it’s going to do for their life—whether it’s going to shorten their commute or allow them to provide for other family members? What will it do for your life? So keep it simple and keep it the most important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’re going into this shifting market, we are also committed to you. We are committed to helping one more family every month get the home of their dreams, the home that really works for them, in 2019 than we did in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Keep it simple and keep the top priority  the top priority.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/keeping-it-simple-in-2019.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Keep it simple and keep the top priority  the top priority.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you are talking with your friends and family and you hear someone is thinking of selling or buying, would you give us a call? Let’s talk about how to get them what’s most important in their home in 2019—whether it’s that space, that security, what it will do for their life, and how we can help them keep what’s most important. Remember that through that process; it can be hairy, so we’ll make it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to buy your next home, click the box to ask to look at all area homes, and if you’re looking to sell, click the box to see your home’s value in today’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so looking forward to a great 2019 keeping the most important priority the most important!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/keeping-it-simple-in-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/keeping-it-simple-in-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have A Blessed Everyday Christmas!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2V23Z8FooVg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christmastime is here, and I spent a lot of time thinking about where to shoot this video, what to say, what I should wear, and all that prep stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I thought, ya know? Christ himself didn’t enter this world in a fancy suit or in a fancy place or with a fancy decorated tree. He came for us in a stable and was very humble. So I came out in my everyday jacket and sweater next to the Snohomish River, where I like to walk, and I’m saying in my normal everyday way, I am grateful for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got an amazing life and amazing family and amazing clients, and I have been blessed in so many ways to have an amazing year. I hope that you have time this Christmas that you can spend with the people that you can be in your “everyday” with, be yourself and be blessed and be filled with joy and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for being a part of my life. I love you, and I’m so excited to look forward to 2019 and see what it brings both of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a blessed Christmas. Every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/have-a-blessed-everyday-christmas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/have-a-blessed-everyday-christmas.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome Back, Old Friend!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/z0B_Tn4Q-aM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back, old friend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes now a great time to be a buyer who also has a house to sell in our market? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a rushed market, people sometimes don’t have time to achieve all of their real estate goals. So many of my clients over the past couple years have been concerned that they can’t sell their current home because they won’t be able to find their next home. They need more bedrooms, more space, more room to park, etc. They’ve been living in smaller homes that function okay for them but aren’t really what they need for their family. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Sellers are realizing that in order to get top dollar in this market, they need to be willing to allow buyers to sell their homes first.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/welcome-back-old-friend.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Sellers are realizing that in order to get top dollar in this market, they need to be willing to allow buyers to sell their homes first.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the kicker, though: Last month I was searching for shop homes for my clients—homes with at least three- or four-car garages—and I noticed that &lt;strong&gt;in the $400,000 to $500,000 price range, there were a lot of sellers that had accepted contingent offers.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers are realizing that in order to still get the price they want, they need to be willing to allow buyers to sell their homes first. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So welcome back contingent offers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you need to sell your current home before you can buy your best home, call me&lt;/strong&gt; so we can make a plan. Then you can transition smoothly and seamlessly between homes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about our market or you have any other real estate needs, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to speak to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/welcome-back-old-friend.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/welcome-back-old-friend.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Still Need Your Own Realtor When Purchasing New Construction</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4lQfjbeyfx0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers often assume they won’t need to have a Realtor on their side when buying new construction. After all, the agent working with the builders has all the information they could need, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, while this agent is usually very knowledgeable, it’s important to realize that they are not working specifically on your behalf. Having your own representation will help make sure you understand all the fine details of the process as they relate to you and your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of my clients are having their new home built in Monroe. Using the budget guidelines given during our initial meeting with the site agent, my clients went to the design studio and shopped for upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine their shock when &lt;strong&gt;the totals came back at $40,000 more than what they had budgeted and planned.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed up quickly. As we found out during this next meeting, the site agent had explained the customization and upgrades in a way that sounded like we had $40,000 to spend in upgrades that were included in our agreed-on price. Not the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, it was up to my clients to decide what truly &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; matter to them. Because while they were happy with the standard finish options, certain customization options can have a significant impact on the livability of a new construction home.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, current new construction doesn’t include overhead lighting in dining rooms, living rooms, or bedrooms. These are the sort of details that buyers might not think to consider until they’ve been prompted. After all, &lt;strong&gt;most people wouldn’t assume that overhead lighting would be an extra expense.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The agents you will find at new construction homes are there to represent the builders’ best interests—not yours.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-you-still-need-your-own-realtor-when-purchasing-new-construction.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The agents you will find at new construction homes are there to represent the builders’ best interests—not yours.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To balance out those extra expenses, I pointed out several upgrades which were in the original plan but weren’t necessary for my clients. A man door in the garage, for instance, turned out to be a $2,500 expense which my clients didn’t even want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gas BBQ stub (which would have added $600 to the cost of the home) and a railing instead of a stair wall (for $3,000) were two other features my clients easily eliminated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By cutting out even just these three features, my clients saved thousands below what the initial bundled cost had been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to this meeting, my clients walked away all smiles. When all was said and done, I helped them save just under $7,000.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, &lt;strong&gt;customizing a new construction home can quickly rack up a high price tag.&lt;/strong&gt; So if you’re interested in purchasing a new construction home, bring your Realtor. You don’t know what you don’t know. Put our experience to use to make sure you’re getting what you want and not paying for what you don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already have a trusted Realtor, &lt;strong&gt;I would love to speak to you about how I help my clients save thousands buying their brand new home.&lt;/strong&gt; I work through transactions like this every day. I would be happy to guide you through yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-you-still-need-your-own-realtor-when-purchasing-new-construction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-you-still-need-your-own-realtor-when-purchasing-new-construction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Driving Your House?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PlKF7rDvH8Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you “driving your house?” Depending on the expert, our millennials can be living with zero debt or lots of debt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do millennials hate debt because they watched their parents get wrapped up in it, or is it because they themselves are already feeling the effects of it from credit cards, car payments, and student loans?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter if you’re a baby boomer or a millennial, people are people—we have to figure out how to live, and if you want to buy a house, you need to start thinking about your debt-to-income ratio (DTI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you want to buy a house, you need to start thinking about your debt-to-income ratio.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/are-you-driving-your-house.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you want to buy a house, you need to start thinking about your debt-to-income ratio.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your lender is looking at how much you can afford in a mortgage payment, you’re looking at a 30-year commitment, so they need to see that you can move around a little bit quicker if times get lean or if times get fat. If you have a rent payment that is $2,500 a month, a car payment that is $600 a month, and student loans upwards of $700 or $800 a month, you’re not going to be able to move quickly since you have these long-term commitments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As consumers and as Americans we need to be asking ourselves, “How much do you need? How much do you want? What are you going to do for yourself and your family moving forward?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what it means to be financially responsible both today and years from now or if you’re looking to sell your home and make a move, feel free to reach out to me. Let’s make great decisions together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/are-you-driving-your-house.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/are-you-driving-your-house.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Have the Tools!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1G8uXeZDs9o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to remind you of a service I provide my friends, clients, and neighbors: Sandy’s Tool Shed. Summer is wrapping up, and for many, that means taking care of some fall cleaning tasks. Our team would like to help by loaning you pressure washers, extension ladders, and other home maintenance tools that you use too rarely to buy yourself. Also, if you don’t know how to use these tools or would prefer someone else handle the jobs, we would be happy to refer you to one of our preferred contractors. We want to help you turn your house into a great place to come home to. To see my full message, watch this short two minute video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/we-have-the-tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/we-have-the-tools.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Make Sure Our Homebuyers Know What They’re Getting</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C3N7Mn-o9rQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more things change, the more they stay the same, even here in the Northwest. I was heading down through the Snohomish Valley a couple weeks ago and saw some new, beautiful homes. And then I took in the unmistakable aroma of cow manure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s just the way it is in the country.&lt;/strong&gt; This is where we live: it’s all a great big beautiful mix of sights, sounds, and scents. We have the outdoors, we have the golf courses, and we have the manure. And still this is where we love to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Country living isn’t for everyone.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/we-make-sure-our-homebuyers-know-what-theyre-getting.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Country living isn’t for everyone.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you’re looking for the home that really works for you, we make sure you know all about what’s around it.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s why we have disclosures and how we use our experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how we can get you into the right home in the right place for your family, don’t hesitate! Give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/we-make-sure-our-homebuyers-know-what-theyre-getting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/we-make-sure-our-homebuyers-know-what-theyre-getting.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do the Latest Developments in Our Midsummer Market Mean for Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JEG2lbLypws?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re right in the middle of summer at the moment, so what does this mean for our market? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;strong&gt;while the sun may be out and blazing, buyer activity isn’t quite as hot as what we’ve seen in the past.&lt;/strong&gt; There hasn’t been nearly as much competition lately, and sellers haven’t been able to pull in quite as many high offers as what was once the case. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this tell us? &lt;strong&gt;As I’ve said in the past, you can’t time the market.&lt;/strong&gt; This past spring may have been our market’s peak, but we can’t say that for sure. We’ll have to wait to see how this fall and winter (and next spring) perform to get a better idea of how current conditions fit into larger market trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Instead of focusing on what’s happening in the market, I encourage you to take a look at what’s happening in your life.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-the-latest-developments-in-our-midsummer-market-mean-for-buyers-and-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Instead of focusing on what’s happening in the market, I encourage you to take a look at what’s happening in your life.”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of focusing on what’s happening in the market, though, I encourage you to take a look at what’s happening in your life. Do you have too many bedrooms? Are you looking to move to the city? Whatever the case is for you, let’s talk. &lt;strong&gt;Let’s get together and develop a strategic plan for your needs.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-the-latest-developments-in-our-midsummer-market-mean-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-the-latest-developments-in-our-midsummer-market-mean-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
