<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sandy and Company Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from -- CLIENT BRAND -- - your professional -- MARKET -- Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 15:49:27 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 15:49:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Is the Puget Sound Market Headed?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bgrQnLV1j2U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of “Where is our market headed?” is one that I get a lot. I’m going to answer it today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The direction the market is heading is a concern for both buyers and sellers.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers want to make sure they don’t miss out on the top price, and buyers want to make sure they don’t pay too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to last year, our growth has slowed a little bit. But make no mistake—our market is still growing. Although we saw an incredible 13.2% growth in 2016 and that number is down to 10.4% in 2017, any appreciation rate close to 10% is outstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The question of “Where is our market headed?” is one that I get a lot. I’m going to answer it today.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/where-is-the-puget-sound-market-headed.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The question of “Where is our market headed?” is one that I get a lot. I’m going to answer it today.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, our inventory is even lower than it was at this point last year. Last year, we had 1.2 months of inventory at this time, which is an extremely low figure. This year, that number dropped to 0.7 months, or just three weeks of inventory. &lt;strong&gt;Until that inventory bumps up in the summer, we’re going to have a bottleneck of buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; The best way for them to compete is by making an offer above asking price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see prices continuing to move up, but we’re in line for stabilization. When will that happen? I can’t tell you, &lt;strong&gt;but I can tell you that if you’ve been thinking about buying or selling a home, you need to give us a call or send us an email&lt;/strong&gt; so we can discuss how the market relates to your individual situation. I’ll give you the facts and present you with your options and potential risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/where-is-the-puget-sound-market-headed.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/where-is-the-puget-sound-market-headed.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Homeownership on Tulalip Land</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pmBDPiinJKY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to talk about land on the Tulalip Reservation, which can either be leased land or it can be deeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it’s leased, then the lease is either through the Tulalip Tribe or through the Fryberg family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When the land is owned by the tribe you pay them a monthly lease fee that’s based on the value of the land and reassessed every three years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you lease from the Fryberg family—who are part of the Tulalip Tribe and own the land—you pay an annual lease fee to them.&lt;/strong&gt; The Fryberg leases are overseen by the Bureau of Indian Affairs. The Fryberg family leased land is reassessed every five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you buy a home on Tulalip leased land, you pay a monthly or annual lease fee.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/homeownership-on-tulalip-land.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you buy a home on Tulalip leased land, you pay a monthly or annual lease fee.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you buy a property that is leased land, you’re buying the improvements on the land, as well as the rights to exclusively use the land. Much like deeded land, no one else can claim rights to use it during your lease period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you buy a deeded property on the Tulalip Reservation, your rights are exactly like buying anywhere else. The only difference is that you’ll pay a 1% fee to the Tulalip Tribe when you sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about tribal land or leased/deeded property, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I am more than happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/homeownership-on-tulalip-land.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/homeownership-on-tulalip-land.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Make Big Decisions?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8-8Lokoiiag?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is like a box of chocolates, or maybe it’s like a bowl of cherries. Sometimes making big life decisions is like the Now and Later candy: all of the life decisions that you make have something to do with now and something to do with later. So, how do you make those big decisions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people  can make a snap decision, jump right in, and everything turns out OK. Even when buying a home. Most of us take a slower pace. I want to encourage you to do three things when making those big decisions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Slow down to be wise.&lt;/strong&gt; Often we can be distracted by the shiny and beautiful surfaces. We don’t always look to see what’s underneath. That can happen in all arenas of life. Let me encourage you to take a harder look and make sure that what you see is really what you get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Pray about it.&lt;/strong&gt; Ask God, “What is it that you have for me and how does this fit in?” Don’t be afraid of his answer. He might say no because he has something better in store for you later on. But he might actually say yes! Then you can be excited that you are being wise and that you are walking along the purpose he has designed for you as your creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure that what you see is really what you’ll get.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-do-you-make-big-decisions.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure that what you see is really what you’ll get.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Talk to others.&lt;/strong&gt; Talk to your spouse, parents, friends, or whomever you know who has a wise demeanor in this arena. Ask what they think about it. When I am looking at homes with single people, they don’t always have another person to talk things over with and bounce ideas off. In that case, I am honored to be on their “Board of Directors” and to help them weigh their options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering a home, there are several things you need to keep in mind. For instance, does it make you smile when you walk in the door? Is the property structurally sound? The house might be really pretty, but if the bones weren’t taken care of, then you have a problem. You should also consider whether or not you have the resources for upkeep down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you make those big decisions, look at Now and Later. Go through a decision-process to ensure that you make a great decision now that will still be a great decision down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-do-you-make-big-decisions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-do-you-make-big-decisions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Tips for New Homeowners</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/htEUsznozAg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you buy a home, the strong temptation is  to grab the keys and move in immediately. But there are a few things to do before you bring in that first box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, look at your key. How many people have had access to your new home before you bought it? The previous owner may have given spare keys to friends, family members, and the neighbor’s cousin. &lt;strong&gt;This is a good time to change those locks. Either call a locksmith to re-key your locks or buy new hardware and switch them out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, change out the air filter in the furnace. The previous owner had different scents, so make the home your own by breathing in that fresh air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Swap that furnace filter out twice a year.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/7-tips-for-new-homeowners.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Swap that furnace filter out twice a year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, check out the toilet seats. Put seats on there that are clean and look good without any cracking paint or broken hinges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon you’ll settle into daily life in the new home. That doesn’t mean you should neglect home maintenance. Everyone forgets some of the regular maintenance routine, &lt;strong&gt;so we have a quick list of things to share that you should keep up with regularly in your home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service the furnace by swapping out the previously mentioned air filter twice per year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a look at your attic and crawlspaces for any water leaks, mold, or pest intrusion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vacuum the refrigerator coils and under the stove. You use these things every day, so it’s smart to keep them clean, fresh, and working properly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flip your mattress. It’s just like rotating your tires. You’ll get more life out of your mattress and probably a better night’s sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me at all, reach out. Call or email me, I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/7-tips-for-new-homeowners.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/7-tips-for-new-homeowners.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Avoid Impulse and Buyer's Remorse</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YcjC_vyrueM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever made an impulsive decision and later realized you forgot to consider a number of important things? Many buyers just like you are afraid of this when a house is listed for sale and multiple offers seem to appear within minutes. &lt;strong&gt;This is what we help our buyers avoid. The last thing I want is for you to have buyer’s remorse when you make such a big purchase.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Finding the right home in this impulsive market comes down to being purposeful.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-we-avoid-impulse-and-buyers-remorse.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Finding the right home in this impulsive market comes down to being purposeful.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purposeful is a word that gets used a lot. For us, it means helping our buyers know what’s most important ahead of time. Then they know they made a wise decision when they bought a home. When we sit down with you for the first time, we talk about what’s important to you and why. We go through categories to make sure you’ve thought of everything. We talk about things like the number of bedrooms and bathrooms that you want. Then if you say you need two bathrooms, for example, does that mean you need a bathtub in that second bathroom or is a shower or just a powder room okay? These questions help us understand the reasons behind the amount of real estate you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my buyers tell me about houses they see somewhere else, I take a look at why they saw it and I didn’t. Is there something I wasn’t considering? Or was there something I thought was important that’s not? One of the biggest factors is location—a buyer might want a certain community, school district, or commute, but then send me a home that’s two school districts away. &lt;strong&gt;That’s when we have that conversation about what’s really most important.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we can back away from the house and talk about what’s most important to you, then we can be purposeful and help you make the right choice. This isn’t the market for buyers to jump up and grab whatever comes along. It’s a market to be careful, wise, and patient. And when the right home comes along, jump quickly and aggressively to win the home they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s anything we can do for you in this hot market, give me a call or send me an email today. I’d be happy to let you know how we can help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-we-avoid-impulse-and-buyers-remorse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-we-avoid-impulse-and-buyers-remorse.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Staging Tips that Earn You Thousands</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pu1eM3DDo1k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably already know that when you sell a home, it’s not the same as when you live in a home. With that in mind, I have four tips for you to stage your home and sell for top dollar in today’s market.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;My first tip is to make a good first impression because &lt;strong&gt;the first impression is the lasting impression.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers take about three to five seconds to make that first impression when they pull up to the house, so clean up the exterior, add some color to the porch, and make sure your trim is freshly painted. When buyers walk into your home, you have another three to five seconds to cement that first impression.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;This leads me to my next tip—&lt;strong&gt;always be show ready.&lt;/strong&gt; In the mornings and evenings, take a look at each room and make sure everything is how you want a buyer to see the house as they walk through it. One great tip I got from Flylady.net is to go through your house every night and pick up the misplaced things you see in each room. Then, when you get the call that someone is coming for a showing, have a list of “hot spots” to take a look at where you know things tend to accumulate quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Use these four tips to get your home sold today for top dollar.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/staging-tips-that-earn-you-thousands.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Use these four tips to get your home sold today for top dollar.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My third tip is to &lt;strong&gt;take the “home” out of your house.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, you need to take personalized items like your family photos down. These photos cause buyers to see your family in the home instead of theirs. And the infamous photo wall hallways– they make buyers uncomfortable from the lack of perceived space when walking down that hallway.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Next, put away about one-third of your stuff. If you have extra bookcases, tables, or trunks that are making any walkways smaller or more inconvenient, remove them. I‘m not a fan of long-term storage units, but they can come in handy when storing these items in the short term. Also, make sure all your closets are half-empty. You want people to look inside of them and see that there’s plenty of room for clothes.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;My last and most important tip is to&lt;strong&gt; hire an informed, professional agent and price it right.&lt;/strong&gt; Pricing is critical when it comes to getting your home sold for top dollar in today’s market. I can’t tell you how many times- even this last year- I’ve seen people list their home for more than it’s worth and end up taking even less than they should have in the end. Hire an agent who’s doing business right now and understands what’s happening in your neighborhood.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions about staging or are thinking about selling your home, please give me a call. I am happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/staging-tips-that-earn-you-thousands.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/staging-tips-that-earn-you-thousands.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why We Don’t Chase the Almighty Dollar</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tVsA8gQEHsI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I wanted to talk about sales—how I serve you, and how that service also serves me at the same time.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Picture a salesperson. Sometimes, I hear from people about what that picture looks like to them. In the last month, I’ve had two people share their assumptions of what it means to make a living from sales. Their emphasis was on the “sales” portion of that paradigm. Let me tell you: at Sandy and Company, &lt;strong&gt;we’re on the opposite side.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;At Keller Williams Realty, just like in many other businesses, we have mottos. One of these is “Customers always comes first.” If I can’t get a customer what they’re looking for, I will tell them. Likewise, when I believe I can help, I jump right in and make it happen.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Going back to the two who shared with me. One of them said he knew I was tempted to withhold information about what might be wrong with the house in the name of getting the sale done. I told him that wasn’t true at all. Don’t get me wrong, I have temptations, but that’s never one of them.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;In the other conversation, she assumed my goal is to push my clients to the very top of their purchase point. In theory, that would serve me best. Once again, I had to correct her. That’s never my goal. as long as we can meet their home needs for less. On the contrary, I love it when my clients purchase well below their price points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=My job is to serve you—not the almighty dollar.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-we-dont-chase-the-almighty-dollar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“My job is to serve you—not the almighty dollar.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because my goal is to make sure that I serve your whole life situation. This means &lt;strong&gt;what’s most important is meeting your needs in the long run.&lt;/strong&gt; If a client of mine purchases for less than they can afford, that means they could save extra money for other needs in their life. And when I serve you well, you are going to be so excited that someone is taking great care of you and giving you all of their expertise and knowledge. You’re going to tell others about me, and that meets my needs in the long run.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I’m in sales, there is a transaction happening, but what I’m thinking about is how I can serve you today.&lt;/strong&gt; If that means we make a transaction together, great! If not, I’m satisfied as long as I know that I helped you. My clients know that about me, which make them comfortable to introduce me to their friends, family and colleagues.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Just yesterday, some clients and I let go of a project we had been working on for six months. It was an arduous process, and we weren’t sure it was going to work, but we gave it a shot anyway. When the numbers didn’t add up in the end and my clients asked to kill the deal, I understood completely. My job is to serve you—not the almighty dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy or sell real estate, please give me a call or shoot me an email. If I’m not the right person for the job, I promise you I’ll find someone who is. I look forward to helping you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-we-dont-chase-the-almighty-dollar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-we-dont-chase-the-almighty-dollar.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do Golf and Real Estate Have in Common?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s3owTyqqV-o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our warm weather is winding down here, but one of the things I really enjoy about both summer and autumn is that both seasons give us a chance to get outside and play golf. It’s a relatively new hobby of mine, and I’ve had a great time lately strengthening my game and thinking about how golf is like real estate.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Golf is different than my previous hobbies like quilting, gardening, or scrapbooking. Then I could produce something tangible to show for my efforts. In golf, when I have a great score, I still feel like I’ve accomplished something.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;How does this relate to real estate? &lt;strong&gt;Real estate has an end product as well.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the time, you have a closing at the end—someone bought a house and someone sold a house. Whether my clients get a paycheck, a new home, or something off their shoulders that they don’t have to think about anymore, it’s a great thing to look back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In both golf and real estate, I can depend on feedback in order to get better.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-golf-and-real-estate-have-in-common.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In both golf and real estate, I can depend on feedback in order to get better.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, when I make a mistake while golfing, I can ask for feedback from my group and advice to improve my game. When real estate issues come up, my amazing team provides feedback and advice on the best way to serve our client. It’s very much a group effort, and we have something great to show for it at the end.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;As you may have seen from my Facebook post this summer, I’m using the budget model of golf. This doesn’t mean it costs less money: rather, I’m squeezing every last pennies’ worth of value because my score(strokes) are so high. &lt;strong&gt;I’m going to enjoy my game, appreciate the people around me, and learn from my mistakes.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I was also fortunate enough to have been able to join golf and real estate in a literal sense when I sponsored a charity golf tournament this last summer for Leah’s Dream Foundation. Whenever I can put golf and real estate together, I get the chance to know people, serve them, and have a great time. So if I ever see you out on the golf course, be sure to come up and say hello!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;In the meantime, if you’re looking to sell or buy real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-golf-and-real-estate-have-in-common.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-golf-and-real-estate-have-in-common.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We're On It For Our Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-_r7xjoKyR4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before Thanksgiving, we were introduced to a couple who weren’t having much luck with their current agent. This agent was selling their house in Woodinville. She’d finally found them a buyer, but she was not returning phone calls and took days to follow up on requests. They knew that on their next purchase they needed an agent who was much more responsive. We talked with our couple that day, looked at five homes the next day, made two offers that night, and had one accepted by the weekend. &lt;strong&gt;We accomplished this even though this purchase was contingent on the their existing home selling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, it was time to schedule the inspection. It was really a clean house overall, and the inspector didn’t find many issues. Then we went out to the back porch, and the light wasn’t turning on. I thought that maybe the bulb just needed to be replaced, but the bulb just turned in circles when I tried to unscrew it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We take active responsibility and make things happen.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/were-on-it-for-our-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We take active responsibility and make things happen.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked the seller to make sure the light was working. To our surprise, they refused this simple repair. They said it had worked the night before, so the inspector must have broken it. Because I had tried to unscrew the light, I knew I could have been the one to break it. Either way, I wasn’t going to get in the way of my client’s dream home because of a broken light fixture. I volunteered to have the light fixed and we moved on with the deal.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;That’s just a little slice of what we do. &lt;strong&gt;If we cause a problem, we take responsibility to fix it.&lt;/strong&gt; We look for solutions, and we won’t let our pride jeopardize our clients’ goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/were-on-it-for-our-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/were-on-it-for-our-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Working with Our Team Benefits You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TKt0bZtHApk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re thinking of buying or selling a house, what you’re really thinking about is yourself. You aren’t thinking about your Realtor’s system and whether it’s set up to help you. Knowing whether that system involves working with a team or not, though, can prove critical.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some people might assume that more people means more problems, but that’s not usually true. Let me share an example.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Just this last month, we were working for one of our buyers who had a few hiccups in his transaction. When we initially wrote the offer, I knew his loan wasn’t going to be the easiest. Still, it was only a matter of following a step-by-step process. Which is why we asked for a six-week closing.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;After the listing agent talked with the seller, she came back to me and asked,”Could we close sooner?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;My standard response to this request is,”Sure, although we may ask for a couple extra days at the very end if we need them.” As per the listing agent’s wishes, we made the closing date sooner by about a week. From there, everything started moving forward—the client got the house, we completed the inspection and appraisal, and we were just about to get documents to escrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=On a team, everyone has to work together to find a solution.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-working-with-our-team-benefits-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“On a team, everyone has to work together to find a solution.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before the underwriter fully checked off, however, she realized that my client’s IRS auto-payment had not been deducted out of his account. Because we needed time to work with the IRS, we asked the seller for another week. Of course, the seller was not happy with this request. They were in the process of buying their own house, and they were getting charged by the builder every single day that they were late for that closing.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I felt very responsible for this quagmire until my office manager reminded me that we’d originally asked for this closing date. With this in mind, we went back to the listing agent and asked for the time back that we originally gave them. Doing that made our responsibility much easier to handle and freed us up to find a solution.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;So you see that &lt;strong&gt;when we have more people involved in a transaction, we work more efficiently to get the job done.&lt;/strong&gt; Let me know what we can do to get my team working for you, whether that means buying a house today or six months down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-working-with-our-team-benefits-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-working-with-our-team-benefits-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
