<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sandy and Company Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Sandy and Company - your professional Marysville Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 09:01:42 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 09:01:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Love Your Home Base</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Th7abje2X3c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the wet windy winter months, I like to hunker down in my home base and enjoy some of my favorite activities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whether it’s reading a good book, like John Eldredge’s “Moving Mountains,” journaling, or knitting,&lt;/strong&gt; I have been really enjoying making the most of my downtime. And of course for my yarn I go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greatyarns.com/&quot;&gt;Great Yarns&lt;/a&gt; in Everett. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I’m rarely without when I am home is a cup of tea. You’ve got to check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everythingtea.net/&quot;&gt;Everything Tea&lt;/a&gt; down on First Street. While you’re there you’ll find old favorites and new flavors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There is so much to do in the Pacific Northwest, even during these cool, wet days.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/love-your-home-base.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There is so much to do in the Pacific Northwest, even during these cool, wet days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re feeling adventurous enough to brave the winter weather, all it takes is a good stocking cap and rain gear to stay warm. We were just golfing over at&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://battlecreekgolfwa.com/&quot;&gt;Battle Creek Golf Course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in the chill. There is so much to do in the Pacific Northwest, even during these cool, wet days. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if your house doesn’t feel like home base, call me!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maybe it’s time for a new house that feels like a good place to call home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, feel free to give me a call or send me an email if you have any questions about real estate or anything I’ve mentioned here today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/love-your-home-base.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/love-your-home-base.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don't Get Your Real Estate Information From the News</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u8GCwBihAA4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where are you getting your “real estate IQ?” If most of your information has been coming from the news, you may want to start looking elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news isn’t off-the-mark with reports of low inventory. However, one thing you may not have seen reported in the media is information about current values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is because values will vary greatly depending on your location. The local area with the biggest rise in value last year was Bothell, &lt;strong&gt;where values moved from an average of $650,000 to an average of $730,000 at the end of the year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everett was a much different story. There, the average sales price of $472,000 dropped by $20,000 at the end of the year. Marysville saw similar changes, beginning at $393,000 at the start of autumn and dropping to $374,000 by the end of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the point is that you need to be educated. It’s important that you understand what is happening in your area so that you can stay in front of the market. &lt;strong&gt;We can’t decide what to do in the future by looking at the past&lt;/strong&gt;, so let’s make sure that your education is local. We can help you with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It is critical that you’re getting your information about the market from a full-time, professional Realtor.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/dont-get-your-real-estate-information-from-the-news.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It is critical that you’re getting your information about the market from a full-time, professional Realtor.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team and I just handed over keys to two families who were both affected by low appraisals in the last couple of months. One of them had the entire transaction fall apart because the seller would not allow us to educate them about the current market. At the end of the day, though, we were able to find this family another, better deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the other family we just worked with, the deal went smoothly because the seller allowed us to educate them. &lt;strong&gt;We showed them statistics and the seller worked with us to create a win-win situation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the most important thing is that you’re getting your information about the market from a full-time, professional Realtor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/dont-get-your-real-estate-information-from-the-news.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/dont-get-your-real-estate-information-from-the-news.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does Your Home Work for You in 2018?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H_eFwT-Hu7U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does your house work for you in 2018?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you get a new puppy for Christmas and now you need to put up a fence? I have a post hole digger I’d be glad to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/toolshed.html&quot;&gt;SandyAndCompanyVideos.com/Toolshed&lt;/a&gt; and browse all the tools we’d let you use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need a tool, but you don’t need to buy it, so let us be there for you if that’s your situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re  the resource to help you find the right person for the job.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/does-your-home-work-for-you-in-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re  the resource to help you find the right person for the job.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is the project bigger than just having the right tool? Let me help you find that right plumber, contractor, etc. We’re the resource to help you find the right person for that job as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking for myself, we’re finally adding our mud sink to the garage this year, so I’ll be calling the plumber to get that started this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, have you had kids move out (or back in) this year and the size of your house needs to change? &lt;strong&gt;Give me a call so we can talk about what your home needs to be in order to work for you and your family.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions or real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would love to help you. Until then, happy 2018 and have a super day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/does-your-home-work-for-you-in-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/does-your-home-work-for-you-in-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What We’re Grateful for This Christmas</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9LwnD12x4yg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Christmas season is a time for gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, my office manager Kerri is with me because we were just talking about what we’re grateful for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the main things we’re grateful for is the trust you put in us during your real estate transactions.&lt;/strong&gt; In these transactions there is so much at stake, so thank you for trusting us with those transactions and with your life. We are so grateful that we get to serve you and be a part of your life. Thank you for your trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We are so grateful that we get to be a part of your transaction and of your life.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-were-grateful-for-this-christmas.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We are so grateful that we get to be a part of your transaction and of your life.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kerri is also grateful for the ability to help all of you. “I truly love my job, and I am grateful for the flexibility that comes with that,” says Kerri. “At times I’m even able to do my job from home and spend a bit more time with my family while still serving you and being there when you need us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we’d like to send you a great big thank you this Christmas. We are excited to see what’s coming up in 2018. &lt;strong&gt;Have a wonderful Christmas and a great, safe New Year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, just give us a call. We look forward to seeing you in 2018!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-were-grateful-for-this-christmas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-were-grateful-for-this-christmas.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Puget Sound Market Is Only Going to Get More Competitive</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/seF0v0ieqRU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of buying a home this spring, then we have to talk right now to make this work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I constantly keep an eye on is our inventory. What’s happening with prices and the number of homes available for sale?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October of 2015, we had 2.2 months of supply. In October of 2016, we had 1.7 months of inventory. This past October, we only had 1.1 months of supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say there is only one month of inventory, that means that if no new homes came on the market, everything would be gone in just one month. &lt;strong&gt;That is the lowest amount of inventory that we have had in recorded history.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a dip in the springtime, so what does that leave us with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last spring, we were helping nine buyers. We found homes for seven of them, but we could not find homes for two of them. Last spring gave us a couple of black eyes. One buyer decided to buy in the south end of Puget Sound, while another decided to rent instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really hard. We had to ask buyers if they wanted to pay for an inspection before they even made an offer because we had to find ways to be competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Puget Sound only has 1.1 months of inventory, the least we’ve ever seen.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/the-puget-sound-market-is-only-going-to-get-more-competitive.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Puget Sound only has 1.1 months of inventory, the least we’ve ever seen.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If last spring gave us two black eyes, this spring will probably give us that along with a bloody nose. If you want to be in a home this spring, we need to talk right now about how to make this market work for you instead of against you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only ways buyers are going to have a chance is by &lt;strong&gt;losing contingencies and raising offer prices.&lt;/strong&gt; I would rather have you in a home by January or February and have that 10% price increase work in your favor instead of making you work even harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my seller clients said, “So if prices are going to be 10% higher this spring, shouldn’t I wait until spring to sell?” Maybe. However, if you are looking to buy a home at the same time, you will still have to go out and buy in the spring market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what market you are going to buy and sell in, you are going to buy and sell in that market. I recommend that you make that happen this winter. That way, you will have peace of mind in March, April, and May while everyone else is scrambling to find a home, because you already found the home that works for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, what if you don’t need to buy another home after you sell your current one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this market, even selling a home puts you in a high-pressure cooker atmosphere. When buyers are under pressure, they are not always so nice to deal with. That’s why we work to protect our sellers and get them top dollar in that pressure cooker environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about your home needs and what we can do for you today to get you ready for the next six months. Just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/the-puget-sound-market-is-only-going-to-get-more-competitive.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/the-puget-sound-market-is-only-going-to-get-more-competitive.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Know the Secret to Shaving Years off Your Mortgage?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hNnHyJvESSg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’ve got one easy way you can pay your mortgage off sooner and ultimately for less money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an American today, you’ve likely got a housing payment. This is true whether you rent or you own a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tip I have today can help regardless of where you’re trying to go, whether that is a paid-off mortgage or car, or getting to homeownership in general. Before I tell you what this tip is, understand that it’s a lot easier than it sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I recommend paying slightly more than you currently are.&lt;/strong&gt; If this doesn’t sound like saving money, let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of this year, I decided I wanted to be at a certain point in my mortgage at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I’m shaving 14 years off my mortgage by using this tip.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/do-you-know-the-secret-to-shaving-years-off-your-mortgage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I’m shaving 14 years off my mortgage by using this tip.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I found what I was paying in principal only each month, and where that would naturally put my mortgage balance by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I &lt;strong&gt;subtracted my goal number from the number it would be without any different payment. I divided that difference by 12 (for each month).&lt;/strong&gt; That number plus my regular payment was doable for me. If you are looking for wealth, use this tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much of a difference did this actually make? Well, using a loan term calculator that you can find &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.free-online-calculator-use.com/missing-term-loan-calculator.html#calculator&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, I did some math. It turns out that I’m shaving 14 years off my mortgage. &lt;strong&gt;Additionally, I’ll save about $90,000  in interest that I won’t have to pay.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us are guilty of simply seeing a number on our statement and just paying that particular amount. But this doesn’t have to be your strategy. Imagine all that you could be saving by using this simple tip. You can implement this incrementally, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you pay just $50 extra per month on your mortgage, you would still be shaving time and money off your mortgage payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These tips can help even if you aren’t currently paying a mortgage.&lt;/strong&gt; Let’s say you’re making car payments right now. Use the calculator to see how a little higher payment each month can make a big difference to your bottom line. This can apply to any payment plan you’re on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now remember, if you need to take care of other areas of your finances before you can implement this strategy, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daveramsey.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.DaveRamsey.com.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be a great steward of your resources. What you have is what you’ve been given to take care of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, if you are looking to sell or to buy a home in the next few months, we can help you with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/do-you-know-the-secret-to-shaving-years-off-your-mortgage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/do-you-know-the-secret-to-shaving-years-off-your-mortgage.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How You Can Be a Hero Around the Holiday Dinner Table</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jRbbX_Oj3sI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of great ways that you can be a hero around the Thanksgiving or Christmas dinner table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I talk with my clients and friends about how we can help their family and friends with their home purchase or sale, I often hear something like, “My sister would be a great person you could help.” Other times, I hear something like, “Well, my cousin Bob needs help, but you don’t want to work with him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may be able to help your cousin Bob and &lt;strong&gt;make you a hero by being his real estate resource.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our family and friends can be hard to please. Let me decide who I can best work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I work with them in a professional setting, I can be professional and let them know, “This is what I can do for you.” That helps them see what can happen and how we can get them there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Nine times out of 10, I help these referrals and end up liking them in the process.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-you-can-be-a-hero-around-the-holiday-dinner-table.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Nine times out of 10, I help these referrals and end up liking them in the process.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t always mean that it’s going to be peaches and cream or that I’m going to be sitting around eating pizza with them on a Seahawks game day. However, I can keep this transaction professional and still make them feel good since we were able to get their house sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first way you can be a hero is to tell your friend or relative, “You should talk to Sandy. She has helped a lot of people over the last 14 years and she has  great ideas to help you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is to tell them, “I’m going to have Sandy call you. Sandy has helped so many people in our area over the last 14 years. She is an expert and a resource. She’s patient and she will help you get through this process and get your next home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whether they need help buying or selling a home, introduce them to me.&lt;/strong&gt; Let me decide whether they’re too hard to work with. Usually I can set good professional boundaries. But if I can’t help them, I’ll tell them up-front. I don’t want them to spend a ton of energy and heartache on something that we both know isn’t going to work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, nine times out of 10 I do help them. And most of the time, I end up liking them in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have a cranky cousin or needy friend and you’re not sure I’ll love them, just give me a call. Those people need help too, and I would be honored with the introduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-you-can-be-a-hero-around-the-holiday-dinner-table.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-you-can-be-a-hero-around-the-holiday-dinner-table.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Common Misunderstandings Smart Sellers Still Have</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qpAigC-9lp4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying and selling real estate is a hot topic, both in the media and in casual conversation. A lot of people have experience buying and selling real estate, but sometimes that experience happened as far back as 20 years ago or in a different state than Washington. In real estate, things happen differently in different times and different areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, there are three main misunderstandings some of my smart sellers have had lately:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Who pays for what?&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes sellers assume that in this hot seller’s market they can get the buyer to pay their closing costs, right? Wrong. The seller always pays their own fees. There’s a title fee, an escrow fee, excise tax, and commissions. And the seller pays commissions for both the buyer’s and seller’s agent. Remember, current prices reflect a market where the seller customarily pays those fees, so you’re actually getting the money for it, just not until the very end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What is personal property?&lt;/strong&gt;I had a seller recently insist that the buyer pay him separately for his propane tank separately from the purchase price of the house. It took a while for him to understand that in this part of the country, the propane tank stays with the house because it’s connected to it and that’s how it gets its fuel. A lawnmower, on the other hand, is something you could sell to your buyer separately from the house’s purchase price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Talk to a Realtor you can trust to lead you down the right path of making smart decisions.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/3-common-misunderstandings-smart-sellers-still-have.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Talk to a Realtor you can trust to lead you down the right path of making smart decisions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What stays and what goes?&lt;/strong&gt; My rule of thumb is if it’s wired in, it stays. If it’s screwed in, it usually stays. One of the most common misunderstandings is curtains and blinds, which always stay with the house. Obviously, these items are of a personal taste, so if they’re something you want to take with you, by all means, take them down ahead of time. Don’t let someone else fall in love with your curtains—that’s disrupted more than one sale at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these things are common sense, and some can be a different way of viewing a real estate transaction. It doesn’t mean you’re stupid; it just means you’ve looked at something differently than the way it’s done here and now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why it’s so important to &lt;strong&gt;talk to a Realtor you can trust to lead you down the right path of making smart decisions&lt;/strong&gt; and you don’t end up shooting yourself in the foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this how it’s really done or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in our Puget Sound market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/3-common-misunderstandings-smart-sellers-still-have.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/3-common-misunderstandings-smart-sellers-still-have.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Few Ways to Add (and Subtract) Value From Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZB5prLFCUcQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about selling your home in the near future, making some upgrades isn’t a bad idea. However, you need to know the difference between which renovations you should do and which you should avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got six different upgrade tips for you today. Two of them are things you should absolutely do if they apply to you. Two of them are things that you want to do if you can afford them. There are also two upgrades that you shouldn’t even consider.
&lt;u&gt;The Must Do&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your siding.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have older siding that is buckling or expanding, it’s time to take a look at some new siding. Buyers will look at how well you took care of the structure of your home and if you’re letting water in through your siding, it doesn’t matter what your kitchen looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Replace aluminum windows.&lt;/strong&gt;Use vinyl, double-pane windows instead, so the buyer of your home has the lowest possible energy bills.
&lt;u&gt;The Want-to-Do&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The kitchen.&lt;/strong&gt; Making upgrades here can get you an 85% return on your investment. However, you want to keep the budget of this project within 20% of your home’s value so you don’t overbuild for your neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Replace aluminum windows with vinyl.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/a-few-ways-to-add-and-subtract-value-from-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Replace aluminum windows with vinyl.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The bathroom.&lt;/strong&gt; Another area that can get you great bang for your buck is the bathroom. You can get up to an 80% return.
&lt;u&gt;The Don&amp;rsquo;t Do&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Combining small rooms into larger rooms.&lt;/strong&gt; Any time you reduce the bedroom count in your home, its value is going to take a big hit, especially if you’re making a 3-bedroom a 2-bedroom. That’s going to drive away most of the families out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Remodel the garage space.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers are going to be looking at your garage space in terms of if it’s going to keep their vehicles dry and warm. If you decide to make part of your garage space a living space, make sure you can easily turn it back into a garage when the time comes to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With any improvement or upgrade you make, it’s first about getting joy out of it while you’re living in the home and then secondly passing that joy onto the next owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about any of these upgrades or any other decisions related to selling your home, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/a-few-ways-to-add-and-subtract-value-from-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/a-few-ways-to-add-and-subtract-value-from-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building Your Faith in Your Everyday Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/swEPkDyn0WU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may know that buying and selling real estate is one of the top five most stressful things that someone can go through in their life, right along with death, divorce, and losing a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my couples was buying a new home, and in the beginning it was a truly exciting time for them. But then they ran into an issue with the lender, who was creating problems where there weren’t any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, the husband told me something that I could totally relate to: “I know I’m supposed to give this to God, but I just keep going back and picking it back up again.” &lt;strong&gt;I’m sure you can relate to that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I began to look at their situation a little differently. God said repeatedly in the Bible, “Remember when…”  Over and over, he provided for his chosen people what they needed, at the exact moment that they needed it. And then God told them to remember those times of his provision when they had another crisis. These memories built their faith and confidence. &lt;strong&gt;So I told my client, “I think the Lord is creating a ‘remember when’ moment for you.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t remember when he did great things for us if we didn’t have those moments to go through in the first place. Later on, he’ll remember that the Lord’s provision came through for him before. And it will again. Because God’s goodness never changes- he is the same yesterday, today and tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The  Bible helps us understand what’s happening in our lives at the current moment.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/building-your-faith-in-your-everyday-life.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The  Bible helps us understand what’s happening in our lives at the current moment.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reminded my client that even though the situation seemed hopeless to him, if he stopped worrying about what-if’s and focused instead on building that airplane (he’s a Boeing guy), and let God take care of this, he was going to turn out okay. Ultimately, the lender referred us to someone else who could finish his loan. Eight days after we began working with this new lender, I was handing my clients the keys to their new home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God promises to provide for us.&lt;/strong&gt; He says in Deuteronomy 31:6, “Be strong and courageous. Do not be afraid or terrified because of them, for the Lord your God goes with you; he will never leave you nor forsake you.” That’s echoed in Hebrew 13:5. Philippians 4:19 says “And my God will supply all your needs according to the riches of his glory in Christ Jesus.” All means ALL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bible helps us understand what’s happening in our lives at the current moment. In the same way, our real-life issues aren’t just earthly conversations—that’s why we must invite God into them on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was such a joy to be able to work with my client through this situation and share this faith experience with him. If there is anything that I can do to help you and your family, whether it be real estate or otherwise, please give me a call. I would be honored to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/building-your-faith-in-your-everyday-life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/building-your-faith-in-your-everyday-life.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
