<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sandy and Company Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from -- CLIENT BRAND -- - your professional -- MARKET -- Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 10:29:46 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 10:29:46 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Donate to Your Local Food Bank This Fall</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0iOUGWOcjEs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall can be a really exciting time. The leaves start turning, the air gets crisp, and the holidays are just around the corner. When everything is groovy around you — the roof over your head is solid and your cupboards are full — it’s easy to think of the fall as a harvest time, a time of ample supply. Unfortunately, that is not the case for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Marysville community, we have a large population of people who are either hungry or on the verge of hunger. This is true in every community, including Everett, Stanwood, and Lake Stevens. Jesus said that the poor will always be with you, but we don’t want them to be the same people all the time. It’s really important to make sure that we do what we can as the hands and the feet of Jesus, caring for our neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus also said that when you give out a cup of water in His name, you are giving it to Him. We need to help our communities in tangible ways. &lt;strong&gt;October is the food drive month for Realtors&lt;/strong&gt;, and that’s why I’m sending you this. If you can, please drop off food or cash donations to our office and we will deliver them to the Marysville Food Bank. I can even swing by and pick up your donations from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not from Marysville but would like to support the food bank, let me know. I can put you in touch with someone either in Marysville or in your own community. Remember, it’s important to give where you live.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Let's be good neighbors to each other.%20localhost:4000/donate-to-your-local-food-bank-this-fall.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Let’s be good neighbors to each other.”&lt;/a&gt;
One reason the food bank is so near to my heart is that when I was a child, we often got those baskets of food. We got the commodity cheese, powdered scrambled eggs, and powdered milk from the government. I didn’t even like real milk when I first tried it because I wasn’t used to it. It’s very important to me that when I am experiencing abundance that I give back as well. &lt;strong&gt;Please help us be a resource for others.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are on the other side of this — if you are struggling right now, please let me know. I can put you in touch with someone who can help you. The Everett Gospel Mission not only helps people with housing, they will also give you a bag of food. They even have a little store that you can walk through complete with household items, clothes, and food that you can have for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this fall, let’s be good neighbors to each other. If you are my neighbor and you need help, please open up. I am here to help you. At Keller Williams, we are a team. TEAM stands for Together Everyone Achieves More. Let’s work together to put food on the table for our neighbors and make our community a great place to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, if you have any donations for our food bank, just drop them off at our office at 1027 State Ave #102 in Marysville. If you can’t make the trip, let me know and I will collect the donations for you. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 12:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/donate-to-your-local-food-bank-this-fall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/donate-to-your-local-food-bank-this-fall.html</guid>
        
        <category>Other</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Our Buyer Shrunk Her Home and Evaporated Her Mortgage Payment</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OJ9524rMVF8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to tell you a story about a Baby Boomer buyer we just helped downsize and why she’s so excited about her brand new home in her retirement years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a call from a lender with a client who was very stressed out–she had a nearly 4,000 sq. ft. house with three living spaces and a huge garage. It was an older brick home that needed some paint and just some all-around love. The payment was also huge, nearly $4,000. It was just too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She has been working hard all her life and is coming up on retirement. She was also having a hard time making ends meet because of this monstrous payment and all the maintenance required.&lt;/strong&gt; So my lender spoke with her about her whole financial situation and found that she was in a position to buy a reverse mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, a reverse mortgage is not for everyone and there are some important criteria to consider, so I’ll refer you to my lender for that conversation if it’s one you want to have.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Where are you in the cycle of your home life?%20localhost:4000/how-our-buyer-shrunk-her-home-and.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Where are you in the cycle of your home life?”&lt;/a&gt;
With the reverse mortgage, &lt;strong&gt;our buyer was able to put down a significant chunk for a down payment, and now she’s not going to have a payment for the rest of time she lives in her home.&lt;/strong&gt; All she has to do is maintain her insurance, taxes, and the home itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at houses, she needed something with separate spaces for both herself and her adult son who lived with her. We were able to find her a split-level home where he has the lower level and she has the upstairs, and the home is much newer than her previous home. It’s perfect for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this was the very first house we looked at. We looked at a couple others, but the first house ended up being her perfect home. It really does happen once in a while. We’re getting her previous home ready for the market, and we know it will be perfect for someone needing more space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking into your retirement years and you’re thinking about your house and your mortgage, I’d love to talk with you about it. The question is this–where are you in the cycle of your home life? Give me a call or send me an email and we’ll talk soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 12:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-our-buyer-shrunk-her-home-and.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-our-buyer-shrunk-her-home-and.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Win as a Buyer in Today’s Market </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PGEO9erJmRk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a tough market out there for buyers right now and it’s important that you work with the right agent. Our team works hard to help buyers win in this market, and you should make sure you work with an agent who knows how to compete with other offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I was doing an open house for one of my sellers. It was a hot listing that went on the market Wednesday and by Saturday, we already had a full-price offer in place. However, we still held open houses that weekend because we had already said we would wait to review offers that Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the buyers who walked in had seen our advertising and really wanted to check out the home. However, they were also bummed because they had just lost out on a house. I said, “I know, it’s a pretty tough market out there. We’re doing a lot of escalation clauses.” I mentioned a few other things we do to help our buyers get ahead in the current market, and they just said, “What’s that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their reaction really gave me pause because we talk about how &lt;strong&gt;we can help our buyers win so frequently that it just becomes an automatic part of our process.&lt;/strong&gt; There are tools you can use to make your offer better than someone else’s and there are ways to put your best offer forward. You don’t have to max out your budget right away; you can start out softer so that you are able to get stronger down the line, and we can help you get that house.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We have tools and strategies to help buyers win in this tough market.%20localhost:4000/how-to-win-as-buyer-in-todays-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We have tools and strategies to help buyers win in this tough market.”&lt;/a&gt;
I took the time to educate this buyer, which still benefits my seller. “Let’s say we have a full-price offer. Here is how you might craft your offer to get the home.” They hadn’t heard any of these strategies before. But they still thought it didn’t matter because the main problem was the seller probably wouldn’t pay the closing costs. My answer? “That’s no problem at all!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most sellers are willing to pay closing costs, especially if they get the price they want for the house. I gave them a few different points to make their offer better. They went back to their own agent and wrote their own offer. The agent called me the next day with some questions. The buyer wound up getting the house for $15,000 less than their max and my seller was able to get $5,000 more than they expected, even after paying the buyers’ closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can make this happen for you.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t assume that just because your agent is part of a big team means they will know, understand and use all of the strategies necessary to win in this tough market. Talk to your agent about what happens when you’re in a bidding war. If you’re not sure what questions to ask them, give me a call and I can help you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 15:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-win-as-buyer-in-todays-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-win-as-buyer-in-todays-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Be a Savvy Investor by Using a Tax Deferred Exchange</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gNNBqxskCiE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an investor looking to sell a property you didn’t live in and avoid paying the capital gains tax on the sale, you need to think about using a tax deferred exchange. That means, basically, rolling the profit you’d make from that sale directly into your next purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our market, it’s the perfect time to sell. Is it the perfect time to buy for an investment property, though?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you sell a 1,500 square foot house and buy a 2,500 square foot house. Then, let’s say you sold that slightly bigger house and bought a duplex. With those three purchases, &lt;strong&gt;you’re getting a bigger investment and putting your equity to work for you by having your tenants pay rent, and still not paying any capital gains tax.&lt;/strong&gt; You’re delaying paying any meaningful taxes until further down the road when you’re not in your strongest income years.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you're an investor, you need to think about using a tax deferred exchange.%20localhost:4000/be-savvy-investor-by-using-tax-deferred.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re an investor, you need to think about using a tax deferred exchange.”&lt;/a&gt;
The question, then, isn’t whether investing in real estate is a good idea, but how to do it in a savvy manner. I have no problem paying taxes; I just don’t plan to be paying more than I need to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any of this interests you, reach out to me by giving me a call or sending me an email. I’m excited to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 16:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/be-savvy-investor-by-using-tax-deferred.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/be-savvy-investor-by-using-tax-deferred.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips and Tricks</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How a $10 Wax Ring Could Save You $10,000</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nOqqobSO9fo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you know about the wax rings on toilets? It’s a very sexy topic, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had two different clients whose inspectors found leaking toilets. In fact, one of the leaks had spread underneath both the bathtub and the surrounding ceramic tile floor. And the seller refused to handle that repair, so my buyer inherited this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This turned out to be a $10,000 repair job!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know how much a new wax ring around that toilet would have cost? About $8. If that seller had replaced the wax ring when needed, the entire $10,000 repair job could have disappeared. Good thing my buyer is planning to do some remodeling in the future, but he still had to spend $2,500 to repair just the minimum damage.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Wouldn't you spend $8 to save $10,000?%20localhost:4000/how-10-wax-ring-could-save-you-10000.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Wouldn’t you spend $8 to save $10,000?”&lt;/a&gt;
So this led me to do some research on toilet maintenance (yeah, it’s a glamorous job being your Realtor resource!). After all, it’s hard to notice a leak when it’s under ceramic tile. What I found is that &lt;strong&gt;a properly installed wax ring should protect for 10 to 20 years.&lt;/strong&gt; So even if all seems well but it has been 10 or 12 years, pick a day. Drain the toilet and replace the wax ring, because it doesn’t cost much at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And do it right! Failing to install a wax ring properly can be just as expensive as having it fail on its own. Further, it can also cause dangerous sewer gas to enter your home.That ring connects the toilet to the floor, acting like a caulking that keeps water and sewer gas from leaking out. But even if you want to hire a professional to ensure it’s done completely correctly, it will only cost you a couple hundred bucks, instead of $10,000!  It’s not worth the risk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you notice any issue with your floor, take care of it quickly. $8? or $10,000? I know which one I’d rather leave in my pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-10-wax-ring-could-save-you-10000.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-10-wax-ring-could-save-you-10000.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips and Tricks</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Agents Must Take the Lead through the Home Sale Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EUm7CZBqaQ0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legal deadlines are one of the most important facets of real estate, so it’s important to &lt;strong&gt;have the help of your real estate expert with you all along the way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, you sign a contract and in 30 days, the buyer has the keys. This is a really complicated transaction though, with legal and physical issues, lender criteria, and much more in between. It’s our job to understand this process so we can assure your success down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We track when your loan gets out of the underwriting process, so you have time to sign disclosures and have the correct documents reviewed. There may also be agreed-upon repairs to inspect prior to closing. Sometimes these repairs aren’t done to the buyer’s satisfaction, which can cause a lot of heartache and delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We deal with the appraiser who may expect things to be done a certain way as well. Appraisers can’t simply take our word that repairs were done right on the home - they re-inspect as well. &lt;strong&gt;Many things happen in 30 to 45 days, and much gets pushed into the last two weeks.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ll make sure you have a Plan A, B, and C to achieve your real estate goals.%20localhost:4000/agents-must-take-lead-through-home-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ll make sure you have a Plan A, B, and C to achieve your real estate goals.”&lt;/a&gt;
Both buyers and sellers have other issues going on in their lives, which also complicates matters. For instance, the seller may be buying a new home too, and they’re being held accountable to their seller to get the funds for their closing. &lt;strong&gt;If they can’t close on the home you’re buying, they may not be able to close in time on their next home.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s extremely stressful. Consider services like a moving truck as well: many are booked three weeks in advance, and can’t accommodate changes on two days’ notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job as a consultant is to talk with you about all these different issues and to ensure that you’re prepared for Plan B and maybe even Plan C. We want to make sure that if we don’t take the exact path we planned on taking at the beginning, we still get you to your destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the real estate process or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in Puget Sound, give me a call today. Make it a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 12:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/agents-must-take-lead-through-home-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/agents-must-take-lead-through-home-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To Permit or Not To Permit</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7g2MDay-RRY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When homeowners are going to build or remodel something in their home, do they really need a permit? &lt;strong&gt;It might seem tempting to just skip this step, but as you’ll see, it can have some horrendous consequences.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A client of mine is currently buying a home here in Washington. However, he needs to sell his home in Alaska first. Things were going just great until he found out that there was a problem with the garage he had built behind his Alaska home. The county found that the garage was built three feet into the setback from the property line. &lt;strong&gt;He had to go in front of the zoning board to ask for a variance to be able to sell his property with the garage. They said no.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the owner has to take three feet off his garage, and that involves removing the stairs, the roof, and changing the foundation.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It's important to consider all the possible consequences.%20localhost:4000/to-permit-or-not-to-permit.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s important to consider all the possible consequences.”&lt;/a&gt;
He thought he was making the right move because he was very handy and knew how to build a garage. What he did not take into account was that he needed a permit. If he would have spent the $100 or so to get the permit, he could have discovered the setback and updated his building plans accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now it is going to cost him more than $18,000 to remove three feet from the corner of his garage.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re confident that we’ll be able to find a solution in the end, but the transaction is a hot mess right now. He’s wishing he got that permit right about now, and you would too if this happened to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when you’re considering a remodel or home improvement project, ask yourself what the possible consequences could be. If they’re anywhere near the trouble that this seller had to go through, go ahead and get a permit. It will save you much more in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: As it turns out, this my client &lt;strong&gt;had&lt;/strong&gt; originally gotten the permit for his garage. However, &lt;strong&gt;he changed the project plans&lt;/strong&gt; after getting the permit and did not check with the county. He wanted the lines of the garage to match his house instead of the property line. So he turned the garage, and that’s when the corner of the garage pushed into that setback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since he didn’t follow up with anyone about his permit after changing the plans, he’s dealing with a lot of heartache along with the almost $20,000. &lt;strong&gt;He lost his Alaska buyer and the Washington home he was hoping to move into.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is still a lesson in not only acquiring a permit, but following a permit closely.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 09:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/to-permit-or-not-to-permit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/to-permit-or-not-to-permit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips and Tricks</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer 2016 Home Price Update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Clients and friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have an important update for you about the value of your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following the news, the Federal Reserve is likely to raise interest rates when they meet on June 15th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been all over the news these past few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;auto&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/G_TlL1xnaekd4O_hAD-TngmzteYPF8d3e4ytlf1ZOG4s7SQ20XLO3II0D4fLvyHA6ZO2k1xHnv9y6LDH-pyw9vukqsN-nWo8zKWWT-Nm7cMJwVUBypBZ4889XpGlgONK-0OLS1o6&quot; style=&quot;border: none; transform: rotate(0rad);&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://nypost.com/2016/05/23/why-the-federal-reserve-has-to-raise-interest-rates/&quot;&gt;Why the Federal Reserve has to raise interest rates&lt;/a&gt;
This makes it more expensive for people to own a home by raising their mortgage payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also decreases your pool of buyers thus lowering your home value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, after a 6-year record run up in home prices since the 2008-2009 recession, &lt;strong&gt;this may be the last year to get the maximum price on your home sale.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s likely we’ll see a market correction next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still seeing neighborhoods with very tight inventory. This means if you list your home for sale, it will sell quickly and in many neighborhoods above asking price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I write you because this summer is the best year to sell your home to get the maximum price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking about selling your home, I have a special gift for you…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the latest housing data from the market. It will give you a good guideline of where the market is going but at the end of the day, the best way to get up-to-date information about the market is by speaking with an expert, like the members of our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find out what your home is worth right now based on your neighbor’s recent home sale price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to know what your home would sell for today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sandyandcompany.blogspot.com/p/home-value-report.html&quot;&gt;Enter your home address here to learn what price your home is worth.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a short visit to your home, I’ll fill you in on what price it will sell for today at no charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve worked with many home buyers recently and know exactly what people are looking for in the hottest homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My estimates are right on the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And not to worry - if you’re thinking about buying a new home, I’ll share with you the neighborhoods where home prices are now more affordable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be able to live in a nicer area you previously thought unaffordable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also help you secure a low, fixed rate mortgage without junk fees with a minimal down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll put you in touch with my best preferred lenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anyway, I write you since we’re wrapping up one of the hottest home selling seasons ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our economy is normalizing, interest rates are rising, and pent-up demand following the 2008-2009 recession is less. This is the summer to sell your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I invite you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://sandyandcompany.blogspot.com/p/home-value-report.html&quot;&gt;find out what your home will sell for&lt;/a&gt;. It’s free to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also email or call me at (425) 422-7372 or &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#083;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#121;&amp;#064;&amp;#083;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#121;&amp;#065;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#067;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&amp;#112;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#121;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#083;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#121;&amp;#064;&amp;#083;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#121;&amp;#065;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#067;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&amp;#112;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#121;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;. I’m happy to answer any questions you have about real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 13:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/summer-2016-home-price-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/summer-2016-home-price-update.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now Is the Time for Sellers to Act</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q5zXxBWwSDU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the Puget Sound area and haven’t been able to sell your home in the last few years because your value isn’t quite where you want it to be, we’ve got some great information to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A homeowner reached out to me about a month and a half ago. They had tried to sell last year, but they owed more than their market value. When they’d bought, they needed all 3200 square feet: they had three children at home and were holding church services in their bonus room. But now it was time to downsize, both for size and money. The husband had just changed jobs and travels a lot, so they weren’t even sure whether Snohomish County was where they wanted to be. Two of the three children are moving out in the fall. Their budget was stretched, the market is peaking, and they knew it was time to sell.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can accomplish your selling goals in today's market.%20localhost:4000/now-is-time-for-sellers-to-act.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can accomplish your selling goals in today’s market.”&lt;/a&gt;
After looking at the home, we decided that if the home was going to sell, this was the market to do it in. We did our full marketing blitz, including personally inviting the neighbors to our open house that had about 30 buyers go through. We really pushed the top of the market with our price, and we were hoping for one or two good offers. We had several people come through multiple times, and the right buyer showed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We secured a full-price offer for our sellers, and the home sale just closed. This family decided to rent so they have the flexibility to decide where they want to settle in the next year. They have 1,500 less square feet to clean, pay $1,000 less per month on their rent, and they accomplished all of this in today’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are at the peak of the market, the growth is slowing. There’s a shift coming up, so your top window of opportunity in this market is closing. Who do you know who we can help with our expert service and proven systems to get top dollar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know has been wondering whether it’s the right time to sell, we would be happy to talk to you. Just give us a call or send us an email and we’ll be in touch!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/now-is-time-for-sellers-to-act.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/now-is-time-for-sellers-to-act.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Puget Sound Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/R32mUxm23hk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our real estate market has been wildly hot for the past few years. It’s even been so good that some people think we’d made another bubble, but we’re starting to see some of that growth slow down. Between January 2015 to 2016, we experienced 11% growth in our market. That is pretty typical from what we have been seeing, but from month to month after January, we have seen that growth trickle slowly down to 8%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean for you? If you’re thinking of selling, you may want to do so soon. Prices are still rising, and they certainly won’t be falling, but you may be better off selling your home right now. Most people look to the past to predict their outcome, but I have to look towards the future for you, and our market is slowing down.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Market growth is slowing, but that doesn't mean it's a bad time to buy or sell.%20localhost:4000/puget-sound-real-estate-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Market growth is slowing, but that doesn’t mean it’s a bad time to buy or sell.”&lt;/a&gt;
I can’t tell you what the future will be like, but I can tell you that growth is slowing for right now. This doesn’t mean you need to rush to get your home on the market, but it’s a good idea to step in sooner than later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re buying, this slowing is helping you. Remember that interest rates are still very low. This is why you need to call me and discuss all the factors in our market that affect your home search. Give me a call today!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/puget-sound-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/puget-sound-real-estate-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
