<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sandy and Company Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from -- CLIENT BRAND -- - your professional -- MARKET -- Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:23:18 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:23:18 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Avoid Impulse and Buyer's Remorse</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YcjC_vyrueM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever made an impulsive decision and later realized you forgot to consider a number of important things? Many buyers just like you are afraid of this when a house is listed for sale and multiple offers seem to appear within minutes. &lt;strong&gt;This is what we help our buyers avoid. The last thing I want is for you to have buyer’s remorse when you make such a big purchase.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Finding the right home in this impulsive market comes down to being purposeful.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-we-avoid-impulse-and-buyers-remorse.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Finding the right home in this impulsive market comes down to being purposeful.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purposeful is a word that gets used a lot. For us, it means helping our buyers know what’s most important ahead of time. Then they know they made a wise decision when they bought a home. When we sit down with you for the first time, we talk about what’s important to you and why. We go through categories to make sure you’ve thought of everything. We talk about things like the number of bedrooms and bathrooms that you want. Then if you say you need two bathrooms, for example, does that mean you need a bathtub in that second bathroom or is a shower or just a powder room okay? These questions help us understand the reasons behind the amount of real estate you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my buyers tell me about houses they see somewhere else, I take a look at why they saw it and I didn’t. Is there something I wasn’t considering? Or was there something I thought was important that’s not? One of the biggest factors is location—a buyer might want a certain community, school district, or commute, but then send me a home that’s two school districts away. &lt;strong&gt;That’s when we have that conversation about what’s really most important.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we can back away from the house and talk about what’s most important to you, then we can be purposeful and help you make the right choice. This isn’t the market for buyers to jump up and grab whatever comes along. It’s a market to be careful, wise, and patient. And when the right home comes along, jump quickly and aggressively to win the home they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s anything we can do for you in this hot market, give me a call or send me an email today. I’d be happy to let you know how we can help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-we-avoid-impulse-and-buyers-remorse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-we-avoid-impulse-and-buyers-remorse.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Staging Tips that Earn You Thousands</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pu1eM3DDo1k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably already know that when you sell a home, it’s not the same as when you live in a home. With that in mind, I have four tips for you to stage your home and sell for top dollar in today’s market.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;My first tip is to make a good first impression because &lt;strong&gt;the first impression is the lasting impression.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers take about three to five seconds to make that first impression when they pull up to the house, so clean up the exterior, add some color to the porch, and make sure your trim is freshly painted. When buyers walk into your home, you have another three to five seconds to cement that first impression.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;This leads me to my next tip—&lt;strong&gt;always be show ready.&lt;/strong&gt; In the mornings and evenings, take a look at each room and make sure everything is how you want a buyer to see the house as they walk through it. One great tip I got from Flylady.net is to go through your house every night and pick up the misplaced things you see in each room. Then, when you get the call that someone is coming for a showing, have a list of “hot spots” to take a look at where you know things tend to accumulate quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Use these four tips to get your home sold today for top dollar.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/staging-tips-that-earn-you-thousands.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Use these four tips to get your home sold today for top dollar.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My third tip is to &lt;strong&gt;take the “home” out of your house.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, you need to take personalized items like your family photos down. These photos cause buyers to see your family in the home instead of theirs. And the infamous photo wall hallways– they make buyers uncomfortable from the lack of perceived space when walking down that hallway.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Next, put away about one-third of your stuff. If you have extra bookcases, tables, or trunks that are making any walkways smaller or more inconvenient, remove them. I‘m not a fan of long-term storage units, but they can come in handy when storing these items in the short term. Also, make sure all your closets are half-empty. You want people to look inside of them and see that there’s plenty of room for clothes.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;My last and most important tip is to&lt;strong&gt; hire an informed, professional agent and price it right.&lt;/strong&gt; Pricing is critical when it comes to getting your home sold for top dollar in today’s market. I can’t tell you how many times- even this last year- I’ve seen people list their home for more than it’s worth and end up taking even less than they should have in the end. Hire an agent who’s doing business right now and understands what’s happening in your neighborhood.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions about staging or are thinking about selling your home, please give me a call. I am happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/staging-tips-that-earn-you-thousands.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/staging-tips-that-earn-you-thousands.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why We Don’t Chase the Almighty Dollar</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tVsA8gQEHsI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I wanted to talk about sales—how I serve you, and how that service also serves me at the same time.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Picture a salesperson. Sometimes, I hear from people about what that picture looks like to them. In the last month, I’ve had two people share their assumptions of what it means to make a living from sales. Their emphasis was on the “sales” portion of that paradigm. Let me tell you: at Sandy and Company, &lt;strong&gt;we’re on the opposite side.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;At Keller Williams Realty, just like in many other businesses, we have mottos. One of these is “Customers always comes first.” If I can’t get a customer what they’re looking for, I will tell them. Likewise, when I believe I can help, I jump right in and make it happen.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Going back to the two who shared with me. One of them said he knew I was tempted to withhold information about what might be wrong with the house in the name of getting the sale done. I told him that wasn’t true at all. Don’t get me wrong, I have temptations, but that’s never one of them.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;In the other conversation, she assumed my goal is to push my clients to the very top of their purchase point. In theory, that would serve me best. Once again, I had to correct her. That’s never my goal. as long as we can meet their home needs for less. On the contrary, I love it when my clients purchase well below their price points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=My job is to serve you—not the almighty dollar.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-we-dont-chase-the-almighty-dollar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“My job is to serve you—not the almighty dollar.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because my goal is to make sure that I serve your whole life situation. This means &lt;strong&gt;what’s most important is meeting your needs in the long run.&lt;/strong&gt; If a client of mine purchases for less than they can afford, that means they could save extra money for other needs in their life. And when I serve you well, you are going to be so excited that someone is taking great care of you and giving you all of their expertise and knowledge. You’re going to tell others about me, and that meets my needs in the long run.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I’m in sales, there is a transaction happening, but what I’m thinking about is how I can serve you today.&lt;/strong&gt; If that means we make a transaction together, great! If not, I’m satisfied as long as I know that I helped you. My clients know that about me, which make them comfortable to introduce me to their friends, family and colleagues.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Just yesterday, some clients and I let go of a project we had been working on for six months. It was an arduous process, and we weren’t sure it was going to work, but we gave it a shot anyway. When the numbers didn’t add up in the end and my clients asked to kill the deal, I understood completely. My job is to serve you—not the almighty dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy or sell real estate, please give me a call or shoot me an email. If I’m not the right person for the job, I promise you I’ll find someone who is. I look forward to helping you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-we-dont-chase-the-almighty-dollar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-we-dont-chase-the-almighty-dollar.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do Golf and Real Estate Have in Common?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s3owTyqqV-o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our warm weather is winding down here, but one of the things I really enjoy about both summer and autumn is that both seasons give us a chance to get outside and play golf. It’s a relatively new hobby of mine, and I’ve had a great time lately strengthening my game and thinking about how golf is like real estate.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Golf is different than my previous hobbies like quilting, gardening, or scrapbooking. Then I could produce something tangible to show for my efforts. In golf, when I have a great score, I still feel like I’ve accomplished something.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;How does this relate to real estate? &lt;strong&gt;Real estate has an end product as well.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the time, you have a closing at the end—someone bought a house and someone sold a house. Whether my clients get a paycheck, a new home, or something off their shoulders that they don’t have to think about anymore, it’s a great thing to look back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In both golf and real estate, I can depend on feedback in order to get better.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-golf-and-real-estate-have-in-common.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In both golf and real estate, I can depend on feedback in order to get better.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, when I make a mistake while golfing, I can ask for feedback from my group and advice to improve my game. When real estate issues come up, my amazing team provides feedback and advice on the best way to serve our client. It’s very much a group effort, and we have something great to show for it at the end.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;As you may have seen from my Facebook post this summer, I’m using the budget model of golf. This doesn’t mean it costs less money: rather, I’m squeezing every last pennies’ worth of value because my score(strokes) are so high. &lt;strong&gt;I’m going to enjoy my game, appreciate the people around me, and learn from my mistakes.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I was also fortunate enough to have been able to join golf and real estate in a literal sense when I sponsored a charity golf tournament this last summer for Leah’s Dream Foundation. Whenever I can put golf and real estate together, I get the chance to know people, serve them, and have a great time. So if I ever see you out on the golf course, be sure to come up and say hello!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;In the meantime, if you’re looking to sell or buy real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-golf-and-real-estate-have-in-common.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-golf-and-real-estate-have-in-common.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We're On It For Our Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-_r7xjoKyR4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before Thanksgiving, we were introduced to a couple who weren’t having much luck with their current agent. This agent was selling their house in Woodinville. She’d finally found them a buyer, but she was not returning phone calls and took days to follow up on requests. They knew that on their next purchase they needed an agent who was much more responsive. We talked with our couple that day, looked at five homes the next day, made two offers that night, and had one accepted by the weekend. &lt;strong&gt;We accomplished this even though this purchase was contingent on the their existing home selling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, it was time to schedule the inspection. It was really a clean house overall, and the inspector didn’t find many issues. Then we went out to the back porch, and the light wasn’t turning on. I thought that maybe the bulb just needed to be replaced, but the bulb just turned in circles when I tried to unscrew it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We take active responsibility and make things happen.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/were-on-it-for-our-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We take active responsibility and make things happen.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked the seller to make sure the light was working. To our surprise, they refused this simple repair. They said it had worked the night before, so the inspector must have broken it. Because I had tried to unscrew the light, I knew I could have been the one to break it. Either way, I wasn’t going to get in the way of my client’s dream home because of a broken light fixture. I volunteered to have the light fixed and we moved on with the deal.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;That’s just a little slice of what we do. &lt;strong&gt;If we cause a problem, we take responsibility to fix it.&lt;/strong&gt; We look for solutions, and we won’t let our pride jeopardize our clients’ goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/were-on-it-for-our-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/were-on-it-for-our-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Working with Our Team Benefits You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TKt0bZtHApk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re thinking of buying or selling a house, what you’re really thinking about is yourself. You aren’t thinking about your Realtor’s system and whether it’s set up to help you. Knowing whether that system involves working with a team or not, though, can prove critical.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some people might assume that more people means more problems, but that’s not usually true. Let me share an example.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Just this last month, we were working for one of our buyers who had a few hiccups in his transaction. When we initially wrote the offer, I knew his loan wasn’t going to be the easiest. Still, it was only a matter of following a step-by-step process. Which is why we asked for a six-week closing.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;After the listing agent talked with the seller, she came back to me and asked,”Could we close sooner?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;My standard response to this request is,”Sure, although we may ask for a couple extra days at the very end if we need them.” As per the listing agent’s wishes, we made the closing date sooner by about a week. From there, everything started moving forward—the client got the house, we completed the inspection and appraisal, and we were just about to get documents to escrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=On a team, everyone has to work together to find a solution.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-working-with-our-team-benefits-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“On a team, everyone has to work together to find a solution.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before the underwriter fully checked off, however, she realized that my client’s IRS auto-payment had not been deducted out of his account. Because we needed time to work with the IRS, we asked the seller for another week. Of course, the seller was not happy with this request. They were in the process of buying their own house, and they were getting charged by the builder every single day that they were late for that closing.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I felt very responsible for this quagmire until my office manager reminded me that we’d originally asked for this closing date. With this in mind, we went back to the listing agent and asked for the time back that we originally gave them. Doing that made our responsibility much easier to handle and freed us up to find a solution.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;So you see that &lt;strong&gt;when we have more people involved in a transaction, we work more efficiently to get the job done.&lt;/strong&gt; Let me know what we can do to get my team working for you, whether that means buying a house today or six months down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-working-with-our-team-benefits-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-working-with-our-team-benefits-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do We Go the Extra Mile(s) for Our Clients?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LpIEy36FSSw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean for us to go the extra mile for one of our clients? Let me tell you a story.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;A few months ago, I got an email from one of my past clients who needed to sell his home and buy a new one for him and his fiance. We were excited to help him. Ultimately, he chose a home in Monroe. We competed for this house against another buyer and won. When we scheduled the inspection, though, we found that the roof was toast and asked the seller to replace it.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The seller took this request hard because he had just put $20,000 into the house to fix it up after he had renters in it. Since he decided it was too much for him to handle, we offered to split the cost with him. We raised the price of the house a little bit, but that wasn’t a problem for my buyer because he was going to get the full value of that roof. To give the seller confidence that we weren’t going anywhere after they put another $7,000 into their house, we also agreed to make our earnest money non-refundable after the roof was finished.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Everything moved along nicely…until the house didn’t appraise. We went back and forth a couple times with the seller and his agent, but the seller wouldn’t budge. He wanted every single penny that he had originally been promised. My buyer, though, was not going to pay more for the house than he could finance, and he wasn’t going to pay more than what it was worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=On our team, we work to find solutions.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-do-we-go-the-extra-miles-for-our-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“On our team, we work to find solutions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, &lt;strong&gt;we started talking with our lender about different finance options that could breathe life into this transaction.&lt;/strong&gt; My lender suggested raising the interest rate a little bit so that instead of my buyer having to bring in his money to pay for his own closing costs, he could use it as a down payment and cover the roof expense. The process was a tad complicated, but the numbers equaled out in the end and my buyer was excited to hear about this compromise.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;When I emailed our proposal to the seller’s agent, I got no response. So I reached out again, with still no response. I decided then that I needed to jump in and make this deal personal. In our business, we don’t have a lot of face-to-face conferencing anymore. Communication in today’s real estate transactions rely on text and email. &lt;strong&gt;I decided, though, that it was time to show up at this agent’s office.&lt;/strong&gt; I cleared my calendar and got in my car. When I arrived, he was in the middle of a meeting. I waited for him to finish.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Once we got the chance to actually talk face to face, he relayed his seller’s frustration to me. He had already put so much work into the house, he shouldn’t have to bite the bullet and eat the whole expense. When I pointed out the counter-proposal that I’d sent to him, he hadn’t even seen it yet. He asked whether my buyer had agreed to this proposal. He promised to contact the seller and get back to me right away. The seller wasn’t excited, but it was a good middle-ground compromise. They took our proposal.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Now my buyer and his fiance are having their first Christmas together in their new home. All because I went a little old-school and met face to face to explain our proposal.  That’s what I mean by going the extra mile for my clients.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you’re looking for an agent who is willing to be a part of the solution, I’m your gal. If you’re interested in buying or selling or just want to hear how today’s market affects you, please don’t hesitate to call me or send me an email. We’re happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-do-we-go-the-extra-miles-for-our-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-do-we-go-the-extra-miles-for-our-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Donate to Your Local Food Bank This Fall</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0iOUGWOcjEs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall can be a really exciting time. The leaves start turning, the air gets crisp, and the holidays are just around the corner. When everything is groovy around you — the roof over your head is solid and your cupboards are full — it’s easy to think of the fall as a harvest time, a time of ample supply. Unfortunately, that is not the case for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Marysville community, we have a large population of people who are either hungry or on the verge of hunger. This is true in every community, including Everett, Stanwood, and Lake Stevens. Jesus said that the poor will always be with you, but we don’t want them to be the same people all the time. It’s really important to make sure that we do what we can as the hands and the feet of Jesus, caring for our neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus also said that when you give out a cup of water in His name, you are giving it to Him. We need to help our communities in tangible ways. &lt;strong&gt;October is the food drive month for Realtors&lt;/strong&gt;, and that’s why I’m sending you this. If you can, please drop off food or cash donations to our office and we will deliver them to the Marysville Food Bank. I can even swing by and pick up your donations from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not from Marysville but would like to support the food bank, let me know. I can put you in touch with someone either in Marysville or in your own community. Remember, it’s important to give where you live.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Let's be good neighbors to each other.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/donate-to-your-local-food-bank-this-fall.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Let’s be good neighbors to each other.”&lt;/a&gt;
One reason the food bank is so near to my heart is that when I was a child, we often got those baskets of food. We got the commodity cheese, powdered scrambled eggs, and powdered milk from the government. I didn’t even like real milk when I first tried it because I wasn’t used to it. It’s very important to me that when I am experiencing abundance that I give back as well. &lt;strong&gt;Please help us be a resource for others.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are on the other side of this — if you are struggling right now, please let me know. I can put you in touch with someone who can help you. The Everett Gospel Mission not only helps people with housing, they will also give you a bag of food. They even have a little store that you can walk through complete with household items, clothes, and food that you can have for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this fall, let’s be good neighbors to each other. If you are my neighbor and you need help, please open up. I am here to help you. At Keller Williams, we are a team. TEAM stands for Together Everyone Achieves More. Let’s work together to put food on the table for our neighbors and make our community a great place to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, if you have any donations for our food bank, just drop them off at our office at 1027 State Ave #102 in Marysville. If you can’t make the trip, let me know and I will collect the donations for you. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 12:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/donate-to-your-local-food-bank-this-fall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/donate-to-your-local-food-bank-this-fall.html</guid>
        
        <category>More From Sandy &amp; Company</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Our Buyer Shrunk Her Home and Evaporated Her Mortgage Payment</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OJ9524rMVF8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to tell you a story about a Baby Boomer buyer we just helped downsize and why she’s so excited about her brand new home in her retirement years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a call from a lender with a client who was very stressed out–she had a nearly 4,000 sq. ft. house with three living spaces and a huge garage. It was an older brick home that needed some paint and just some all-around love. The payment was also huge, nearly $4,000. It was just too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She has been working hard all her life and is coming up on retirement. She was also having a hard time making ends meet because of this monstrous payment and all the maintenance required.&lt;/strong&gt; So my lender spoke with her about her whole financial situation and found that she was in a position to buy a reverse mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, a reverse mortgage is not for everyone and there are some important criteria to consider, so I’ll refer you to my lender for that conversation if it’s one you want to have.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Where are you in the cycle of your home life?%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-our-buyer-shrunk-her-home-and.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Where are you in the cycle of your home life?”&lt;/a&gt;
With the reverse mortgage, &lt;strong&gt;our buyer was able to put down a significant chunk for a down payment, and now she’s not going to have a payment for the rest of time she lives in her home.&lt;/strong&gt; All she has to do is maintain her insurance, taxes, and the home itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at houses, she needed something with separate spaces for both herself and her adult son who lived with her. We were able to find her a split-level home where he has the lower level and she has the upstairs, and the home is much newer than her previous home. It’s perfect for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this was the very first house we looked at. We looked at a couple others, but the first house ended up being her perfect home. It really does happen once in a while. We’re getting her previous home ready for the market, and we know it will be perfect for someone needing more space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking into your retirement years and you’re thinking about your house and your mortgage, I’d love to talk with you about it. The question is this–where are you in the cycle of your home life? Give me a call or send me an email and we’ll talk soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 12:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-our-buyer-shrunk-her-home-and.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-our-buyer-shrunk-her-home-and.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Win as a Buyer in Today’s Market </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PGEO9erJmRk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a tough market out there for buyers right now and it’s important that you work with the right agent. Our team works hard to help buyers win in this market, and you should make sure you work with an agent who knows how to compete with other offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I was doing an open house for one of my sellers. It was a hot listing that went on the market Wednesday and by Saturday, we already had a full-price offer in place. However, we still held open houses that weekend because we had already said we would wait to review offers that Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the buyers who walked in had seen our advertising and really wanted to check out the home. However, they were also bummed because they had just lost out on a house. I said, “I know, it’s a pretty tough market out there. We’re doing a lot of escalation clauses.” I mentioned a few other things we do to help our buyers get ahead in the current market, and they just said, “What’s that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their reaction really gave me pause because we talk about how &lt;strong&gt;we can help our buyers win so frequently that it just becomes an automatic part of our process.&lt;/strong&gt; There are tools you can use to make your offer better than someone else’s and there are ways to put your best offer forward. You don’t have to max out your budget right away; you can start out softer so that you are able to get stronger down the line, and we can help you get that house.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We have tools and strategies to help buyers win in this tough market.%20http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-to-win-as-buyer-in-todays-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We have tools and strategies to help buyers win in this tough market.”&lt;/a&gt;
I took the time to educate this buyer, which still benefits my seller. “Let’s say we have a full-price offer. Here is how you might craft your offer to get the home.” They hadn’t heard any of these strategies before. But they still thought it didn’t matter because the main problem was the seller probably wouldn’t pay the closing costs. My answer? “That’s no problem at all!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most sellers are willing to pay closing costs, especially if they get the price they want for the house. I gave them a few different points to make their offer better. They went back to their own agent and wrote their own offer. The agent called me the next day with some questions. The buyer wound up getting the house for $15,000 less than their max and my seller was able to get $5,000 more than they expected, even after paying the buyers’ closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can make this happen for you.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t assume that just because your agent is part of a big team means they will know, understand and use all of the strategies necessary to win in this tough market. Talk to your agent about what happens when you’re in a bidding war. If you’re not sure what questions to ask them, give me a call and I can help you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 15:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-to-win-as-buyer-in-todays-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-to-win-as-buyer-in-todays-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
