<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Marysville Real Estate Podcast Sandy Eagon</title>
    <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Sandy &amp; Company Real Estate - your professional Marysville Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Sandy Eagon</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-04-12 09:01:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Sandy Eagon</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/img/Eagon_Podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Sandy@SandyAndCompany.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Sandy Eagon</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/img/Eagon_Podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Marysville Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Sandy &amp; Company Real Estate - your professional Marysville Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Love Your Home Base</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/love-your-home-base.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/2018/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+I+Enjoy+the+Comforts+of+Home+During+Winter+Months.mp4</guid>
        <description>

During the wet windy winter months, I like to hunker down in my home base and enjoy some of my favorite activities. 

Whether it’s reading a good book, like John Eldredge’s “Moving Mountains,” journaling, or knitting, I have been really enjoying making the most of my downtime. And of course for my yarn I go to Great Yarns in Everett. 

Another thing I’m rarely without when I am home is a cup of tea. You’ve got to check out Everything Tea down on First Street. While you’re there you’ll find old favorites and new flavors.

“There is so much to do in the Pacific Northwest, even during these cool, wet days.”

If you’re feeling adventurous enough to brave the winter weather, all it takes is a good stocking cap and rain gear to stay warm. We were just golfing over atBattle Creek Golf Course in the chill. There is so much to do in the Pacific Northwest, even during these cool, wet days. 

And if your house doesn’t feel like home base, call me!Maybe it’s time for a new house that feels like a good place to call home.

As always, feel free to give me a call or send me an email if you have any questions about real estate or anything I’ve mentioned here today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/2018/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+I+Enjoy+the+Comforts+of+Home+During+Winter+Months.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/2018/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+I+Enjoy+the+Comforts+of+Home+During+Winter+Months.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>During the cold and wet winter months we have here in the Pacific Northwest, it’s always good to enjoy the comforts of home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>During the cold and wet winter months we have here in the Pacific Northwest, it’s always good to enjoy the comforts of home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don't Get Your Real Estate Information From the News</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/dont-get-your-real-estate-information-from-the-news.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-02 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Beyond+the+newsyour+real+values.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Where are you getting your “real estate IQ?” If most of your information has been coming from the news, you may want to start looking elsewhere.

The news isn’t off-the-mark with reports of low inventory. However, one thing you may not have seen reported in the media is information about current values.

Of course, this is because values will vary greatly depending on your location. The local area with the biggest rise in value last year was Bothell, where values moved from an average of $650,000 to an average of $730,000 at the end of the year.

Everett was a much different story. There, the average sales price of $472,000 dropped by $20,000 at the end of the year. Marysville saw similar changes, beginning at $393,000 at the start of autumn and dropping to $374,000 by the end of 2017.

Ultimately, the point is that you need to be educated. It’s important that you understand what is happening in your area so that you can stay in front of the market. We can’t decide what to do in the future by looking at the past, so let’s make sure that your education is local. We can help you with that.

“It is critical that you’re getting your information about the market from a full-time, professional Realtor.”

My team and I just handed over keys to two families who were both affected by low appraisals in the last couple of months. One of them had the entire transaction fall apart because the seller would not allow us to educate them about the current market. At the end of the day, though, we were able to find this family another, better deal.

As for the other family we just worked with, the deal went smoothly because the seller allowed us to educate them. We showed them statistics and the seller worked with us to create a win-win situation.

Overall, the most important thing is that you’re getting your information about the market from a full-time, professional Realtor.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Beyond+the+newsyour+real+values.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Beyond+the+newsyour+real+values.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Where are you getting your “real estate IQ?” If most of your information has been coming from the news, you may want to start looking elsewhere.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Where are you getting your “real estate IQ?” If most of your information has been coming from the news, you may want to start looking elsewhere.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does Your Home Work for You in 2018?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/does-your-home-work-for-you-in-2018.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-08 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+your+home+ready+for+2018%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Does your house work for you in 2018?

Did you get a new puppy for Christmas and now you need to put up a fence? I have a post hole digger I’d be glad to share with you.

Check out SandyAndCompanyVideos.com/Toolshed and browse all the tools we’d let you use.

Sometimes you need a tool, but you don’t need to buy it, so let us be there for you if that’s your situation.

“We’re  the resource to help you find the right person for the job.”

Is the project bigger than just having the right tool? Let me help you find that right plumber, contractor, etc. We’re the resource to help you find the right person for that job as well.

Speaking for myself, we’re finally adding our mud sink to the garage this year, so I’ll be calling the plumber to get that started this week.

Finally, have you had kids move out (or back in) this year and the size of your house needs to change? Give me a call so we can talk about what your home needs to be in order to work for you and your family.

As always, if you have any other questions or real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would love to help you. Until then, happy 2018 and have a super day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+your+home+ready+for+2018%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+your+home+ready+for+2018%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Does your house work for you in 2018?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Does your house work for you in 2018?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What We’re Grateful for This Christmas</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-were-grateful-for-this-christmas.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-19 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+This+Christmas%252C+we+are+grateful+for+you.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The Christmas season is a time for gratitude.

Today, my office manager Kerri is with me because we were just talking about what we’re grateful for.

One of the main things we’re grateful for is the trust you put in us during your real estate transactions. In these transactions there is so much at stake, so thank you for trusting us with those transactions and with your life. We are so grateful that we get to serve you and be a part of your life. Thank you for your trust.

“We are so grateful that we get to be a part of your transaction and of your life.”

Kerri is also grateful for the ability to help all of you. “I truly love my job, and I am grateful for the flexibility that comes with that,” says Kerri. “At times I’m even able to do my job from home and spend a bit more time with my family while still serving you and being there when you need us.”

So, we’d like to send you a great big thank you this Christmas. We are excited to see what’s coming up in 2018. Have a wonderful Christmas and a great, safe New Year.

If you have any questions, just give us a call. We look forward to seeing you in 2018!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+This+Christmas%252C+we+are+grateful+for+you.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+This+Christmas%252C+we+are+grateful+for+you.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The Christmas season is a time for gratitude.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The Christmas season is a time for gratitude.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Puget Sound Market Is Only Going to Get More Competitive</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/the-puget-sound-market-is-only-going-to-get-more-competitive.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-27 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Get+ready+for+the+spring+market+now.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you are thinking of buying a home this spring, then we have to talk right now to make this work for you.

One of the things that I constantly keep an eye on is our inventory. What’s happening with prices and the number of homes available for sale?

In October of 2015, we had 2.2 months of supply. In October of 2016, we had 1.7 months of inventory. This past October, we only had 1.1 months of supply.

When I say there is only one month of inventory, that means that if no new homes came on the market, everything would be gone in just one month. That is the lowest amount of inventory that we have had in recorded history.

There is a dip in the springtime, so what does that leave us with?

Last spring, we were helping nine buyers. We found homes for seven of them, but we could not find homes for two of them. Last spring gave us a couple of black eyes. One buyer decided to buy in the south end of Puget Sound, while another decided to rent instead.

It was really hard. We had to ask buyers if they wanted to pay for an inspection before they even made an offer because we had to find ways to be competitive.

“Puget Sound only has 1.1 months of inventory, the least we’ve ever seen.”

If last spring gave us two black eyes, this spring will probably give us that along with a bloody nose. If you want to be in a home this spring, we need to talk right now about how to make this market work for you instead of against you.

The only ways buyers are going to have a chance is by losing contingencies and raising offer prices. I would rather have you in a home by January or February and have that 10% price increase work in your favor instead of making you work even harder.

One of my seller clients said, “So if prices are going to be 10% higher this spring, shouldn’t I wait until spring to sell?” Maybe. However, if you are looking to buy a home at the same time, you will still have to go out and buy in the spring market.

No matter what market you are going to buy and sell in, you are going to buy and sell in that market. I recommend that you make that happen this winter. That way, you will have peace of mind in March, April, and May while everyone else is scrambling to find a home, because you already found the home that works for you.

On the other hand, what if you don’t need to buy another home after you sell your current one?

In this market, even selling a home puts you in a high-pressure cooker atmosphere. When buyers are under pressure, they are not always so nice to deal with. That’s why we work to protect our sellers and get them top dollar in that pressure cooker environment.

Let’s talk about your home needs and what we can do for you today to get you ready for the next six months. Just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Get+ready+for+the+spring+market+now.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Get+ready+for+the+spring+market+now.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you are thinking of buying a home this spring, then we have to talk right now to make this work for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you are thinking of buying a home this spring, then we have to talk right now to make this work for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Know the Secret to Shaving Years off Your Mortgage?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/do-you-know-the-secret-to-shaving-years-off-your-mortgage.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-13 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+you+can+pay+off+your+home+14+years+sooner.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’ve got one easy way you can pay your mortgage off sooner and ultimately for less money.

If you’re an American today, you’ve likely got a housing payment. This is true whether you rent or you own a home.

The tip I have today can help regardless of where you’re trying to go, whether that is a paid-off mortgage or car, or getting to homeownership in general. Before I tell you what this tip is, understand that it’s a lot easier than it sounds.

I recommend paying slightly more than you currently are. If this doesn’t sound like saving money, let me explain.

At the beginning of this year, I decided I wanted to be at a certain point in my mortgage at the end of the year.

“I’m shaving 14 years off my mortgage by using this tip.”

So I found what I was paying in principal only each month, and where that would naturally put my mortgage balance by the end of the year.

Then I subtracted my goal number from the number it would be without any different payment. I divided that difference by 12 (for each month). That number plus my regular payment was doable for me. If you are looking for wealth, use this tip.

How much of a difference did this actually make? Well, using a loan term calculator that you can find here, I did some math. It turns out that I’m shaving 14 years off my mortgage. Additionally, I’ll save about $90,000  in interest that I won’t have to pay.

Many of us are guilty of simply seeing a number on our statement and just paying that particular amount. But this doesn’t have to be your strategy. Imagine all that you could be saving by using this simple tip. You can implement this incrementally, as well.

Even if you pay just $50 extra per month on your mortgage, you would still be shaving time and money off your mortgage payments.

These tips can help even if you aren’t currently paying a mortgage. Let’s say you’re making car payments right now. Use the calculator to see how a little higher payment each month can make a big difference to your bottom line. This can apply to any payment plan you’re on.

Now remember, if you need to take care of other areas of your finances before you can implement this strategy, visit www.DaveRamsey.com.

Be a great steward of your resources. What you have is what you’ve been given to take care of.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email.

And of course, if you are looking to sell or to buy a home in the next few months, we can help you with that.

I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+you+can+pay+off+your+home+14+years+sooner.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+you+can+pay+off+your+home+14+years+sooner.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’ve got one easy way you can pay your mortgage off sooner and ultimately for less money.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’ve got one easy way you can pay your mortgage off sooner and ultimately for less money.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How You Can Be a Hero Around the Holiday Dinner Table</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-you-can-be-a-hero-around-the-holiday-dinner-table.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-30 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Be+the+hero+this+holiday+season.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a couple of great ways that you can be a hero around the Thanksgiving or Christmas dinner table.

When I talk with my clients and friends about how we can help their family and friends with their home purchase or sale, I often hear something like, “My sister would be a great person you could help.” Other times, I hear something like, “Well, my cousin Bob needs help, but you don’t want to work with him.”

We may be able to help your cousin Bob and make you a hero by being his real estate resource.

Some of our family and friends can be hard to please. Let me decide who I can best work with.

Since I work with them in a professional setting, I can be professional and let them know, “This is what I can do for you.” That helps them see what can happen and how we can get them there.

“Nine times out of 10, I help these referrals and end up liking them in the process.”

It doesn’t always mean that it’s going to be peaches and cream or that I’m going to be sitting around eating pizza with them on a Seahawks game day. However, I can keep this transaction professional and still make them feel good since we were able to get their house sold.

The first way you can be a hero is to tell your friend or relative, “You should talk to Sandy. She has helped a lot of people over the last 14 years and she has  great ideas to help you.”

The second is to tell them, “I’m going to have Sandy call you. Sandy has helped so many people in our area over the last 14 years. She is an expert and a resource. She’s patient and she will help you get through this process and get your next home.”

Whether they need help buying or selling a home, introduce them to me. Let me decide whether they’re too hard to work with. Usually I can set good professional boundaries. But if I can’t help them, I’ll tell them up-front. I don’t want them to spend a ton of energy and heartache on something that we both know isn’t going to work out.

That said, nine times out of 10 I do help them. And most of the time, I end up liking them in the process.

So if you have a cranky cousin or needy friend and you’re not sure I’ll love them, just give me a call. Those people need help too, and I would be honored with the introduction.

As always, if you have any other questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Be+the+hero+this+holiday+season.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Be+the+hero+this+holiday+season.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are a couple of great ways that you can be a hero around the Thanksgiving or Christmas dinner table.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are a couple of great ways that you can be a hero around the Thanksgiving or Christmas dinner table.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Common Misunderstandings Smart Sellers Still Have</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/3-common-misunderstandings-smart-sellers-still-have.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-09 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+common+seller+misunderstandings.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Buying and selling real estate is a hot topic, both in the media and in casual conversation. A lot of people have experience buying and selling real estate, but sometimes that experience happened as far back as 20 years ago or in a different state than Washington. In real estate, things happen differently in different times and different areas.

With that in mind, there are three main misunderstandings some of my smart sellers have had lately:

1. Who pays for what? Sometimes sellers assume that in this hot seller’s market they can get the buyer to pay their closing costs, right? Wrong. The seller always pays their own fees. There’s a title fee, an escrow fee, excise tax, and commissions. And the seller pays commissions for both the buyer’s and seller’s agent. Remember, current prices reflect a market where the seller customarily pays those fees, so you’re actually getting the money for it, just not until the very end.

2. What is personal property?I had a seller recently insist that the buyer pay him separately for his propane tank separately from the purchase price of the house. It took a while for him to understand that in this part of the country, the propane tank stays with the house because it’s connected to it and that’s how it gets its fuel. A lawnmower, on the other hand, is something you could sell to your buyer separately from the house’s purchase price.

“Talk to a Realtor you can trust to lead you down the right path of making smart decisions.”

3. What stays and what goes? My rule of thumb is if it’s wired in, it stays. If it’s screwed in, it usually stays. One of the most common misunderstandings is curtains and blinds, which always stay with the house. Obviously, these items are of a personal taste, so if they’re something you want to take with you, by all means, take them down ahead of time. Don’t let someone else fall in love with your curtains—that’s disrupted more than one sale at the end.

Some of these things are common sense, and some can be a different way of viewing a real estate transaction. It doesn’t mean you’re stupid; it just means you’ve looked at something differently than the way it’s done here and now.

This is why it’s so important to talk to a Realtor you can trust to lead you down the right path of making smart decisions and you don’t end up shooting yourself in the foot.

If you have any questions about this how it’s really done or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in our Puget Sound market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to help you.

.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+common+seller+misunderstandings.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+common+seller+misunderstandings.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buying and selling real estate is a hot topic, both in the media and in casual conversation. A lot of people have a lot of experience buying and selling real estate, but the problem with that is sometimes that experience happened as far back as 10 to 20 years ago in different places than where they’re located now. In real estate, things happen differently in different times and different areas.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buying and selling real estate is a hot topic, both in the media and in casual conversation. A lot of people have a lot of experience buying and selling real estate, but the problem with that is sometimes that experience happened as far back as 10 to 20 years ago in different places than where they’re located now. In real estate, things happen differently in different times and different areas.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few Ways to Add (and Subtract) Value From Your Home</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/a-few-ways-to-add-and-subtract-value-from-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-21 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Six+home+improvement+dos+and+donts.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about selling your home in the near future, making some upgrades isn’t a bad idea. However, you need to know the difference between which renovations you should do and which you should avoid.

We’ve got six different upgrade tips for you today. Two of them are things you should absolutely do if they apply to you. Two of them are things that you want to do if you can afford them. There are also two upgrades that you shouldn’t even consider.
The Must Do&rsquo;s

1. Your siding. If you have older siding that is buckling or expanding, it’s time to take a look at some new siding. Buyers will look at how well you took care of the structure of your home and if you’re letting water in through your siding, it doesn’t matter what your kitchen looks like.

2. Replace aluminum windows.Use vinyl, double-pane windows instead, so the buyer of your home has the lowest possible energy bills.
The Want-to-Do&rsquo;s

1. The kitchen. Making upgrades here can get you an 85% return on your investment. However, you want to keep the budget of this project within 20% of your home’s value so you don’t overbuild for your neighborhood.

“Replace aluminum windows with vinyl.”

2. The bathroom. Another area that can get you great bang for your buck is the bathroom. You can get up to an 80% return.
The Don&rsquo;t Do&rsquo;s

1. Combining small rooms into larger rooms. Any time you reduce the bedroom count in your home, its value is going to take a big hit, especially if you’re making a 3-bedroom a 2-bedroom. That’s going to drive away most of the families out there.

2. Remodel the garage space. Buyers are going to be looking at your garage space in terms of if it’s going to keep their vehicles dry and warm. If you decide to make part of your garage space a living space, make sure you can easily turn it back into a garage when the time comes to sell.

With any improvement or upgrade you make, it’s first about getting joy out of it while you’re living in the home and then secondly passing that joy onto the next owner.

If you have any questions about any of these upgrades or any other decisions related to selling your home, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Six+home+improvement+dos+and+donts.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Six+home+improvement+dos+and+donts.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re thinking about selling your home in the near future, making some upgrades isn’t a bad idea. However, you need to know the difference between which renovations you should do and which you should avoid.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re thinking about selling your home in the near future, making some upgrades isn’t a bad idea. However, you need to know the difference between which renovations you should do and which you should avoid.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building Your Faith in Your Everyday Life</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/building-your-faith-in-your-everyday-life.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-16 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Building+your+faith+in+your+everyday+life.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You may know that buying and selling real estate is one of the top five most stressful things that someone can go through in their life, right along with death, divorce, and losing a job.

One of my couples was buying a new home, and in the beginning it was a truly exciting time for them. But then they ran into an issue with the lender, who was creating problems where there weren’t any.

At one point, the husband told me something that I could totally relate to: “I know I’m supposed to give this to God, but I just keep going back and picking it back up again.” I’m sure you can relate to that.

Then I began to look at their situation a little differently. God said repeatedly in the Bible, “Remember when…”  Over and over, he provided for his chosen people what they needed, at the exact moment that they needed it. And then God told them to remember those times of his provision when they had another crisis. These memories built their faith and confidence. So I told my client, “I think the Lord is creating a ‘remember when’ moment for you.”

We can’t remember when he did great things for us if we didn’t have those moments to go through in the first place. Later on, he’ll remember that the Lord’s provision came through for him before. And it will again. Because God’s goodness never changes- he is the same yesterday, today and tomorrow.

“The  Bible helps us understand what’s happening in our lives at the current moment.”

I reminded my client that even though the situation seemed hopeless to him, if he stopped worrying about what-if’s and focused instead on building that airplane (he’s a Boeing guy), and let God take care of this, he was going to turn out okay. Ultimately, the lender referred us to someone else who could finish his loan. Eight days after we began working with this new lender, I was handing my clients the keys to their new home.

God promises to provide for us. He says in Deuteronomy 31:6, “Be strong and courageous. Do not be afraid or terrified because of them, for the Lord your God goes with you; he will never leave you nor forsake you.” That’s echoed in Hebrew 13:5. Philippians 4:19 says “And my God will supply all your needs according to the riches of his glory in Christ Jesus.” All means ALL.

The Bible helps us understand what’s happening in our lives at the current moment. In the same way, our real-life issues aren’t just earthly conversations—that’s why we must invite God into them on a daily basis.

It was such a joy to be able to work with my client through this situation and share this faith experience with him. If there is anything that I can do to help you and your family, whether it be real estate or otherwise, please give me a call. I would be honored to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Building+your+faith+in+your+everyday+life.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Building+your+faith+in+your+everyday+life.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You may know that buying and selling real estate is one of the top five most stressful things that someone can go through in their life, right along with death, divorce, and losing a job.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You may know that buying and selling real estate is one of the top five most stressful things that someone can go through in their life, right along with death, divorce, and losing a job.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Kind of Agents Do Lenders Recommend?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-kind-of-agents-do-lenders-recommend.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-08 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whom+do+lenders+trust%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Have you ever been curious about who our lenders use for their Realtors?

The truth is that everyone from our lenders, our title representatives, and our inspectors see a lot of agents each day.

Since they work so closely with so many agents, they’ve come to understand the difference between an agent who serves their clients and one who may not do so much.

Recently, one of my lenders sent me to his colleague who was looking to buy a duplex with her husband. The plan was for them to live in one side with close family in the other.

“My buyers won this home because this lender knew me and my skills.”

This sounded like an awesome plan, and it didn’t take long for us to find the right duplex for them.

Even though it was listed for more than they could afford, we struck a deal with the seller that worked within our budget. We won this battle because the listing agent knew he could trust me to represent my clients as they really are.

My buyers won this home because this lender knew me and my skills.

When looking for an agent who can make a strong transaction, go to the agent other professionals are recommending.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whom+do+lenders+trust%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whom+do+lenders+trust%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you ever been curious about who our lenders use for their Realtors?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you ever been curious about who our lenders use for their Realtors?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Surprising but Welcome  Summer Vacation</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/a-surprising-but-welcome-summer-vacation.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-24 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Surprising+but+Welcome+Summer+Vacation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

My family was supposed to head up to Victoria, B.C. over the last days of June for some much-needed relaxation time. However, not everyone could make it so we decided to scratch the plans for now and stay in the beautiful NW instead. It was fine because I was still able to spend time with my awesome peeps.

I also accomplished quite a bit during my time off. I cleaned my garage and fixed a shelf that had fallen off. We planted a new cherry tree from Flower World and other assorted color spots from Sunnyside Nursery. Our yard is looking good!

“I accomplished quite a bit.”

I had dinner one night with my dear friend in Bellingham, and Don and I golfed up at Semiahmoo- it’s gorgeous up there! With relaxing time around home, in nurseries, and at the golf course, I was rejuvenated when it was time to go back to work. I was able to spend my time off at the places I love with the people I love: exactly what I needed.

I would love to how you’re getting fun and relaxation this summer. Let me know! Or if you have any questions about real estate, give me a call, Facebook message me or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Surprising+but+Welcome+Summer+Vacation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Surprising+but+Welcome+Summer+Vacation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My family was supposed to head up to Victoria, B.C. over the last days of June for some much-needed relaxation time. However, not everyone could make it so we decided to scratch the plans for now and stay in the beautiful NW instead.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My family was supposed to head up to Victoria, B.C. over the last days of June for some much-needed relaxation time. However, not everyone could make it so we decided to scratch the plans for now and stay in the beautiful NW instead.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Summer's the Best Time to Tackle These 5 Home Upkeeps & Upgrades</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/summers-the-best-time-to-tackle-these-5-home-upkeeps-upgrades.html</link>
        
          <category>More Sandy & Company Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-10 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Upkeeps-Updates+for+your+Puget+Sound+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Summer can be a great time for some to-do list items around the house that are a little more weather-dependent. There are five things in particular that you should consider doing to your Puget Sound home this summer while the weather’s fine:

1. Paint: Houses get thirsty! They need to be caulked and painted, which are the first barriers for water damage in your house.

2. Taking care of your windows: Popped seals are a common issue here, so now is the time to look into new vinyl windows. The perfect window is one that doesn’t draw attention to the window itself, just what’s on the other side.

3. Fences: Look now while it’s sunny and (hopefully) not raining. Keep your fences strong to keep the pets in and add beauty to your property. There are plenty of options that will fit almost any budget whether that’s chain link, cedar, or something in between.

“Where do you gather with your family and friends?”

4. The driveway:This could mean just cleaning if there are no big cracks that trip people or chunks of grass growing through. I’ll even lend you my power washer if you need it! Is it time to pour new concrete? Options from aggregate to stamping designs can change your driveway to beautiful and inviting.

5. Yard space: Where do you gather with your family and friends? Updating your yard can be as easy as putting in a fire pit, or you could go the outdoor kitchen route with a grill, oven, and a cover for year-round entertaining. Covered decks and patios are important in our part of the country where clear skies are a little less dependable. You could also add in some game spots like horseshoes or a volleyball net. Make your yard a place that you can enjoy as an extension of your home.

If you have any questions or you’re looking for recommendations for the best tasks to tackle in your home this summer, or you’re looking to make a move this season, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Upkeeps-Updates+for+your+Puget+Sound+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Upkeeps-Updates+for+your+Puget+Sound+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Summer can be a great time for some to-do list items around the house that are a little more weather-dependent. There are five things in particular that you should consider doing to your Puget Sound home this summer while the weather's fine:</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Summer can be a great time for some to-do list items around the house that are a little more weather-dependent. There are five things in particular that you should consider doing to your Puget Sound home this summer while the weather's fine:</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Congratulations to Chloe and the Class of 2017</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/congratulations-to-chloe-and-the-class-of-2017.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-21 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Congratulations+to+Chloe+%2526+the+Class+of+2017.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I want to take a step away from the real estate market for a moment to talk about my darling Chloe. She graduated from community college last week. We’re celebrating that big life step in our family.

When Chloe graduated from high school two years ago, she announced, “I think I want to open a bakery. If that doesn’t work, maybe I’ll go work for NASA.”

I asked, “Why don’t you go work for NASA and bake on the weekends?”

“Nah,” she replied, “I don’t want to do all of that really big math.”

Chloe is good at really big math problems, but having to do that all the time was just not her cup of tea. And she really loved to bake. So, she went to community college to study business administration and prepare to open the bakery. When she took her first accounting class, she realized how much accounting made sense for her.

I am so proud of Chloe. She just finished up at Everett Community College and she will move to the University of Washington Bothell campus in the fall.

“I am so excited for Chloe and her bright future.”

These transitions give us opportunity. How great is it that we get to celebrate these awesome times in our family when we get to see growth? It’s so amazing that we get to see the people our children are becoming.

I am so excited for Chloe and her future. She’s made some awesome steps. She has been working for Chick-fil-A for the last year and before that she worked at Alfie’s. She’s been so strong and responsible, and I am excited because her future is bright.

I hope that you take the time to talk to your own graduates and tell them how proud you are. After all, they’ve done something really big, whether they are graduating from high school, college or some other training program. They are taking a step forward, making themselves better, and working to be the best person they can be.

This is the time of year to celebrate your family and friends’ accomplishments. So, I would like to take a minute to say:

Chloe, I am so proud of you. You are awesome. I couldn’t be more happy with the young lady you are today.

I hope you have an awesome day and remember, celebrate! Of course if you have any real estate questions, please be sure to reach out. I am happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Congratulations+to+Chloe+%2526+the+Class+of+2017.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Congratulations+to+Chloe+%2526+the+Class+of+2017.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I want to take a step away from the real estate market for a moment to talk about my darling Chloe. She graduated from community college last week. We're celebrating that big life step in our family.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I want to take a step away from the real estate market for a moment to talk about my darling Chloe. She graduated from community college last week. We're celebrating that big life step in our family.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Become a Hog in This Market</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/dont-become-a-hog-in-this-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-07 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Pig+Market+or+Hog+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I met an awesome couple about a month ago who were looking to sell their condo and buy a home with more space. When we got ready to price their condo, we looked at what the most recent sales numbers were. We listed for the same as the last identical sale, knowing that the market would bring the price up all on its own.

In a market like this, you want to be a little bit under where buyers will come in so they feel like they have a bit of control and they can then push you up to where you want to go and you can get the benefit of that competition.

We priced the condo at $210,000 and lo and behold, we got six offers in three days. The highest offer was all the way up at $250,000!. The big question now whether the condo was going to appraise because it sold for so much higher than any comparable condos.

“To our surprise, the appraisal came in at $250,000.”

We knew we didn’t have time to mess around if the appraisal came in low, so the sellers agreed that they would accept the price at whatever the appraisal came in at and move forward. To our surprise (and our excitement), the appraisal came in at $250,000! My clients got everything they needed and more. They are absolutely ecstatic and so are we.

What does this have to do with pigs and hogs? Well, my lender has a phrase that goes like this: “Pigs get fat but hogs get slaughtered.” It’s one thing to get nice, fat, and sassy about where you could possibly sell your home at; it’s another to become a hog and demand that a buyer pay the price even if the appraisal comes in under that number and their lender won’t lend on the full amount. Just something to keep in mind if you or someone you know is in a similar situation.

If you or someone you know needs the right person who can help them buy or sell in Puget Sound and make the right decisions along the way, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Pig+Market+or+Hog+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Pig+Market+or+Hog+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I met an awesome couple about a month ago who were looking to sell their condo and buy a home with more space. When we got ready to price their condo, we looked at what the most recent sales numbers were. We listed for the same as the last identical sale, knowing that the market would bring the price up all on its own.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I met an awesome couple about a month ago who were looking to sell their condo and buy a home with more space. When we got ready to price their condo, we looked at what the most recent sales numbers were. We listed for the same as the last identical sale, knowing that the market would bring the price up all on its own.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making a Plan to Get the Home You Want</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/making-a-plan-to-get-the-home-you-want.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-24 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Making+a+home+purchasing+plan.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Last night, I had some first-time homebuyers ask me if they were ready to purchase and what I thought of their situation. In response, I had a couple questions for them. These questions are the same ones you need to ask yourself if you’re in a similar situation so you can make a plan to get the home you want.

First, do you have an emergency fund?By this I mean a sum of at least $1,000 set aside for when certain things go wrong—maybe the car needs new brakes or the hot water heater needs to be replaced. These are things that you know will happen at some point in the future, but you just don’t know when. It’s not an unexpected expense; it’s an unscheduled expense.

“Let  me help you figure out a plan to get the home you want.”

Second, what’s happening with your debt? Is it going up or down? If this sounds familiar, you might be listening to Dave Ramsey. If not, Dave Ramsey is a financial advisor who has sound financial sense, hates debt, and wants to make sure you’re constantly moving toward being on secure ground financially so you can do what you need to do for you and your family. I highly recommend you check out his site at DaveRamsey.com for more information.

Lastly, have you made a plan to figure out how to chunk that debt away? If you don’t have a plan, that’s fine. Let’s talk about making one. If you do have a plan, let’s talk about how close you are and how you might accelerate yourself to be ready. It’s not just about the house payment; it’s about what’s going out and what’s coming in.

I want you ready for homeownership so you can look back and say “You know what? This was awesome!” instead of “Oh my word, I’m hanging on by the skin of my teeth!”

If you’re interested in making your plan, give me a call so we can help you get ready to get that house. I look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Making+a+home+purchasing+plan.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Making+a+home+purchasing+plan.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Last night, I had some first-time homebuyers ask me if they were ready to purchase and what I thought of their situation. In response, I had a couple questions for them. These questions are the same ones you need to ask yourself if you’re in a similar situation so you can make a plan to get the home you want.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Last night, I had some first-time homebuyers ask me if they were ready to purchase and what I thought of their situation. In response, I had a couple questions for them. These questions are the same ones you need to ask yourself if you’re in a similar situation so you can make a plan to get the home you want.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Helping Seniors Plan the Downsize</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/helping-seniors-plan-the-downsize.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-10 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Helping+seniors+plan+the+downsize.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Last month one of my neighbors told me that she was in a dire financial situation, as she was in pre-foreclosure. As it turns out, one of her family members who shares a joint account with her and assists her making her mortgage payments actually stole money from that account and lied about it.

Now this neighbor is a number of months late on her mortgage payment. She’s been consulting with an agent on how to rectify this situation and it sounds like her bank may help her. But I’m not sure she’s getting the results she’s looking for. Needless to say, I have many concerns for this dear lady. She has a significant amount of equity, so she can sell her home and put that equity into her next place, but what’s the next place that works best for her?

“We’re here to help.”

If you’re asking yourself this same question, we have the resources and know many experts who specialize in assisting with the downsizing process. They can clear out any clutter and help to sift through the loads of paperwork that you don’t need to hang on to anymore. We also know people who can help you determine whether you’re capable of maintaining your own apartment or if you would like assisted living.

These are the additional questions you need to ask yourself, and we can help you with that at no charge. I have a senior real estate specialist designation. What that really means is that I have a heart for seniors and I’m ready to use my expertise for their benefit.

If you or someone you know is ready to downsize but you don’t know where to turn to next, please reach out to me so we can sit down and have a free, no-risk, no-obligation consultation. I’m happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Helping+seniors+plan+the+downsize.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Helping+seniors+plan+the+downsize.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a homeowner who is looking to downsize, what’s the next place that works best for you?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a homeowner who is looking to downsize, what’s the next place that works best for you?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Is the Puget Sound Market Headed?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/where-is-the-puget-sound-market-headed.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-26 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+An+update+on+the+Puget+Sound+real+estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The question of “Where is our market headed?” is one that I get a lot. I’m going to answer it today.

The direction the market is heading is a concern for both buyers and sellers. Sellers want to make sure they don’t miss out on the top price, and buyers want to make sure they don’t pay too much.

Compared to last year, our growth has slowed a little bit. But make no mistake—our market is still growing. Although we saw an incredible 13.2% growth in 2016 and that number is down to 10.4% in 2017, any appreciation rate close to 10% is outstanding.

“The question of “Where is our market headed?” is one that I get a lot. I’m going to answer it today.”

At the same time, our inventory is even lower than it was at this point last year. Last year, we had 1.2 months of inventory at this time, which is an extremely low figure. This year, that number dropped to 0.7 months, or just three weeks of inventory. Until that inventory bumps up in the summer, we’re going to have a bottleneck of buyers. The best way for them to compete is by making an offer above asking price.

I see prices continuing to move up, but we’re in line for stabilization. When will that happen? I can’t tell you, but I can tell you that if you’ve been thinking about buying or selling a home, you need to give us a call or send us an email so we can discuss how the market relates to your individual situation. I’ll give you the facts and present you with your options and potential risks.

If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+An+update+on+the+Puget+Sound+real+estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+An+update+on+the+Puget+Sound+real+estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The question of “Where is our market headed?” is one that I get a lot. I’m going to answer it today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The question of “Where is our market headed?” is one that I get a lot. I’m going to answer it today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Homeownership on Tulalip Land</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/homeownership-on-tulalip-land.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-11 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Purchasing+a+home+on+the+Tulalip+Reservation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to talk about land on the Tulalip Reservation, which can either be leased land or it can be deeded.

If it’s leased, then the lease is either through the Tulalip Tribe or through the Fryberg family.

When the land is owned by the tribe you pay them a monthly lease fee that’s based on the value of the land and reassessed every three years.

When you lease from the Fryberg family—who are part of the Tulalip Tribe and own the land—you pay an annual lease fee to them. The Fryberg leases are overseen by the Bureau of Indian Affairs. The Fryberg family leased land is reassessed every five years.

“When you buy a home on Tulalip leased land, you pay a monthly or annual lease fee.”

When you buy a property that is leased land, you’re buying the improvements on the land, as well as the rights to exclusively use the land. Much like deeded land, no one else can claim rights to use it during your lease period.

When you buy a deeded property on the Tulalip Reservation, your rights are exactly like buying anywhere else. The only difference is that you’ll pay a 1% fee to the Tulalip Tribe when you sell.

If you have any questions about tribal land or leased/deeded property, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I am more than happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Purchasing+a+home+on+the+Tulalip+Reservation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Purchasing+a+home+on+the+Tulalip+Reservation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I wanted to talk about land on the Tulalip Reservation, which can either be leased land from the Fryeburgs or it can be deeded.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I wanted to talk about land on the Tulalip Reservation, which can either be leased land from the Fryeburgs or it can be deeded.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Make Big Decisions?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-do-you-make-big-decisions.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-27 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Email+Assets/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+tips+for+making+big+life+decisions.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Life is like a box of chocolates, or maybe it’s like a bowl of cherries. Sometimes making big life decisions is like the Now and Later candy: all of the life decisions that you make have something to do with now and something to do with later. So, how do you make those big decisions?

Some people  can make a snap decision, jump right in, and everything turns out OK. Even when buying a home. Most of us take a slower pace. I want to encourage you to do three things when making those big decisions:

1. Slow down to be wise. Often we can be distracted by the shiny and beautiful surfaces. We don’t always look to see what’s underneath. That can happen in all arenas of life. Let me encourage you to take a harder look and make sure that what you see is really what you get.

2. Pray about it. Ask God, “What is it that you have for me and how does this fit in?” Don’t be afraid of his answer. He might say no because he has something better in store for you later on. But he might actually say yes! Then you can be excited that you are being wise and that you are walking along the purpose he has designed for you as your creator.

“Make sure that what you see is really what you’ll get.”

3. Talk to others. Talk to your spouse, parents, friends, or whomever you know who has a wise demeanor in this arena. Ask what they think about it. When I am looking at homes with single people, they don’t always have another person to talk things over with and bounce ideas off. In that case, I am honored to be on their “Board of Directors” and to help them weigh their options.

When considering a home, there are several things you need to keep in mind. For instance, does it make you smile when you walk in the door? Is the property structurally sound? The house might be really pretty, but if the bones weren’t taken care of, then you have a problem. You should also consider whether or not you have the resources for upkeep down the road.

So when you make those big decisions, look at Now and Later. Go through a decision-process to ensure that you make a great decision now that will still be a great decision down the road.

If you have any questions for me, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Email+Assets/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+tips+for+making+big+life+decisions.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Email+Assets/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+tips+for+making+big+life+decisions.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Life is like a box of chocolates, or maybe it’s like a bowl of cherries. I believe that making big life decisions is like the Now and Later candy; all of the life decisions that you make have something to do with now and something to do with later. So, how do you make those big decisions?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Life is like a box of chocolates, or maybe it’s like a bowl of cherries. I believe that making big life decisions is like the Now and Later candy; all of the life decisions that you make have something to do with now and something to do with later. So, how do you make those big decisions?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7 Tips for New Homeowners</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/7-tips-for-new-homeowners.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-10 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Tips+for+new+homeowners.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you buy a home, the strong temptation is  to grab the keys and move in immediately. But there are a few things to do before you bring in that first box.

First, look at your key. How many people have had access to your new home before you bought it? The previous owner may have given spare keys to friends, family members, and the neighbor’s cousin. This is a good time to change those locks. Either call a locksmith to re-key your locks or buy new hardware and switch them out.

Secondly, change out the air filter in the furnace. The previous owner had different scents, so make the home your own by breathing in that fresh air.

“Swap that furnace filter out twice a year.”

Finally, check out the toilet seats. Put seats on there that are clean and look good without any cracking paint or broken hinges.

Soon you’ll settle into daily life in the new home. That doesn’t mean you should neglect home maintenance. Everyone forgets some of the regular maintenance routine, so we have a quick list of things to share that you should keep up with regularly in your home.


  Service the furnace by swapping out the previously mentioned air filter twice per year.
  Take a look at your attic and crawlspaces for any water leaks, mold, or pest intrusion.
  Vacuum the refrigerator coils and under the stove. You use these things every day, so it’s smart to keep them clean, fresh, and working properly.
  Flip your mattress. It’s just like rotating your tires. You’ll get more life out of your mattress and probably a better night’s sleep.


If you have any questions for me at all, reach out. Call or email me, I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Tips+for+new+homeowners.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Tips+for+new+homeowners.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When you buy a home, the strong temptation is  to grab the keys and move in immediately. But there are a few things to do before you bring in that first box.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When you buy a home, the strong temptation is  to grab the keys and move in immediately. But there are a few things to do before you bring in that first box.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How We Avoid Impulse and Buyer's Remorse</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-we-avoid-impulse-and-buyers-remorse.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-21 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Being+purposeful+is+key+in+our+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Have you ever made an impulsive decision and later realized you forgot to consider a number of important things? Many buyers just like you are afraid of this when a house is listed for sale and multiple offers seem to appear within minutes. This is what we help our buyers avoid. The last thing I want is for you to have buyer’s remorse when you make such a big purchase.

“Finding the right home in this impulsive market comes down to being purposeful.”

Purposeful is a word that gets used a lot. For us, it means helping our buyers know what’s most important ahead of time. Then they know they made a wise decision when they bought a home. When we sit down with you for the first time, we talk about what’s important to you and why. We go through categories to make sure you’ve thought of everything. We talk about things like the number of bedrooms and bathrooms that you want. Then if you say you need two bathrooms, for example, does that mean you need a bathtub in that second bathroom or is a shower or just a powder room okay? These questions help us understand the reasons behind the amount of real estate you want.

When my buyers tell me about houses they see somewhere else, I take a look at why they saw it and I didn’t. Is there something I wasn’t considering? Or was there something I thought was important that’s not? One of the biggest factors is location—a buyer might want a certain community, school district, or commute, but then send me a home that’s two school districts away. That’s when we have that conversation about what’s really most important.

When we can back away from the house and talk about what’s most important to you, then we can be purposeful and help you make the right choice. This isn’t the market for buyers to jump up and grab whatever comes along. It’s a market to be careful, wise, and patient. And when the right home comes along, jump quickly and aggressively to win the home they want.

If there’s anything we can do for you in this hot market, give me a call or send me an email today. I’d be happy to let you know how we can help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Being+purposeful+is+key+in+our+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Being+purposeful+is+key+in+our+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you ever made an impulsive decision and later realized you forgot to consider a number of important things? Many buyers just like you are afraid of this when a house is listed for sale and multiple offers seem to appear within minutes. This is what we help our buyers avoid. The last thing I want is for you to have buyer's remorse when you make such a big purchase.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you ever made an impulsive decision and later realized you forgot to consider a number of important things? Many buyers just like you are afraid of this when a house is listed for sale and multiple offers seem to appear within minutes. This is what we help our buyers avoid. The last thing I want is for you to have buyer's remorse when you make such a big purchase.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Staging Tips that Earn You Thousands</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/staging-tips-that-earn-you-thousands.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-31 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Staging+tips+that+earn+you+thousands.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You probably already know that when you sell a home, it’s not the same as when you live in a home. With that in mind, I have four tips for you to stage your home and sell for top dollar in today’s market.

My first tip is to make a good first impression because the first impression is the lasting impression. Buyers take about three to five seconds to make that first impression when they pull up to the house, so clean up the exterior, add some color to the porch, and make sure your trim is freshly painted. When buyers walk into your home, you have another three to five seconds to cement that first impression.

This leads me to my next tip—always be show ready. In the mornings and evenings, take a look at each room and make sure everything is how you want a buyer to see the house as they walk through it. One great tip I got from Flylady.net is to go through your house every night and pick up the misplaced things you see in each room. Then, when you get the call that someone is coming for a showing, have a list of “hot spots” to take a look at where you know things tend to accumulate quickly.

“Use these four tips to get your home sold today for top dollar.”

My third tip is to take the “home” out of your house. For example, you need to take personalized items like your family photos down. These photos cause buyers to see your family in the home instead of theirs. And the infamous photo wall hallways– they make buyers uncomfortable from the lack of perceived space when walking down that hallway.

Next, put away about one-third of your stuff. If you have extra bookcases, tables, or trunks that are making any walkways smaller or more inconvenient, remove them. I‘m not a fan of long-term storage units, but they can come in handy when storing these items in the short term. Also, make sure all your closets are half-empty. You want people to look inside of them and see that there’s plenty of room for clothes.

My last and most important tip is to hire an informed, professional agent and price it right. Pricing is critical when it comes to getting your home sold for top dollar in today’s market. I can’t tell you how many times- even this last year- I’ve seen people list their home for more than it’s worth and end up taking even less than they should have in the end. Hire an agent who’s doing business right now and understands what’s happening in your neighborhood.

If you have any questions about staging or are thinking about selling your home, please give me a call. I am happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Staging+tips+that+earn+you+thousands.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Staging+tips+that+earn+you+thousands.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You probably already know that when you sell a home, it’s not the same as when you live in a home. With that in mind, I have four tips for you to stage your home and sell for top dollar in today’s market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You probably already know that when you sell a home, it’s not the same as when you live in a home. With that in mind, I have four tips for you to stage your home and sell for top dollar in today’s market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why We Don’t Chase the Almighty Dollar</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/why-we-dont-chase-the-almighty-dollar.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+makes+our+service+different%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I wanted to talk about sales—how I serve you, and how that service also serves me at the same time.

Picture a salesperson. Sometimes, I hear from people about what that picture looks like to them. In the last month, I’ve had two people share their assumptions of what it means to make a living from sales. Their emphasis was on the “sales” portion of that paradigm. Let me tell you: at Sandy and Company, we’re on the opposite side.

At Keller Williams Realty, just like in many other businesses, we have mottos. One of these is “Customers always comes first.” If I can’t get a customer what they’re looking for, I will tell them. Likewise, when I believe I can help, I jump right in and make it happen.

Going back to the two who shared with me. One of them said he knew I was tempted to withhold information about what might be wrong with the house in the name of getting the sale done. I told him that wasn’t true at all. Don’t get me wrong, I have temptations, but that’s never one of them.

In the other conversation, she assumed my goal is to push my clients to the very top of their purchase point. In theory, that would serve me best. Once again, I had to correct her. That’s never my goal. as long as we can meet their home needs for less. On the contrary, I love it when my clients purchase well below their price points.

“My job is to serve you—not the almighty dollar.”

Why? Because my goal is to make sure that I serve your whole life situation. This means what’s most important is meeting your needs in the long run. If a client of mine purchases for less than they can afford, that means they could save extra money for other needs in their life. And when I serve you well, you are going to be so excited that someone is taking great care of you and giving you all of their expertise and knowledge. You’re going to tell others about me, and that meets my needs in the long run.

When I’m in sales, there is a transaction happening, but what I’m thinking about is how I can serve you today. If that means we make a transaction together, great! If not, I’m satisfied as long as I know that I helped you. My clients know that about me, which make them comfortable to introduce me to their friends, family and colleagues.

Just yesterday, some clients and I let go of a project we had been working on for six months. It was an arduous process, and we weren’t sure it was going to work, but we gave it a shot anyway. When the numbers didn’t add up in the end and my clients asked to kill the deal, I understood completely. My job is to serve you—not the almighty dollar.

If you’re looking to buy or sell real estate, please give me a call or shoot me an email. If I’m not the right person for the job, I promise you I’ll find someone who is. I look forward to helping you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+makes+our+service+different%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+makes+our+service+different%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here at Sandy and Company, if we’re going to serve you, we do it with your whole life situation in mind.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here at Sandy and Company, if we’re going to serve you, we do it with your whole life situation in mind.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do Golf and Real Estate Have in Common?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-do-golf-and-real-estate-have-in-common.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+golf+is+like+real+estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our warm weather is winding down here, but one of the things I really enjoy about both summer and autumn is that both seasons give us a chance to get outside and play golf. It’s a relatively new hobby of mine, and I’ve had a great time lately strengthening my game and thinking about how golf is like real estate.

Golf is different than my previous hobbies like quilting, gardening, or scrapbooking. Then I could produce something tangible to show for my efforts. In golf, when I have a great score, I still feel like I’ve accomplished something.

How does this relate to real estate? Real estate has an end product as well. Most of the time, you have a closing at the end—someone bought a house and someone sold a house. Whether my clients get a paycheck, a new home, or something off their shoulders that they don’t have to think about anymore, it’s a great thing to look back on.

“In both golf and real estate, I can depend on feedback in order to get better.”

Also, when I make a mistake while golfing, I can ask for feedback from my group and advice to improve my game. When real estate issues come up, my amazing team provides feedback and advice on the best way to serve our client. It’s very much a group effort, and we have something great to show for it at the end.

As you may have seen from my Facebook post this summer, I’m using the budget model of golf. This doesn’t mean it costs less money: rather, I’m squeezing every last pennies’ worth of value because my score(strokes) are so high. I’m going to enjoy my game, appreciate the people around me, and learn from my mistakes.

I was also fortunate enough to have been able to join golf and real estate in a literal sense when I sponsored a charity golf tournament this last summer for Leah’s Dream Foundation. Whenever I can put golf and real estate together, I get the chance to know people, serve them, and have a great time. So if I ever see you out on the golf course, be sure to come up and say hello!

In the meantime, if you’re looking to sell or buy real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+golf+is+like+real+estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+golf+is+like+real+estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Though golf is a new hobby of mine, it shares many characteristics with the real estate world. Each practice has taught me something about the other.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Though golf is a new hobby of mine, it shares many characteristics with the real estate world. Each practice has taught me something about the other.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We're On It For Our Clients</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/were-on-it-for-our-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+We%2527re+on+it+for+our+clients.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Just before Thanksgiving, we were introduced to a couple who weren’t having much luck with their current agent. This agent was selling their house in Woodinville. She’d finally found them a buyer, but she was not returning phone calls and took days to follow up on requests. They knew that on their next purchase they needed an agent who was much more responsive. We talked with our couple that day, looked at five homes the next day, made two offers that night, and had one accepted by the weekend. We accomplished this even though this purchase was contingent on the their existing home selling.

Next, it was time to schedule the inspection. It was really a clean house overall, and the inspector didn’t find many issues. Then we went out to the back porch, and the light wasn’t turning on. I thought that maybe the bulb just needed to be replaced, but the bulb just turned in circles when I tried to unscrew it.

“We take active responsibility and make things happen.”

We asked the seller to make sure the light was working. To our surprise, they refused this simple repair. They said it had worked the night before, so the inspector must have broken it. Because I had tried to unscrew the light, I knew I could have been the one to break it. Either way, I wasn’t going to get in the way of my client’s dream home because of a broken light fixture. I volunteered to have the light fixed and we moved on with the deal.

That’s just a little slice of what we do. If we cause a problem, we take responsibility to fix it. We look for solutions, and we won’t let our pride jeopardize our clients’ goals.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+We%2527re+on+it+for+our+clients.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+We%2527re+on+it+for+our+clients.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We have a great story to share today. It’s about how we were able to help some clients out of a stalemate during the inspection period.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We have a great story to share today. It’s about how we were able to help some clients out of a stalemate during the inspection period.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Working with Our Team Benefits You</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-working-with-our-team-benefits-you.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+work+with+our+real+estate+team%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you’re thinking of buying or selling a house, what you’re really thinking about is yourself. You aren’t thinking about your Realtor’s system and whether it’s set up to help you. Knowing whether that system involves working with a team or not, though, can prove critical.

Some people might assume that more people means more problems, but that’s not usually true. Let me share an example.

Just this last month, we were working for one of our buyers who had a few hiccups in his transaction. When we initially wrote the offer, I knew his loan wasn’t going to be the easiest. Still, it was only a matter of following a step-by-step process. Which is why we asked for a six-week closing.

After the listing agent talked with the seller, she came back to me and asked,”Could we close sooner?”

My standard response to this request is,”Sure, although we may ask for a couple extra days at the very end if we need them.” As per the listing agent’s wishes, we made the closing date sooner by about a week. From there, everything started moving forward—the client got the house, we completed the inspection and appraisal, and we were just about to get documents to escrow.

“On a team, everyone has to work together to find a solution.”

Just before the underwriter fully checked off, however, she realized that my client’s IRS auto-payment had not been deducted out of his account. Because we needed time to work with the IRS, we asked the seller for another week. Of course, the seller was not happy with this request. They were in the process of buying their own house, and they were getting charged by the builder every single day that they were late for that closing.

I felt very responsible for this quagmire until my office manager reminded me that we’d originally asked for this closing date. With this in mind, we went back to the listing agent and asked for the time back that we originally gave them. Doing that made our responsibility much easier to handle and freed us up to find a solution.

So you see that when we have more people involved in a transaction, we work more efficiently to get the job done. Let me know what we can do to get my team working for you, whether that means buying a house today or six months down the road.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+work+with+our+real+estate+team%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+work+with+our+real+estate+team%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Working with a team means knowing that everyone is on the same page to find the best solution as quickly as possible.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Working with a team means knowing that everyone is on the same page to find the best solution as quickly as possible.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do We Go the Extra Mile(s) for Our Clients?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-do-we-go-the-extra-miles-for-our-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+we+go+the+extra+mile%2528s%2529+for+our+clients.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does it mean for us to go the extra mile for one of our clients? Let me tell you a story.

A few months ago, I got an email from one of my past clients who needed to sell his home and buy a new one for him and his fiance. We were excited to help him. Ultimately, he chose a home in Monroe. We competed for this house against another buyer and won. When we scheduled the inspection, though, we found that the roof was toast and asked the seller to replace it.

The seller took this request hard because he had just put $20,000 into the house to fix it up after he had renters in it. Since he decided it was too much for him to handle, we offered to split the cost with him. We raised the price of the house a little bit, but that wasn’t a problem for my buyer because he was going to get the full value of that roof. To give the seller confidence that we weren’t going anywhere after they put another $7,000 into their house, we also agreed to make our earnest money non-refundable after the roof was finished.

Everything moved along nicely…until the house didn’t appraise. We went back and forth a couple times with the seller and his agent, but the seller wouldn’t budge. He wanted every single penny that he had originally been promised. My buyer, though, was not going to pay more for the house than he could finance, and he wasn’t going to pay more than what it was worth.

“On our team, we work to find solutions.”

At this point, we started talking with our lender about different finance options that could breathe life into this transaction. My lender suggested raising the interest rate a little bit so that instead of my buyer having to bring in his money to pay for his own closing costs, he could use it as a down payment and cover the roof expense. The process was a tad complicated, but the numbers equaled out in the end and my buyer was excited to hear about this compromise.

When I emailed our proposal to the seller’s agent, I got no response. So I reached out again, with still no response. I decided then that I needed to jump in and make this deal personal. In our business, we don’t have a lot of face-to-face conferencing anymore. Communication in today’s real estate transactions rely on text and email. I decided, though, that it was time to show up at this agent’s office. I cleared my calendar and got in my car. When I arrived, he was in the middle of a meeting. I waited for him to finish.

Once we got the chance to actually talk face to face, he relayed his seller’s frustration to me. He had already put so much work into the house, he shouldn’t have to bite the bullet and eat the whole expense. When I pointed out the counter-proposal that I’d sent to him, he hadn’t even seen it yet. He asked whether my buyer had agreed to this proposal. He promised to contact the seller and get back to me right away. The seller wasn’t excited, but it was a good middle-ground compromise. They took our proposal.

Now my buyer and his fiance are having their first Christmas together in their new home. All because I went a little old-school and met face to face to explain our proposal.  That’s what I mean by going the extra mile for my clients.

If you’re looking for an agent who is willing to be a part of the solution, I’m your gal. If you’re interested in buying or selling or just want to hear how today’s market affects you, please don’t hesitate to call me or send me an email. We’re happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+we+go+the+extra+mile%2528s%2529+for+our+clients.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sandy+Eagon/Puget+Sound+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+we+go+the+extra+mile%2528s%2529+for+our+clients.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The art of winning a negotiation for our team is based on our ability to find a solution to any problem. To show you what I mean, I have a quick story to tell you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The art of winning a negotiation for our team is based on our ability to find a solution to any problem. To show you what I mean, I have a quick story to tell you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Donate to Your Local Food Bank This Fall</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/donate-to-your-local-food-bank-this-fall.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-12 12:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Fall can be a really exciting time. The leaves start turning, the air gets crisp, and the holidays are just around the corner. When everything is groovy around you — the roof over your head is solid and your cupboards are full — it’s easy to think of the fall as a harvest time, a time of ample supply. Unfortunately, that is not the case for everyone.

In the Marysville community, we have a large population of people who are either hungry or on the verge of hunger. This is true in every community, including Everett, Stanwood, and Lake Stevens. Jesus said that the poor will always be with you, but we don’t want them to be the same people all the time. It’s really important to make sure that we do what we can as the hands and the feet of Jesus, caring for our neighbors.

Jesus also said that when you give out a cup of water in His name, you are giving it to Him. We need to help our communities in tangible ways. October is the food drive month for Realtors, and that’s why I’m sending you this. If you can, please drop off food or cash donations to our office and we will deliver them to the Marysville Food Bank. I can even swing by and pick up your donations from you.

If you are not from Marysville but would like to support the food bank, let me know. I can put you in touch with someone either in Marysville or in your own community. Remember, it’s important to give where you live.
“Let’s be good neighbors to each other.”
One reason the food bank is so near to my heart is that when I was a child, we often got those baskets of food. We got the commodity cheese, powdered scrambled eggs, and powdered milk from the government. I didn’t even like real milk when I first tried it because I wasn’t used to it. It’s very important to me that when I am experiencing abundance that I give back as well. Please help us be a resource for others.

If you are on the other side of this — if you are struggling right now, please let me know. I can put you in touch with someone who can help you. The Everett Gospel Mission not only helps people with housing, they will also give you a bag of food. They even have a little store that you can walk through complete with household items, clothes, and food that you can have for free.

So this fall, let’s be good neighbors to each other. If you are my neighbor and you need help, please open up. I am here to help you. At Keller Williams, we are a team. TEAM stands for Together Everyone Achieves More. Let’s work together to put food on the table for our neighbors and make our community a great place to live.

Again, if you have any donations for our food bank, just drop them off at our office at 1027 State Ave #102 in Marysville. If you can’t make the trip, let me know and I will collect the donations for you. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When everything is going groovy for you, it’s easy to think of fall as a time of harvest and ample supply. However, there are many out there who are hungry. We need to be a resource to them too.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When everything is going groovy for you, it’s easy to think of fall as a time of harvest and ample supply. However, there are many out there who are hungry. We need to be a resource to them too.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Our Buyer Shrunk Her Home and Evaporated Her Mortgage Payment</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-our-buyer-shrunk-her-home-and.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-05 12:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to tell you a story about a Baby Boomer buyer we just helped downsize and why she’s so excited about her brand new home in her retirement years.

I got a call from a lender with a client who was very stressed out–she had a nearly 4,000 sq. ft. house with three living spaces and a huge garage. It was an older brick home that needed some paint and just some all-around love. The payment was also huge, nearly $4,000. It was just too much.

She has been working hard all her life and is coming up on retirement. She was also having a hard time making ends meet because of this monstrous payment and all the maintenance required. So my lender spoke with her about her whole financial situation and found that she was in a position to buy a reverse mortgage.

Now, a reverse mortgage is not for everyone and there are some important criteria to consider, so I’ll refer you to my lender for that conversation if it’s one you want to have.
“Where are you in the cycle of your home life?”
With the reverse mortgage, our buyer was able to put down a significant chunk for a down payment, and now she’s not going to have a payment for the rest of time she lives in her home. All she has to do is maintain her insurance, taxes, and the home itself.

When looking at houses, she needed something with separate spaces for both herself and her adult son who lived with her. We were able to find her a split-level home where he has the lower level and she has the upstairs, and the home is much newer than her previous home. It’s perfect for them.

And this was the very first house we looked at. We looked at a couple others, but the first house ended up being her perfect home. It really does happen once in a while. We’re getting her previous home ready for the market, and we know it will be perfect for someone needing more space.

If you’re looking into your retirement years and you’re thinking about your house and your mortgage, I’d love to talk with you about it. The question is this–where are you in the cycle of your home life? Give me a call or send me an email and we’ll talk soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I have a story I wanted to share about a buyer who we recently helped downsize into a newer home that better fit her needs as she transitioned into retirement.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I have a story I wanted to share about a buyer who we recently helped downsize into a newer home that better fit her needs as she transitioned into retirement.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Win as a Buyer in Today’s Market </title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-to-win-as-buyer-in-todays-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-21 15:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It is a tough market out there for buyers right now and it’s important that you work with the right agent. Our team works hard to help buyers win in this market, and you should make sure you work with an agent who knows how to compete with other offers.

Last weekend, I was doing an open house for one of my sellers. It was a hot listing that went on the market Wednesday and by Saturday, we already had a full-price offer in place. However, we still held open houses that weekend because we had already said we would wait to review offers that Monday.

One of the buyers who walked in had seen our advertising and really wanted to check out the home. However, they were also bummed because they had just lost out on a house. I said, “I know, it’s a pretty tough market out there. We’re doing a lot of escalation clauses.” I mentioned a few other things we do to help our buyers get ahead in the current market, and they just said, “What’s that?”

Their reaction really gave me pause because we talk about how we can help our buyers win so frequently that it just becomes an automatic part of our process. There are tools you can use to make your offer better than someone else’s and there are ways to put your best offer forward. You don’t have to max out your budget right away; you can start out softer so that you are able to get stronger down the line, and we can help you get that house.
“We have tools and strategies to help buyers win in this tough market.”
I took the time to educate this buyer, which still benefits my seller. “Let’s say we have a full-price offer. Here is how you might craft your offer to get the home.” They hadn’t heard any of these strategies before. But they still thought it didn’t matter because the main problem was the seller probably wouldn’t pay the closing costs. My answer? “That’s no problem at all!”

Most sellers are willing to pay closing costs, especially if they get the price they want for the house. I gave them a few different points to make their offer better. They went back to their own agent and wrote their own offer. The agent called me the next day with some questions. The buyer wound up getting the house for $15,000 less than their max and my seller was able to get $5,000 more than they expected, even after paying the buyers’ closing costs.

We can make this happen for you. Don’t assume that just because your agent is part of a big team means they will know, understand and use all of the strategies necessary to win in this tough market. Talk to your agent about what happens when you’re in a bidding war. If you’re not sure what questions to ask them, give me a call and I can help you out.

If you have any other real estate questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you are a buyer in today’s market, you probably know that things are tough out there. How can you win the house you want?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you are a buyer in today’s market, you probably know that things are tough out there. How can you win the house you want?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Be a Savvy Investor by Using a Tax Deferred Exchange</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/be-savvy-investor-by-using-tax-deferred.html</link>
        
          <category>More Sandy & Company Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-30 16:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re an investor looking to sell a property you didn’t live in and avoid paying the capital gains tax on the sale, you need to think about using a tax deferred exchange. That means, basically, rolling the profit you’d make from that sale directly into your next purchase.

In our market, it’s the perfect time to sell. Is it the perfect time to buy for an investment property, though?

Let’s say you sell a 1,500 square foot house and buy a 2,500 square foot house. Then, let’s say you sold that slightly bigger house and bought a duplex. With those three purchases, you’re getting a bigger investment and putting your equity to work for you by having your tenants pay rent, and still not paying any capital gains tax. You’re delaying paying any meaningful taxes until further down the road when you’re not in your strongest income years.
“If you’re an investor, you need to think about using a tax deferred exchange.”
The question, then, isn’t whether investing in real estate is a good idea, but how to do it in a savvy manner. I have no problem paying taxes; I just don’t plan to be paying more than I need to.

If any of this interests you, reach out to me by giving me a call or sending me an email. I’m excited to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re an investor looking to sell a property you didn’t live in and avoid paying the capital gains tax on the sale, you need to think about using a tax deferred exchange. That means, basically, rolling the profit you’d make from that sale directly into your next purchase.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re an investor looking to sell a property you didn’t live in and avoid paying the capital gains tax on the sale, you need to think about using a tax deferred exchange. That means, basically, rolling the profit you’d make from that sale directly into your next purchase.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How a $10 Wax Ring Could Save You $10,000</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-10-wax-ring-could-save-you-10000.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Tips and Tricks</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-22 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What do you know about the wax rings on toilets? It’s a very sexy topic, I know.

I recently had two different clients whose inspectors found leaking toilets. In fact, one of the leaks had spread underneath both the bathtub and the surrounding ceramic tile floor. And the seller refused to handle that repair, so my buyer inherited this problem.

This turned out to be a $10,000 repair job!

Do you know how much a new wax ring around that toilet would have cost? About $8. If that seller had replaced the wax ring when needed, the entire $10,000 repair job could have disappeared. Good thing my buyer is planning to do some remodeling in the future, but he still had to spend $2,500 to repair just the minimum damage.
“Wouldn’t you spend $8 to save $10,000?”
So this led me to do some research on toilet maintenance (yeah, it’s a glamorous job being your Realtor resource!). After all, it’s hard to notice a leak when it’s under ceramic tile. What I found is that a properly installed wax ring should protect for 10 to 20 years. So even if all seems well but it has been 10 or 12 years, pick a day. Drain the toilet and replace the wax ring, because it doesn’t cost much at all.

And do it right! Failing to install a wax ring properly can be just as expensive as having it fail on its own. Further, it can also cause dangerous sewer gas to enter your home.That ring connects the toilet to the floor, acting like a caulking that keeps water and sewer gas from leaking out. But even if you want to hire a professional to ensure it’s done completely correctly, it will only cost you a couple hundred bucks, instead of $10,000!  It’s not worth the risk!

If you notice any issue with your floor, take care of it quickly. $8? or $10,000? I know which one I’d rather leave in my pocket.

If you have more questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What do you know about the wax rings on toilets? It’s a very sexy topic, I know.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What do you know about the wax rings on toilets? It’s a very sexy topic, I know.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Agents Must Take the Lead through the Home Sale Process</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/agents-must-take-lead-through-home-sale.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-03 12:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Legal deadlines are one of the most important facets of real estate, so it’s important to have the help of your real estate expert with you all along the way.

In a perfect world, you sign a contract and in 30 days, the buyer has the keys. This is a really complicated transaction though, with legal and physical issues, lender criteria, and much more in between. It’s our job to understand this process so we can assure your success down the road.

We track when your loan gets out of the underwriting process, so you have time to sign disclosures and have the correct documents reviewed. There may also be agreed-upon repairs to inspect prior to closing. Sometimes these repairs aren’t done to the buyer’s satisfaction, which can cause a lot of heartache and delay.

We deal with the appraiser who may expect things to be done a certain way as well. Appraisers can’t simply take our word that repairs were done right on the home - they re-inspect as well. Many things happen in 30 to 45 days, and much gets pushed into the last two weeks.
“We’ll make sure you have a Plan A, B, and C to achieve your real estate goals.”
Both buyers and sellers have other issues going on in their lives, which also complicates matters. For instance, the seller may be buying a new home too, and they’re being held accountable to their seller to get the funds for their closing. If they can’t close on the home you’re buying, they may not be able to close in time on their next home. It’s extremely stressful. Consider services like a moving truck as well: many are booked three weeks in advance, and can’t accommodate changes on two days’ notice.

My job as a consultant is to talk with you about all these different issues and to ensure that you’re prepared for Plan B and maybe even Plan C. We want to make sure that if we don’t take the exact path we planned on taking at the beginning, we still get you to your destination.

If you have any questions about the real estate process or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in Puget Sound, give me a call today. Make it a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Legal deadlines are one of the most important facets of real estate, so it’s important to have the help of your real estate expert with you all along the way.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Legal deadlines are one of the most important facets of real estate, so it’s important to have the help of your real estate expert with you all along the way.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>To Permit or Not To Permit</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/to-permit-or-not-to-permit.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Tips and Tricks</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-27 09:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

When homeowners are going to build or remodel something in their home, do they really need a permit? It might seem tempting to just skip this step, but as you’ll see, it can have some horrendous consequences.

A client of mine is currently buying a home here in Washington. However, he needs to sell his home in Alaska first. Things were going just great until he found out that there was a problem with the garage he had built behind his Alaska home. The county found that the garage was built three feet into the setback from the property line. He had to go in front of the zoning board to ask for a variance to be able to sell his property with the garage. They said no.

Now the owner has to take three feet off his garage, and that involves removing the stairs, the roof, and changing the foundation.
“It’s important to consider all the possible consequences.”
He thought he was making the right move because he was very handy and knew how to build a garage. What he did not take into account was that he needed a permit. If he would have spent the $100 or so to get the permit, he could have discovered the setback and updated his building plans accordingly.

Now it is going to cost him more than $18,000 to remove three feet from the corner of his garage. We’re confident that we’ll be able to find a solution in the end, but the transaction is a hot mess right now. He’s wishing he got that permit right about now, and you would too if this happened to you.

So, when you’re considering a remodel or home improvement project, ask yourself what the possible consequences could be. If they’re anywhere near the trouble that this seller had to go through, go ahead and get a permit. It will save you much more in the long run.

UPDATE: As it turns out, this my client had originally gotten the permit for his garage. However, he changed the project plans after getting the permit and did not check with the county. He wanted the lines of the garage to match his house instead of the property line. So he turned the garage, and that’s when the corner of the garage pushed into that setback.

Since he didn’t follow up with anyone about his permit after changing the plans, he’s dealing with a lot of heartache along with the almost $20,000. He lost his Alaska buyer and the Washington home he was hoping to move into.

This is still a lesson in not only acquiring a permit, but following a permit closely.

If you have any questions for me don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When homeowners are going to build or remodel something in their home, do they really need a permit? It might seem tempting to just skip this step, but as you’ll see, it can have some horrendous consequences.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When homeowners are going to build or remodel something in their home, do they really need a permit? It might seem tempting to just skip this step, but as you’ll see, it can have some horrendous consequences.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Summer 2016 Home Price Update</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/summer-2016-home-price-update.html</link>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-03 13:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Clients and friends,

I have an important update for you about the value of your home.

If you’ve been following the news, the Federal Reserve is likely to raise interest rates when they meet on June 15th.

It’s been all over the news these past few weeks.


Why the Federal Reserve has to raise interest rates
This makes it more expensive for people to own a home by raising their mortgage payments.

It also decreases your pool of buyers thus lowering your home value.

Further, after a 6-year record run up in home prices since the 2008-2009 recession, this may be the last year to get the maximum price on your home sale.

It’s likely we’ll see a market correction next year.

We’re still seeing neighborhoods with very tight inventory. This means if you list your home for sale, it will sell quickly and in many neighborhoods above asking price.

I write you because this summer is the best year to sell your home to get the maximum price.

If you are thinking about selling your home, I have a special gift for you…

It’s the latest housing data from the market. It will give you a good guideline of where the market is going but at the end of the day, the best way to get up-to-date information about the market is by speaking with an expert, like the members of our team.

You can find out what your home is worth right now based on your neighbor’s recent home sale price.

Want to know what your home would sell for today?

Enter your home address here to learn what price your home is worth.

With a short visit to your home, I’ll fill you in on what price it will sell for today at no charge.

We’ve worked with many home buyers recently and know exactly what people are looking for in the hottest homes.

My estimates are right on the money.

And not to worry - if you’re thinking about buying a new home, I’ll share with you the neighborhoods where home prices are now more affordable.

You may be able to live in a nicer area you previously thought unaffordable.

I can also help you secure a low, fixed rate mortgage without junk fees with a minimal down payment.

I’ll put you in touch with my best preferred lenders.

Anyway, I write you since we’re wrapping up one of the hottest home selling seasons ever.

Our economy is normalizing, interest rates are rising, and pent-up demand following the 2008-2009 recession is less. This is the summer to sell your home.

So, I invite you to find out what your home will sell for. It’s free to you.

You can also email or call me at (425) 422-7372 or &#083;&#097;&#110;&#100;&#121;&#064;&#083;&#097;&#110;&#100;&#121;&#065;&#110;&#100;&#067;&#111;&#109;&#112;&#097;&#110;&#121;&#046;&#099;&#111;&#109;. I’m happy to answer any questions you have about real estate.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our economy is normalizing, interest rates are rising, and pent-up demand following the 2008-2009 recession is less. This is the summer to sell your home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our economy is normalizing, interest rates are rising, and pent-up demand following the 2008-2009 recession is less. This is the summer to sell your home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Now Is the Time for Sellers to Act</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/now-is-time-for-sellers-to-act.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-02 11:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re in the Puget Sound area and haven’t been able to sell your home in the last few years because your value isn’t quite where you want it to be, we’ve got some great information to share with you.

A homeowner reached out to me about a month and a half ago. They had tried to sell last year, but they owed more than their market value. When they’d bought, they needed all 3200 square feet: they had three children at home and were holding church services in their bonus room. But now it was time to downsize, both for size and money. The husband had just changed jobs and travels a lot, so they weren’t even sure whether Snohomish County was where they wanted to be. Two of the three children are moving out in the fall. Their budget was stretched, the market is peaking, and they knew it was time to sell.
“You can accomplish your selling goals in today’s market.”
After looking at the home, we decided that if the home was going to sell, this was the market to do it in. We did our full marketing blitz, including personally inviting the neighbors to our open house that had about 30 buyers go through. We really pushed the top of the market with our price, and we were hoping for one or two good offers. We had several people come through multiple times, and the right buyer showed up.

We secured a full-price offer for our sellers, and the home sale just closed. This family decided to rent so they have the flexibility to decide where they want to settle in the next year. They have 1,500 less square feet to clean, pay $1,000 less per month on their rent, and they accomplished all of this in today’s market.

We are at the peak of the market, the growth is slowing. There’s a shift coming up, so your top window of opportunity in this market is closing. Who do you know who we can help with our expert service and proven systems to get top dollar?

If you or someone you know has been wondering whether it’s the right time to sell, we would be happy to talk to you. Just give us a call or send us an email and we’ll be in touch!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re in the Puget Sound area and haven’t been able to sell your home in the last few years because your value isn’t quite where you want it to be, we’ve got some great information to share with you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re in the Puget Sound area and haven’t been able to sell your home in the last few years because your value isn’t quite where you want it to be, we’ve got some great information to share with you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Puget Sound Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-02 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Our real estate market has been wildly hot for the past few years. It’s even been so good that some people think we’d made another bubble, but we’re starting to see some of that growth slow down. Between January 2015 to 2016, we experienced 11% growth in our market. That is pretty typical from what we have been seeing, but from month to month after January, we have seen that growth trickle slowly down to 8%.

What does this mean for you? If you’re thinking of selling, you may want to do so soon. Prices are still rising, and they certainly won’t be falling, but you may be better off selling your home right now. Most people look to the past to predict their outcome, but I have to look towards the future for you, and our market is slowing down.
“Market growth is slowing, but that doesn’t mean it’s a bad time to buy or sell.”
I can’t tell you what the future will be like, but I can tell you that growth is slowing for right now. This doesn’t mean you need to rush to get your home on the market, but it’s a good idea to step in sooner than later.

If you’re buying, this slowing is helping you. Remember that interest rates are still very low. This is why you need to call me and discuss all the factors in our market that affect your home search. Give me a call today!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our real estate market has been wildly hot for the past few years. It’s even been so good that some people think we’d made another bubble, but we’re starting to see some of that growth slow down. Between January 2015 to 2016, we experienced 11% growth in our market. That is pretty typical from what we have been seeing, but from month to month after January, we have seen that growth trickle slowly down to 8%.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our real estate market has been wildly hot for the past few years. It’s even been so good that some people think we’d made another bubble, but we’re starting to see some of that growth slow down. Between January 2015 to 2016, we experienced 11% growth in our market. That is pretty typical from what we have been seeing, but from month to month after January, we have seen that growth trickle slowly down to 8%.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Be Worried About Puget Sound Real Estate?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/should-you-be-worried-about-puget-sound.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-19 12:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re seeing a very small amount of homes available in Puget Sound, and demand is sky-high right now. There is less than a month’s supply of homes! That means we’re operating in a heavy seller’s market. If no new homes come on the market in the next 27 days, we would be left without any homes to buy or sell.

So, what does this mean for buyers in Puget Sound? You’ll have to fight other buyers if you find a home that you like. On a recent showing with a buyer, we encountered another buyer completing an inspection even before they made an offer on the home. Of the five offers the agent received, four out of these five families opted to get pre-inspections done. Traditionally, this inspection happens after a seller accepts a buyer’s offer. This means that the other three families just spent $300-$400 on an inspection, and they didn’t even win the house.
“Your home will sell before you can bat an eye.”
So what advice are we giving buyers? We recommend that you don’t fall in love with a home when you walk in. Be realistic - this market is crazy and you might just have a home swept out from under you by a buyer that’s even more eager than you. If you’ve fallen in love and lost the home, then you will have a hard time acting when you have another opportunity. Also, you’re going to have to make some sacrifices if you want your dream home. Size, money, or finishes- you’re either paying more or getting less.

However, we have just helped two buyers win bidding wars on homes, so it is possible and we know how to win over sellers.

For sellers in Puget Sound, we have one simple question; what are you waiting for? Get your home on the market immediately if you want to sell! Your home will sell before you bat an eye.

If you’re looking to buy or sell in Puget Sound, please don’t hesitate to contact me. You deserve an expert at your side to navigate you through this tough market!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’re seeing a very small amount of homes available in Puget Sound, and demand is sky-high right now. There is less than a month’s supply of homes! That means we’re operating in a heavy seller’s market. If no new homes come on the market in the next 27 days, we would be left without any homes to buy or sell.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re seeing a very small amount of homes available in Puget Sound, and demand is sky-high right now. There is less than a month’s supply of homes! That means we’re operating in a heavy seller’s market. If no new homes come on the market in the next 27 days, we would be left without any homes to buy or sell.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Faith and Support Systems, Final Thoughts with Sylvia Anderson</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/faith-and-support-systems-final.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-09 12:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I’m here recounting my interview with Sylvia Anderson. Unfortunately, we experienced some technical difficulties during recording, so I want to recreate it for you. The last portion of our talk focused on the challenging position of her team, including helping people in crisis and supporting them.

I asked Sylvia how she keeps strong for her clients. She has to keep herself refreshed, or she gives out stale water, she said. One way is that when she’s off the grounds she leaves her work at the office.

Since we’d been talking about how they make it clear to their clients that they’re the same, I wondered how transparent are they with clients? “We have to be careful because clients are in their own crisis, and if we share our current crisis, then they jump on board to solve our issues. It’s a welcome but unhealthy diversion, so we only share situations that we’ve come through and had victory in or have learned lessons from.”
“Everyone needs a support system.”
Current staff struggles are saved for sharing outside the EGM circle. Sylvia continued that everyone needs to have a support system of two people in their lives; one we can let see us in our weakness and another who can be a truth teller, who has permission to take us aside and share a hard truth we need to hear.

So to give back, I wanted to show you how you can learn more about the mission. You can go to their website at www.EGmission.org. They offer poverty awareness training, volunteering opportunities, and tours. They’re always happy to talk about their mission. There are resources for all people in the community who need help, whether they are homeless, struggling to maintain their home, or dealing with the associated struggles.

I asked Sylvia for any final thoughts. She said, “We have a responsibility to the poor. Isaiah 43 says ‘bring my sons from afar and my daughters from ends of the Earth, everyone who is called by my name who I created for my glory whom I formed and made.’ That’s what we’re doing; bringing in God’s sons and daughters, and if we’re not giving away to people who have no way to give back to us, then we’d better check our faith.”
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I’m here recounting my interview with Sylvia Anderson. Unfortunately, we experienced some technical difficulties during recording, so I want to recreate it for you. The last portion of our talk focused on the challenging position of her team, including helping people in crisis and supporting them.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I’m here recounting my interview with Sylvia Anderson. Unfortunately, we experienced some technical difficulties during recording, so I want to recreate it for you. The last portion of our talk focused on the challenging position of her team, including helping people in crisis and supporting them.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Part 2 of My Amazing Conversation with Sylvia Anderson</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/part-2-of-my-amazing-conversation-with.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-06 15:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I recently had an amazing conversation with Sylvia Anderson of the Everett Gospel Mission. We talked a lot about faith and life and although the audio was cut short, I want to share some of the things we talked about with you. This is part two of our interview.

The message Sylvia shares the first time someone walks in their door is that we can all have faith that God is there and is for us. So I asked, “What about the second or third time someone comes in? How do they believe you this time when their circumstances are the same as before?” Sylvia responded that she is so glad God doesn’t just meet her in her addictions the first time around the mountain, He is there every time. We all have addictions, and when we say that our addictions are “better” than others, we’re setting up ourselves as the judge. Put another way, her clients’ struggles are no bigger to God than her struggles.  We are all valuable and human, and she shares that message with her clients at the Everett Gospel Mission.
“Seeds take time to grow.”
After all, how many times have you dealt with something over and over, only to finally resolve the issue? Besides, when a client comes back to EGM after being back on the street, they are not the same person as before. They’ve grown and they’ve learned. If they see something happening around them that’s not right, maybe before it didn’t bother them. And now it does. That is change to be celebrated.

Sometimes seeds take a while to grow. Change doesn’t happen overnight. Sylvia was recently with a gentleman who was getting ready to sign a lease, but was hesitant– he had never signed a lease on his own. He was 50 years old! With the support of the Everett Gospel Mission, he signed that lease and is doing well.

This is just an example of the success stories that Sylvia and the Everett Gospel Mission are seeing. Every situation is different and people constantly change and grow. When you have support from family, friends, and Jesus Christ, anything is possible.

Stay tuned for part 3 of our conversation, where we will handle being emotionally supportive of the people in your life. I can’t wait to see you soon on the next step of this faith walk.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I recently had an amazing conversation with Sylvia Anderson of the Everett Gospel Mission. We talked a lot about faith and life and although the audio was cut short, I want to share some of the things we talked about with you. This is part two of our interview.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I recently had an amazing conversation with Sylvia Anderson of the Everett Gospel Mission. We talked a lot about faith and life and although the audio was cut short, I want to share some of the things we talked about with you. This is part two of our interview.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How the Everett Gospel Mission Helps Puget Sound’s Homeless</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-everett-gospel-mission-helps-puget.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-05 15:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I recently had the pleasure of speaking with Sylvia Anderson, the CEO of Everett Gospel Mission. She’s been there for about 20 years. I took a few notes from our conversation and wanted to share those with you today.

First of all, a little information about Sylvia’s background. When she started working with the Everett Gospel Mission, she wasn’t quite sure what it was all about. So after eight months, she asked the board if she could stay and has been here ever since. She has two children, one adopted, and has also fostered a number of children.

When she was fostering, Sylvia didn’t realize she was training for her work with Everett Gospel Mission. There’s a strong correlation between foster care and homelessness: 40% of the homeless population has been in foster care.

Sylvia and I were talking about faith, and one of the first questions I asked her was, “How do you share faith with a group of people who may not see a lot of reason for faith?” She responded that actually, a lot of their clients have very strong faith. They get on their feet every morning searching for what they don’t see.
“The Everett Gospel Mission sees the homeless as Jesus would.”
Sylvia said, “Faith is the substance of things hoped for and the evidence of things not seen.” Sylvia gets the privilege of speaking with these people and helping them strengthen their faith that has already kept them going. They just don’t know the name behind it, so she and her staff have the opportunity to introduce them to Jesus, who has been with them and they may not have realized it.

“When we realize that the homeless are strong, valuable people, that helps alleviate judgment.”  The Everett Gospel Mission looks at people as Jesus would see them. Part of their mission is to open the eyes of the community to see the value in every person.

The Everett Gospel Mission works to build connections between the homeless and the rest of the community. When someone loses their home, they can also lose their sense of belonging. Sylvia wants to make it clear that they have a respectful, strong community of people at the Everett Gospel Mission and this is where they belong.

Sylvia and I talked for a while, so watch out for parts two and three of our discussion in the next few days. If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to talk with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I recently had the pleasure of speaking with Sylvia Anderson, the CEO of Everett Gospel Mission. She’s been there for about 20 years. I took a few notes from our conversation and wanted to share those with you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I recently had the pleasure of speaking with Sylvia Anderson, the CEO of Everett Gospel Mission. She’s been there for about 20 years. I took a few notes from our conversation and wanted to share those with you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Four Questions to Ask Yourself Before You Sell</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/four-questions-to-ask-yourself-before.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-06 10:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Moving from one property to another is a major decision for yourself and your family. It’s difficult to tell when the right time to sell is, but you can come closer to your answer by asking yourself a few tough questions.


  Consider some of these questions:
  If you could live anywhere, where would it be?
  Why aren’t you there yet?
  If you sell in 5-10 years, will you wish that you’d sold sooner?
  Is now the time?
“Don’t wait for the market to peak to sell your home.”
If you need a professional to consult with, please don’t hesitate to contact me. This is not a ‘yes’ or ‘no’ decision, and sometimes this answer cannot come from you alone. I would be happy to consult with you to determine an appropriate time for you and your family to sell.


Keep in mind that we expect a great spring selling season, so talk to us as soon as possible if you’re interested!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Moving from one property to another is a major decision for yourself and your family. It’s difficult to tell when the right time to sell is, but you can come closer to your answer by asking yourself a few tough questions.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Moving from one property to another is a major decision for yourself and your family. It’s difficult to tell when the right time to sell is, but you can come closer to your answer by asking yourself a few tough questions.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is Most Important to You in a Real Estate Transaction?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/what-is-most-important-to-you-in-real.html</link>
        
          <category>More Sandy & Company Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-23 15:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Real estate transactions can be tough. You often have a lot on the line, both in thousands of dollars and in the security of your home. How can you ‘win’ what you want in a real estate transaction? It helps to determine what is most important to you. You have to ask yourself what you need to get out of a transaction.

Stress is common when making negotiations in the real estate market, and when we stress we often get stuck on the smaller details. Instead, we should focus on the bigger picture and what is really at stake in your transaction.
“Think about the big picture.”
When you worry that everything is falling apart, remember the bigger picture. Sometimes several things go wrong with the home or the negotiation. That’s when we assess how important it really is, what we can do, and whether we’ll be happy with the outcome. We don’t have to walk away or bail out because we’re scared- we move step by step to resolve, overcome, and come up with a win after the finish line.

If you have any questions about buying or selling in Puget Sound, please don’t hesitate to contact me! 2016 will be a great year to sell a home, but spring has already begun, so don’t delay.

I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Real estate transactions can be tough. You often have a lot on the line, both in thousands of dollars and in the security of your home. How can you ‘win’ what you want in a real estate transaction? It helps to determine what is most important to you. You have to ask yourself what you need to get out of a transaction.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Real estate transactions can be tough. You often have a lot on the line, both in thousands of dollars and in the security of your home. How can you ‘win’ what you want in a real estate transaction? It helps to determine what is most important to you. You have to ask yourself what you need to get out of a transaction.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Smile When You Walk into Your Puget Sound Home?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/do-you-smile-when-you-walk-into-your.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-23 12:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, we’re talking about making our homes into places that make us smile. When I help clients, I explain how important it is to smile while walking through the front door.

In the winter, we have a tendency to hunker down. This time of year is great for focusing on interior projects, like making a quilt or painting a room.
“Your home is an extension of you.”
I’m a project person. My husband and I love projects that will make us smile when we walk into our homes. Now that spring is coming, it’s time to focus on outdoor projects. In fact, we just took a tree down in the backyard yesterday. We also went to Sunnyside Nursery, which has a great selection, and picked out some fruit trees to plant this weekend. We got dwarf apple, plum, and pear trees so we won’t have to spend the whole day out in the yard but can still enjoy the fruits of our labors.

We love to make our home our castle! My castle probably looks different from your castle, but if you’re a homeowner, you want to be able to come home and enjoy it. Your home is an extension of you. That’s why it’s crucial for your home to make you smile.

If you’re looking for a space to please you, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you find your castle here in Puget Sound!

With spring around the corner, it’s a perfect time to go through my 5 Step Home Review and find out what your home is worth.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, we’re talking about making our homes into places that make us smile. When I help clients, I explain how important it is to smile while walking through the front door.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, we’re talking about making our homes into places that make us smile. When I help clients, I explain how important it is to smile while walking through the front door.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Kill Your Home with Kindness</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/dont-kill-your-home-with-kindness.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-16 15:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today we’re talking about how you’re killing your home with kindness. I bring this up because spring is approaching and you’re probably going to be making some improvements to your home. Most of the time the work you do will improve your home, but sometimes it can actually take away from the value of your property.

Today we will discuss four different ways that you could be hurting your home instead of helping it.


  Don’t buy light bulbs that are too bright. Bright homes are good, but buying bulbs that are too powerful can be a fire hazard. Also related, I recommend incandescent bulbs for when you’re showing your home because they warm up quickly.
  Don’t plant trees near driveways and near your slab. Trees should be at least 10-20 feet away from paved areas, and this is also true for septic drainfield areas. The roots will destroy your driveway, and you don’t want a buyer to inherit this problem.
  Overzealous pressure washing. It’s easy to damage the wood on your deck or your siding by power washing it too vigorously. Be careful and use the right nozzle, or just hire a professional to do it. And stay off your roof with your pressure washer!!
  If you store firewood in your home, make sure it is cured and dried. Fresh wood will likely have dormant insects nesting in it, and when you bring it into your warm home, the bugs will leave the wood and enter your home. Only store a few pieces of dry wood at a time if you’re looking for ambiance.


If you’d like to learn more, ask me for a copy of 19 Ways You’re Killing Your Home with Kindness.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today we’re talking about how you’re killing your home with kindness. I bring this up because spring is approaching and you’re probably going to be making some improvements to your home. Most of the time the work you do will improve your home, but sometimes it can actually take away from the value of your property.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today we’re talking about how you’re killing your home with kindness. I bring this up because spring is approaching and you’re probably going to be making some improvements to your home. Most of the time the work you do will improve your home, but sometimes it can actually take away from the value of your property.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Unique Home Selling Story</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/a-unique-home-selling-story.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-09 13:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Last fall we sold a very unique home- let me share. Originally listed with a different agent, the home sat on 3 acres inside Marysville, but the home was priced too high. The home and property were beautiful, but it had all the original features in it. It’s what we affectionately call vintage,requiring at least $60,000 in updating to make this home shine again.

We listed the property in the range to accommodate the repairs. We got lots of showings but everyone had a bigger number in their head for repairs, so we inched the price down just a little more. There was nothing else with acreage in-town, so we gave it a little longer and kept holding open houses. Within a few days, we got two full price offers and then a third offer willing to pay $5,000 above what anyone else put down.
“We got two full price offers and then a third offer willing to pay $5,000 above what anyone else put down.”
When it was all said and done, we had three different offers resulting in $13,000 above the listed price. This was only days before we thought we were going to have to reduce the price!

So, what happened? We were patient and the market responded. We used all our marketing avenues, and the buyers who fell in love originally found us through our open house.

If you have a unique home to sell in Puget Sound, please don’t hesitate to contact us. It’s going to be a great year to sell a home!

With spring around the corner, it’s a perfect time to go through my 5 Step Home Review and find out what your home is worth.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Last fall we sold a very unique home- let me share. Originally listed with a different agent, the home sat on 3 acres inside Marysville, but the home was priced too high. The home and property were beautiful, but it had all the original features in it. It’s what we affectionately call vintage,requiring at least $60,000 in updating to make this home shine again.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Last fall we sold a very unique home- let me share. Originally listed with a different agent, the home sat on 3 acres inside Marysville, but the home was priced too high. The home and property were beautiful, but it had all the original features in it. It’s what we affectionately call vintage,requiring at least $60,000 in updating to make this home shine again.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Help You Limit the Stress that Typically Comes with Buying in a Tight Puget Sound Market</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/we-help-you-limit-stress-that-typically.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-02-23 12:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

About a year and a half ago, a couple reached out to me online. They were looking for a home that fit them and their three large dogs and property with breathing room between them and neighbors. We looked for about a year, but nothing worked perfectly. Then their landlord told them that he was selling the rental they lived in. Urgency kicked in- they needed a home that they could count on rather than try to find another landlord who would allow their dogs.

We found them a great house next to forestry land- country living and trails through the the forestry acres to walk the dogs. But the night we all came to agreement, a windstorm knocked three trees into the house.

I communicated with the listing agent regularly and then the contractor to see how work was going. Unfortunately, after two months, we realized we were no closer to work starting on the home and needed to keep looking.
“We work hard to find security for our buyers.”
Keeping this contract in place as a back-up, we chose a rambler that was perfect for their needs. It was more money, and it had a long honey-do list that came with it, but the home and property worked better for my clients than the “tree-house.” We helped them get bids on a couple of the projects to make sure they weren’t biting off more than they could chew. And our lender handled their financing which was a little tricky. After we’d cleared all the obstacles on this perfect home, we let the first house go.

Now our friends are securely in their own home with elbow room that they’ll treasure for many years to come.

We work hard to find security for our buyers so that they have a plan B should their initial plan fall through. The beauty is that sometimes Plan B turns out even better than Plan A. It’s worked for our other clients, and we’d love to make it work for you!

If you have any real estate questions or concerns, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would love to hear from you!

“Sandy is one of the most positive, upbeat, motivated, caring and just plain nice people I have ever worked with.  I believe she is actually interested in helping improve the lives of each and every client that is lucky enough to have come in contact with her.

We had a unique situation with pretty specific needs in finding the right house.   We searched and searched with Sandy and her team, looking at house after house.  We looked at so many I was worried about Sandy giving up on us.  She never did at all.  We finally found “the house” and Sandy negotiated a great deal for us.  The very night we signed the agreement the winds came up and blew not one but three trees down on the house destroying much of the upper level.  Sandy was out there with us every step again and when it became apparent the repair project would not meet our time frame needs, it was off to look at more houses.  I just knew now she had to be sick of us and would send us on our way to find another agent, but not a chance.  With the same care and energy from day one she set out to find us a great home.  After many more appointments and miles and miles of travel for Sandy and her team, we found an even better home in a beautiful location with plenty of room and trees to enjoy for years to come.  I am amazed that Sandy always had the same big smile and enthusiasm at each property we viewed and I believe that that through all this journey to find our home we were so very lucky to have come across Sandy Eagon.”  - John. J.

With spring around the corner, it’s a perfect time to go through my 5 Step Home Review and find out what your home is worth.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

About a year and a half ago, a couple reached out to me online. They were looking for a home that fit them and their three large dogs and property with breathing room between them and neighbors. We looked for about a year, but nothing worked perfectly. Then their landlord told them that he was selling the rental they lived in. Urgency kicked in- they needed a home that they could count on rather than try to find another landlord who would allow their dogs.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

About a year and a half ago, a couple reached out to me online. They were looking for a home that fit them and their three large dogs and property with breathing room between them and neighbors. We looked for about a year, but nothing worked perfectly. Then their landlord told them that he was selling the rental they lived in. Urgency kicked in- they needed a home that they could count on rather than try to find another landlord who would allow their dogs.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Market Update for the Puget Sound Area</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/market-update-for-puget-sound-area.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-02-03 08:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’ve been working throughout the surrounding Puget Sound area and the market is the same in every county! There are hardly any houses for sale. Instead of talking about inventory in terms of months, now we’re talking about it in terms of weeks: we have about five to seven weeks of inventory. If nothing new came on for sale, that’s how long it’d take to sell every house in our MLS.
“There’s next to no inventory!”
If you have a property priced right and in good condition, it can sell in two days! This urgency gives sellers so much power and buyers especially need to be conscious of this.

If you’re looking to buy, let’s have a conversation and see what the best fit is.

With spring around the corner, it’s a perfect time to go through my 5 Step Home Review and find out what your home is worth.

Reach out to me by phone or email. Capture your top dollar today!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’ve been working throughout the surrounding Puget Sound area and the market is the same in every county! There are hardly any houses for sale.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’ve been working throughout the surrounding Puget Sound area and the market is the same in every county! There are hardly any houses for sale.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Walking Out My Purpose: How Faith Can Get You Through Your Emotions</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/walking-out-my-purpose-how-faith-can.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2016-01-14 12:41:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>


Today, we’re talking about walking out our purpose. I want to work on dealing with my emotions in a way that practices my faith. Our emotions affect so much of what happens in our day and how we treat other people.

I’d like to share a conversation I had with my coach, Chris, about how to get to that next level. Here’s what I took back.

“There’s a teaching that says, ‘We can’t control the first thought, but we can control the second thought, and the third.’ It’s like putting yourself on a mental diet. You have to ask, ‘Do I really want to allow those negative thoughts?’
“You have to exercise your faith muscle.”
“You have to exercise your faith muscle. There are all kinds of levels of [physical] fitness, and for some people, just being able to move more in a general, active way is more fit than they were, especially for people overcoming health issues. Just being able to be mobile is huge, so how can we judge ourselves based on one person to the other?”

You can listen to the full conversation here. I would love to hear your thoughts. If there’s anything you can share or learn from each other to get us out of that rut of how we’ve always worked, please reach out to me. Let’s be purposeful in our lives and be that person we’re meant and created to be. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>


Today, we’re talking about walking out our purpose. I want to work on dealing with my emotions in a way that practices my faith. Our emotions affect so much of what happens in our day and how we treat other people.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>


Today, we’re talking about walking out our purpose. I want to work on dealing with my emotions in a way that practices my faith. Our emotions affect so much of what happens in our day and how we treat other people.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Selling During the Winter in Puget Sound</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/the-benefits-of-selling-during-winter.html</link>
        
          <category>Seasonal Selling</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-12-11 12:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

One of the biggest misconceptions out there is that the winter is a bad time to sell a home. Today, I have three reasons this couldn’t be further from the truth:


  
    You have less competition in January. March and April are when inventory starts to increase. When buyers have more options, you are less likely to sell your home quickly and for top dollar. Listing now is a great way to avoid getting lost in the crowd.
  
  
    Winter buyers are more motivated. In our part of the country, we get a lot of rain, wind, and sometimes snow in the winter. And yet, we still have people purchasing homes! This happens because there are always people that need to make a move in the next 30 days. The people out looking now are extremely serious about buying a home soon.
  
  
    Your competition doesn’t look perfect right now either. There aren’t many homes on the market right now, and the ones that are don’t look as good right now as they will later. Take advantage of this by making your home look spectacular right now!
“Many people mistakenly believe that the winter is a bad time to sell.”
If you’re looking to sell your home quickly and for top dollar, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would love to help you make informed decisions in today’s market!
  

</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

One of the biggest misconceptions out there is that the winter is a bad time to sell a home. Today, I have three reasons this couldn’t be further from the truth:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

One of the biggest misconceptions out there is that the winter is a bad time to sell a home. Today, I have three reasons this couldn’t be further from the truth:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have to Leave Before You Sell? We Can Help with That!</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-client-success.html</link>
        
          <category>Success Stories</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-12-11 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Recently, a client had to move out of town before they sold their property. They needed someone here in Puget Sound to manage the home sale, and we were happy to fulfill their need.

We marketed their home aggressively in many ways, including knocking on doors to let neighbors know about the new listing.

It was a nice ranch-style rambler with a three-car garage and an open back yard. When we held an open house, several neighbors came through and we ended up getting three offers on the property! We negotiated and accepted the best offer for our client.

That very night, the house was broken into. Fortunately a neighbor noticed and called us- we called our client and then the police immediately. Whoever broke in had started setting up a drug operation. We cleaned up the house, posted signs that the house was being watched and instructed the neighbors to call 911 immediately and us second this time. No need, our prompt response let the drug makers know they should go elsewhere.
“We took care of everything for our client.”
After this happened, we coordinated with the police to make sure that only certain people were allowed in the home. The neighbors kept a great eye on the house, and we had a lot of conversations to make sure everyone was safe.

That is one downside to vacant homes. Unfortunately, they are vulnerable to break-ins. Luckily, we were here to repair the damage and make a plan to prevent further incidents.

We moved smoothly to closing until the last weekend. They seller’s car broke down so he couldn’t get here to finish the final clean up and dump runs. We had promised the buyer in the contract that the house would be clean and ready. So my team hired a handyman service to haul everything out and leave the home tidy.

After the house sold, our client was able to make an offer on a new house in Spokane. The agent we set him up with got him ready to go with his new home.

We have a hands-on approach to real estate. If you know anyone who is thinking of buying or selling a home, please call or email us for an introduction. As always, if you have any real estate questions, give us a call or send us an email.

We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Recently, a client had to move out of town before they sold their property. They needed someone here in Puget Sound to manage the home sale, and we were happy to fulfill their need.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Recently, a client had to move out of town before they sold their property. They needed someone here in Puget Sound to manage the home sale, and we were happy to fulfill their need.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Tool Shed</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-tool-resources.html</link>
        
          <category>More Sandy & Company Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-11-30 13:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

In my tool shed at home, I made some additions and improvements. I’d like to share them with you today.

Recently, I added a pegboard space to organize tools in my shed. I picked it out at a local hardware store. With saws, we were able to cut it to fit the size of our wall.
“If you’re looking for any home tools, please talk to me!”
If you’re looking for any home tools, please talk to me! I can help you out. I’d love to share my resources with you. Don’t rent it out. I have plenty of tools that I’m willing to loan out to the community. Don’t be afraid to ask!

As always, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me with any and all of your real estate questions. Please reach out by phone or email!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

In my tool shed at home, I made some additions and improvements. I’d like to share them with you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

In my tool shed at home, I made some additions and improvements. I’d like to share them with you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Are We Comfortable Selling Unique Homes in the Puget Sound?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-sell-unique.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-11-03 13:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Recently, we sold a pretty unique property for a seller of ours, and today we’re talking about what we did to sell that home quickly and for top dollar. I got a call this summer from a colleague in the lending field who was ready to sell his home.

They had 5 acres, complete with a huge shop, apartment, barn, and private lakefront in a quiet area of Arlington. It was an awesome property, and there were quite a few agents competing for their listing. I put my best foot forward, told them I would earn their business, and showed them how. When they trusted me to list their home, we put together a game plan to make it happen.

The first part of the plan was marketing. We posted the listing on all of the online portals we usually do, with the addition of some specific sites where we knew the horse owners would be looking.

Since we know 70% of homes get sold through the local MLS, we had to make sure the agents out there knew exactly all we had here. We invited them to an open house for brokers, where we toured them through the great big shop and barn on the property.

“We ended up getting 2 full-price offers for the home.”
We had four strong buyer candidates in just the first weekend. None of them needed everything, so one by one the buyers started pulling out. But we knew the value was there. We continued marketing the property and each week we added another piece to get some extra exposure.

Sure enough, we had a buyer come in from out of town who was looking for a lakefront property. They came out and looked, and we started negotiating from there. Then another buyer who had looked and been asking questions offered, and we ended up getting 2 full-price offers for the home. Ultimately, we sold it to the out of town buyer, and ended up delivering a nice profit check to our sellers.

If you are looking for someone to sell your home who takes the time to understand your unique situation and use it to your advantage when marketing the property, we would love to sit down with you and talk about how we can get you the most amount of money in your pocket today.

If you have any questions for us, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Recently, we sold a pretty unique property for a seller of ours, and today we’re talking about what we did to sell that home quickly and for top dollar. I got a call this summer from a colleague in the lending field who was ready to sell his home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Recently, we sold a pretty unique property for a seller of ours, and today we’re talking about what we did to sell that home quickly and for top dollar. I got a call this summer from a colleague in the lending field who was ready to sell his home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Walking Out My Purpose: Persevering for God</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-daily.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-10-27 11:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I want to show you a brief snippet of a longer interview that I did with Pastor Chris Manginelli. You can find the full interview here.

A lot of us want instantaneous gratification, and God doesn’t always grant that. He rewards those who diligently seek him. You have to learn how to hear him and how to respond to him. To those who sincerely seek him, you will find him.
“God rewards those who diligently seek him.”
Even when life gets tough and dark, remember that life is seasonal and that God is always there for us. If you persevere, you will find God.

Once again, if you’d like to hear the full interview, you can listen to it here.

I hope that you find value in this. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to contact me!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I want to show you a brief snippet of a longer interview that I did with Pastor Chris Manginelli. You can find the full interview here.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I want to show you a brief snippet of a longer interview that I did with Pastor Chris Manginelli. You can find the full interview here.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Puget Sound Shifting Market</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-shifting-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-10-19 13:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, we’re talking about our current market. Right now, our market is shifting, so you definitely need to hear this.

Last week, for the first time in a long time, an appraisal came back where the appraiser did not give the full value of what the buyer and seller had agreed upon.

We were representing the seller, and we were pushing to sell for the highest amount we could. We contested some points of the appraisal, but ultimately, the appraisal stood. What that tells me is our market is definitely stabilizing, so sellers can’t reach that higher ground now. My broker even told me that if our listings had not sold, we need to make a 10% price drop.

The good news is that we don’t have any listings that haven’t sold, but this is just another sign that the shift I’ve been talking about for the last couple months is happening now.
“”
What does this shift mean? What do I need to do for my clients? Basically, I can report on the market and let you know how you can be successful. For sellers, this means we need to be a bit more conservative. We will have open conversations about what you can expect, and how you can get top dollar in this market.

The market is warming up to buyers. This gives buyers confidence, so we need to make sure your home is priced correctly as the market continues to slide. If you’re thinking about selling, now is the time to do so.

Buyers may lose confidence as prices go down, but with low interest rates, now is the time to buy. What you can afford to purchase will be better now than it will be next year, when we’re looking at higher interest rates. I’m actually purchasing myself because right now, buyers can afford a better house for a lower monthly payment. If you’re buying now, have confidence. You’ve made a great decision!

If you’re making a decision about buying or selling, sit down and talk with me about your specific situation. I can figure out a way to make your home dreams come true.

If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, we’re talking about our current market. Right now, our market is shifting, so you definitely need to hear this.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, we’re talking about our current market. Right now, our market is shifting, so you definitely need to hear this.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Puget Sound Real Estate Home Selling Tips</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-home-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-10-14 11:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We have a lot of professionals who ask us about handling short sale situations, particularly when their clients are in distress mode and need to sell.

For example, a couple of years ago, an agent wanted to partner with us in selling their client’s house because we could negotiate the short sale. It was a long road for that client.

Last February, we made it all the way to closing, but the buyer never sent in their money. That meant we had to relist the home. We got another offer fairly quickly. We were told that this buyer was making a cash offer, but then we got a call from a lender asking for certain documentation before they would send us the money.
“We will do everything we can to make the closing happen!”
A lot of people wanted to fire the buyer. We had to deal with the escrow people, the mortgage holders, and the lender. However, this seller deserved a close. As the professionals, we wanted to do everything in our power to make this closing happen. We were able to get everybody on board, and we had a closing right on time!

So here’s my question to you: Who do you know right now who is looking for a real estate professional who will make a sale happen for them? Whether they have equity on the home or not, we will work every angle to get that job done. Give us a call or send us an email. We would love to guide you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We have a lot of professionals who ask us about handling short sale situations, particularly when their clients are in distress mode and need to sell.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We have a lot of professionals who ask us about handling short sale situations, particularly when their clients are in distress mode and need to sell.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Puget Sound Real Estate Replacing an Old Roof</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-replacing-old.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-10-05 09:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Sellers will commonly ask me whether they should get an entire new roof or can they  just put a second layer of composition shingles on top. Putting an entire new roof on a home is expensive, so this is a very important question.

“If you skimp on your roof, buyers will think you’ve skimped in other places”
If you have composition shingles on your roof, you can either replace sections of it, replace all of it, or put a new layer over the old layer, but this depends on multiple factors. One way to tell if you need to remove the old before putting on the new is to look at the edges of the roof and up in your attic crawlspace. If you can see rot or damage on the plywood sheeting, you should remove and replace it along with the new layer of shingles.

It’s important to keep in mind that cutting corners like  covering up rotten plywood will send messages to the buyer that you’ve been cutting a lot of corners and covering up problems elsewhere in your home. When it comes to something as important as your roof, it’s best to do the job right.

If you have any more questions or concerns about this issue, please don’t hesitate to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Sellers will commonly ask me whether they should get an entire new roof or can they  just put a second layer of composition shingles on top. Putting an entire new roof on a home is expensive, so this is a very important question.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Sellers will commonly ask me whether they should get an entire new roof or can they  just put a second layer of composition shingles on top. Putting an entire new roof on a home is expensive, so this is a very important question.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Now the Time to Get Top Dollar for Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/is-now-time-to-get-top-dollarfor-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-09-03 14:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Where is the Puget Sound market heading? Today I’ll explain how conditions are changing in our area and what it means for you!

Right now, there is a tiny bit less urgency for buyers in our market. They have a little more time to take a good look at homes before making a quick decision. Inventory isn’t moving as swiftly as it once was, showing that our market has finally cooled off a bit.
“Now is a wonderful time to be a seller!”
In March, we had an inventory of 1.3 months’ supply. This means that if no other homes were listed, in just over a month all available homes would be sold. When the market was that hot, buyers had to scramble and act quickly if they were going to get the right house. Since then, inventory has built slowly to where we are now, at 1.8 months’ supply. Although it doesn’t seem like much difference, it does allow our buyers to put their best foot forward after thinking about it for more than 5 minutes.

For sellers, we’re still getting full-priced offers in competitive situations. However, the offers aren’t coming in quite as quickly as they were earlier this summer. Nonetheless, homes are selling quickly and for top dollar, so now is a great time to sell!

If you have any questions about how you can make this market work for you, don’t hesitate- reach out to me. I would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Where is the Puget Sound market heading? Today I’ll explain how conditions are changing in our area and what it means for you!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Where is the Puget Sound market heading? Today I’ll explain how conditions are changing in our area and what it means for you!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Walking Out My Purpose: How Does My Faith Affect My Business?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/walking-out-my-purpose-how-does-my.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-08-19 11:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Waiting on the Lord is an evolving experience. When I have an obstacle or issue, I start to worry. When things don’t happen right, that’s where my worry kicks in.

I have noticed that my approach is different when observing others. I recently had a coworker who got very worried, upset, and anxious, and I was thinking to myself, “Why are they so upset? Don’t they know it’s just work, and it will be over at 5pm?” Then it hit me. It doesn’t really matter why it bothers him, it just does.

When I sat back and reflected on this, it allowed me to realize that, looking in, if I could detach myself emotionally from the situation, I can take away the emotional response and look at things more objectively. Then I can rely on my faith and trust in the Lord that things will be alright.
“God provides for me, but sometimes I forget this.”
God provides for me, but sometimes I forget this. This has happened to all of us; we forget to remember him. It’s not remembering in the mental sense, it’s kind of a sensory recall where you put yourself in a situation where the Lord has previously delivered you. For me, I try to remember that God brought me out of the wilderness of 2007 and 2008, and I’m here and better off for it.

I have found that I have more peace and understanding that all will be well, both in my heart and my head, when I trust in the Lord. I do this by having a constant relationship with Him, and making sure He knows all my fears, struggles, and aspirations, so He can help me make them a reality.

If you have any questions for me, or would like to discuss how you deal with impatience or anxiety, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to chat, and am always here to be there for you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Waiting on the Lord is an evolving experience. When I have an obstacle or issue, I start to worry. When things don’t happen right, that’s where my worry kicks in.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Waiting on the Lord is an evolving experience. When I have an obstacle or issue, I start to worry. When things don’t happen right, that’s where my worry kicks in.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sandy's Tool Shed Has Two New Items</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-tools-for-rent.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-08-10 14:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As you may know, we like to share our tools with our clients. We call it Sandy’s Tool Shed! Any of our clients are able to use them, and we have two more tools available in our shed.

First is a pressure washer, which can be really useful for improving your curb appeal and maintaining a beautiful home. Wash off the side of your home, your driveway, your patio, or any other outdoor space. My husband used it on our patio which now looks brand new! All you have to do is contact me and set up a time to come pick it up.
“New Paint can add a lot of value to your property.”
The second addition to our tool shed is a power paint sprayer. This tool takes a little bit of training, so when you borrow it, please have a good idea of how to operate it, or plan a little extra time to learn before you jump in.

A power paint sprayer can be a little tricky. And we want you to have a great experience when using our tools. After all, we like you to associate our help with great results, not with frustration! So if you feel like a power paint sprayer is a little more than you can handle, I will recommend a great painter who can do a beautiful job for you. New paint is proven to add a lot of value to a home and is important to maintain your home’s condition.

So now Sandy’s Tool Shed includes 2 extension ladders, a carpet cleaner, plumbing snake, ratchet straps for securing loads, the pressure washer and power paint sprayer, and various yard tools. As always, please feel free to contact us if you want to borrow these tools, and let us know what else you recommend we add!

Always refer to us as your #1 resource for real estate in Puget Sound!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As you may know, we like to share our tools with our clients. We call it Sandy’s Tool Shed! Any of our clients are able to use them, and we have two more tools available in our shed.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As you may know, we like to share our tools with our clients. We call it Sandy’s Tool Shed! Any of our clients are able to use them, and we have two more tools available in our shed.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Purchase After a Foreclosure</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-to-purchase-after-foreclosure.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-07-08 10:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’m going to be speaking about how you can prepare to buy a home again after a major life event like a bankruptcy, foreclosure, or short sale. A lot of people are finding themselves in this situation after the market crashed in 2007. If you’re having difficulty when you’re speaking with a lender or a real estate agent, I have one important question to ask you:

What could you have done differently that in any part contributed to this painful outcome?

It’s probably not your fault that your company downsized and you lost your job, and it’s probably not your fault that the economy took a turn for the worse and housing values plummeted. However, is there something that you could have done and now could be doing differently to allow yourself to succeed? Is there a skill you need that you don’t have right now?
“You have the power to decide where your money goes and how it’s used.”
I suggest stepping back for a moment to examine where your priorities lie for yourself and your family. Even I have had to do this in my life, and I turned to certain family members and friends for advice on matters like handling my money wisely. I also took advantage of resources like www.daveramsey.com.

You have the power to decide where your money goes and how it’s used. If you have goals that are on hold and need assistance with any step of this process, please don’t hesitate to contact me!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m going to be speaking about how you can prepare to buy a home again after a major life event like a bankruptcy, foreclosure, or short sale. A lot of people are finding themselves in this situation after the market crashed in 2007. If you’re having difficulty when you’re speaking with a lender or a real estate agent, I have one important question to ask you:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m going to be speaking about how you can prepare to buy a home again after a major life event like a bankruptcy, foreclosure, or short sale. A lot of people are finding themselves in this situation after the market crashed in 2007. If you’re having difficulty when you’re speaking with a lender or a real estate agent, I have one important question to ask you:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Walking Out My Purpose: Are You Waiting for Your Prayers to Be Answered?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/walking-out-my-purpose-are-you-waiting.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-06-26 10:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’m speaking with my coach about what we do when we are waiting for our prayers to be answered.

When something is going really wrong in your life, what do you do in the meantime? Do you pray? Do you think things over in your head?

It keeps coming back to the seeds that I plant in my life. Do you cultivate joy? Do you do the things necessary to give you peace?
“You have to take care of yourself while your prayers are being answered.”
When I get upset I work to remind myself what I need to do in order to restore my peace. In the downtime between something bad and something good, it’s important to remember what you need to do to make yourself better while you’re waiting for your prayers to be answered.

When you can do these things, you are more able to handle the tough things that happen in your life.

Thanks for watching, and I hope everyone gets something good out of this conversation!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m speaking with my coach about what we do when we are waiting for our prayers to be answered.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m speaking with my coach about what we do when we are waiting for our prayers to be answered.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can An Escalation Clause Help You?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-can-escalation-clause-help-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-06-24 13:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I have a good story about how I helped some buyers get a home for less than what they were willing to pay.

This particular couple needed a home where they could have a shorter commute to work, and after looking at about 20 homes, we found one that they fell in love with. Because they wanted it so badly, we crafted an offer that was above full price and also put in an escalation clause.
“An escalation clause will surely strengthen your offer.”
An escalation clause means that we were willing to pay slightly above everyone else’s offer, up to a certain amount.

This made our offer seem very strong and very urgent, and it ended up working! Early the next morning the sellers told us that they would take our offer without even waiting to see what others would offer. They named us a price, which was actually a bit below what we were willing to pay in the escalation clause, and we matched the offer.

This just goes to show how important it is to craft a good offer in a competitive market, such as the one that we have here in Puget Sound.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I have a good story about how I helped some buyers get a home for less than what they were willing to pay.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I have a good story about how I helped some buyers get a home for less than what they were willing to pay.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Is the Market Performing for Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/how-is-market-performing-for-buyers-and.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-06-22 09:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Hey everyone, today we are going to talk about what’s going on in the Puget Sound real estate market, for buyers and sellers.

In Puget Sound, we are actually seeing interest rates bounce around a little bit. I recently spoke to a lender, who told me that last week he could quote an interest rate somewhere around 4.5%, but today, he could quote the buyer for 4.25%. With rates fluctuating, we are going to pay very close attention to them. When interest rates go up, the purchasing power of buyers decreases. Just a 1% increase in rates will cut affordability by 10%.
“Just a 1% increase in rates will cut affordability by 10%.”
We are expecting to see a bit of softening in the market by the end of the year, so sellers need to be spiffy. We are still in a hot seller’s market, but buyers are going to be more cautious and picky when choosing a home. However, if you’re looking to get value on your home sale, selling soon is ideal for you.

For buyers, sellers are still getting 98 or 99% of their asking price, so low-ball offers won’t work for the most part. However, we can give you advice on what kind of offer you can make in order to win a property.

If you have any questions for us, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Hey everyone, today we are going to talk about what’s going on in the Puget Sound real estate market, for buyers and sellers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Hey everyone, today we are going to talk about what’s going on in the Puget Sound real estate market, for buyers and sellers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's Happening with Real Estate in Puget Sound?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-06-18 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As we near the end of spring and begin to enter summer, I thought it would be useful to provide you with a real estate market update.

Currently, inventory is shifting a little bit, but inventory is still very, very low and buyers are squirming to find good homes. We actually only have 1.3 months of inventory right now. However, we expect a seasonal rise in inventory to help buyers find good homes. For sellers, this means that you have a very good opportunity to find a buyer willing to pay top dollar.
“The important thing to remember is to price your home correctly when you’re selling.”
Prices are still going up, but interest rates are starting to rise. For sellers, this means that you need to price your home so that many different buyers can afford your home if you want to capture the largest possible audience. Homes that are priced well and in good condition are selling very well, and sometimes even for more than the asking price. However, buyers are more savvy than they used to be and they will not overpay for homes very often unless they are really in love with a property.

The important thing to remember is to price your home correctly when you’re selling, because even though inventory is low, buyers aren’t willing to pay a whole lot extra.

Hopefully this information is useful to you if you’re planning on buying or selling a home in Puget Sound this summer. Please contact me with any questions you may have!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As we near the end of spring and begin to enter summer, I thought it would be useful to provide you with a real estate market update.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As we near the end of spring and begin to enter summer, I thought it would be useful to provide you with a real estate market update.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Walking Out My Purpose: Battling My Impatience</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/walking-out-my-purpose-battling-my.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-05-12 14:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re all very busy in our lives. We have work to do, people to see, and probably a million other odds and ends that we need to accomplish. This is why today I’ll be speaking with my coach about being more purposeful in order to improve my personal life, my professional life, and my spiritual life.

One of the most important parts of being patient is slowing down enough to listen to God prompting us to go one direction or another. We like to think that we know exactly what to do, and we often do know what to do. But sometimes God is asking us to go a different direction. So, sometimes our first reactions aren’t the best ones for us, and we don’t always hear him until afterwards when it’s too late. And then we miss out on the better plans that he has for us.
“When I’m impatient and push forward, that’s when I really miss God’s best plan for me.”
I’d like to share what the Lord is working on with me right now regarding patience and listening and having a soft heart that hears and follows his direction. Hopefully this video encourages you in your walk, and I’d love to hear how he’s working in your heart as well.

If you have any comments or questions about this, please don’t hesitate to contact me and I’ll be sure to get back to you quickly.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’re all very busy in our lives. We have work to do, people to see, and probably a million other odds and ends that we need to accomplish. This is why today I’ll be speaking with my coach about being more purposeful in order to improve my personal life, my professional life, and my spiritual life.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re all very busy in our lives. We have work to do, people to see, and probably a million other odds and ends that we need to accomplish. This is why today I’ll be speaking with my coach about being more purposeful in order to improve my personal life, my professional life, and my spiritual life.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Sell Quickly and For Top Dollar in Puget Sound</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-home-seller.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-04-27 13:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

A while back, I worked with some attorneys who ran into a sticky situation. The long story short is that they needed to sell their home quickly. The home itself was a project home with lots of repairs that needed to be done, but the owners didn’t have the time or resources to put in the necessary repairs.

We eventually listed it as a home that needed some elbow grease, and we listed it at a fair market value compared to the other fixer-uppers in the area. When we advertised it as a property that needed some love, we had every home flipper and investor in the area wanting to take a look at it.
“We know how to find serious buyers that are willing to pay top dollar for your property.”
In two days we had fifteen offers on the home! We got a full price offer in the first twenty minutes, and eventually we had an offer that was $20,000 over the asking price.

My question for you is: who do you know out there who wants to sell their home quickly and for top dollar?

We know how to find serious buyers that are willing to pay top dollar for your property. If you are looking to buy or sell anytime soon, please don’t hesitate to contact me!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A while back, I worked with some attorneys who ran into a sticky situation. The long story short is that they needed to sell their home quickly. The home itself was a project home with lots of repairs that needed to be done, but the owners didn’t have the time or resources to put in the necessary repairs.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A while back, I worked with some attorneys who ran into a sticky situation. The long story short is that they needed to sell their home quickly. The home itself was a project home with lots of repairs that needed to be done, but the owners didn’t have the time or resources to put in the necessary repairs.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Be Doing to Your Home Before You Sell?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-home-seller-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-04-23 12:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’ll be giving you advice on certain things you should not be doing to your home before you go to sell it, and then I’ll also give some suggestions on other things that you can do instead.

One thing that I’ve been getting questions about lately is whether or not sellers should be adding granite counter tops. My answer is always NO because multiple surveys have revealed that you don’t get your investment back when you sell your home. Instead, you can just clean your kitchen and countertops extremely thoroughly. Although it may not have the same appeal as granite, your kitchen will be spotless and will signal to the buyer that your home is in good shape.
“Repainting and putting in new carpet are pretty solid ways to add value to your home when you go to sell later on.”
Another thing you need to do is repaint the interior of your home. Pets and kids can really wreak havoc on the walls, and the same goes for carpeting. If your carpet is more than one to two years old, then I would highly suggest getting new carpet and repainting your home in light earth tones. Repainting and putting in new carpet are pretty solid ways to add value to your home when you go to sell later on.

One last thing that you might consider if you have hardwood floors is to refinish them. This can add a nice touch, and buyers will be appreciative that you went the extra step and had this done to your home.

If you don’t have the time to do these things for yourself, I know excellent contractors that can come in and get this job done quickly and efficiently.

As always, if you need assistance when you’re buying or selling in Marysville, please don’t hesitate to contact me.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’ll be giving you advice on certain things you should not be doing to your home before you go to sell it, and then I’ll also give some suggestions on other things that you can do instead.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’ll be giving you advice on certain things you should not be doing to your home before you go to sell it, and then I’ll also give some suggestions on other things that you can do instead.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are You Looking for Free Tools and Resources?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/puget-sound-real-estate-available-tools.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-04-22 15:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Do you have a project that you’re waiting to complete because you don’t have the right tools? Depending on what you need, tools can be extremely expensive.

Luckily, I have collected some tools from my sellers, and you’re able to rent them from me as long as you sign a release. We have ladders, carpet cleaners, and more.

I recently got a hold of an extension ladder that fits in your car and stands up to twelve feet tall. You can paint vaulted ceilings or underneath your eaves. I’m happy to let you to use these items; all you have to do is contact me!
“Please let me know which tools you’re looking for- I’m gathering the equipment that people need most.”
Please let me know which tools you’re looking for- I’m gathering the equipment that people need most.

As always, please contact me if you’re looking to buy or sell in Puget Sound.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Do you have a project that you’re waiting to complete because you don’t have the right tools? Depending on what you need, tools can be extremely expensive.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Do you have a project that you’re waiting to complete because you don’t have the right tools? Depending on what you need, tools can be extremely expensive.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Spring Activities in Puget Sound That Everyone Can Enjoy</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/marysville-spring-vacation-ideas-march.html</link>
        
          <category>More From Sandy & Company</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-03-24 13:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re extremely fortunate here in the Pacific Northwest to have such great scenery around us. There is so much for us to do -  we have mountains, oceans, and much more.

My daughter will be turning 18 this summer, and we’ve decided that we’re going to take a Clipper Tour up to Victoria. We’re also going to be visiting Butchart Gardens while we’re there, and we’re extremely excited to be planning this trip.
“There is so much for us to do -  we have mountains, oceans, and much more.”
We’re also going to be heading to Mt. Rainier to do some camping and fishing, and I cannot wait to smell trout cooking on the campfire. I’ve always liked camping and spending time in the outdoors, and the options are limitless in our area. We’re extremely blessed to live in an area like this with so much to offer.

Another favorite day trip of mine is in Friday Harbor on San Juan Island. There is a very inexpensive ferry you can take to see the wildlife, and you can take this trip in early spring.

We would love for you to share ideas on what you do for fun in this area. We’re always looking for new adventures.

As always, please refer to us with any questions you might have about our local real estate market. We’re always here to help you - except for when we’re out enjoying this beautiful area!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’re extremely fortunate here in the Pacific Northwest to have such great scenery around us. There is so much for us to do -  we have mountains, oceans, and much more.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re extremely fortunate here in the Pacific Northwest to have such great scenery around us. There is so much for us to do -  we have mountains, oceans, and much more.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Take Advantage of Puget Sound Real Estate?</title>
        <link>http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com/marysville-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Sandy Eagon</author>
        <pubDate>2015-03-23 14:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

In order to prepare you for a successful spring real estate transaction, I’d like to share some information with you in the hopes that you can use it to your own advantage when you enter the real estate market.


  Home prices are rising slightly because of increased competition from spring home buyers.
  There is only a month and a half of inventory, and this is driving up prices as well.
  Home prices should soften up after the spring when there is less competition.
  With low interest rates, (sitting right around 3.75%) more buyers will be able to afford homes, and sellers will also reap the benefits of this increased affordability.
“Home prices should soften up after the spring when there is less competition.”
Thanks for tuning in again, I hope this information will be helpful to you when you’re buying or selling in Marysville. Please consider me your #1 resource for real estate!

</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://sandyandcompanyvideos.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

In order to prepare you for a successful spring real estate transaction, I’d like to share some information with you in the hopes that you can use it to your own advantage when you enter the real estate market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sandy Eagon</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

In order to prepare you for a successful spring real estate transaction, I’d like to share some information with you in the hopes that you can use it to your own advantage when you enter the real estate market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Sandy Eagon</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Sandy Eagon</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Sandy &amp; Company Real Estate - your professional Marysville Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
